<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>aarond.me</title>
        <link>https://aarond.me/</link>
        <description>The blog of Aaron Davies</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:53:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Gridsome Feed Plugin</generator>
        <atom:link href="https://aarond.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When I get that feeling]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/12/when-i-get-that-feeling/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/12/when-i-get-that-feeling/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It's been a little slow at work these past few weeks. I've had a few early starts, but other than that I've generally been home by about 7pm. It's unsettling! When work gets intense I can be out until close to midnight, but when there are no urgent calls coming in I just sit around at home… waiting. 

I find it difficult to do stuff when I'm on call like this. Can I bake? Watch a movie? Learn a new dance? Not really, if a priority one call comes in I've normally got to be out the door in 10 minutes just to meet resolution targets.

I dance far worse than I sing, so it's a very scary thought.

To be honest? While I'm single and alone I'd rather be working long hours than just loafing about at home. I just feel way less productive and accomplished when I'm sitting around home "relaxing" when I could be out there earning cash and fixing stuff!

And I love complaining about how much I work. I inherited my love of complaining from my Dad, so at this point it's a tradition.

My Instagram is still banned. I got suspended as someone reported me as an imposter. I think they were just jealous of my… wild and exciting life? Nope, maybe not that. It sucks, I liked posting my bad singing and torturing all the people following me! I've done the appeal process to try and get it back, but given how these companies work I'm not holding out hope.

But hey, to make up for it I put this on my dating profile.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkabUfWmzWk`

How the hell am I still single?!

It kind of worked? Some match with me and ask "What's up with that video?!" Others find it funny. Either way? It's something unique!

Right! Out the door at 6am tomorrow. I have to get to site for a scheduled job, but want to participate in the weekly meeting for work. Only way to make it fit is to leave very early, then sit in the car tuning into the exciting meeting from my phone.

Shit it's going to be cold!]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turns out? I'm not an asshole]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/11/turns-out-i-m-not-an-asshole/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/11/turns-out-i-m-not-an-asshole/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Shit I’m old. I turned a grand age of 34 on Monday. But let’s not panic, I’m not frail and fatigued yet!

I was resigned just to have a night in, but I got invited out. A girl I dated many moons ago took me out to a really nice local place with her partner. It was an awesome night: Pizza, Beer and Banter. Turns out just hanging out with cool people is a fun thing to do!

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/drinks.jpg)](/media/images/blog/drinks.jpg)
_And I didn't used to like beer! Times they are changing._

And after that? I’m slowly realising I might not be the biggest asshole in the world. 

My ex thinks I wronged her in so many ways and never wants to have anything to do with me again. That got to me! I don’t like people hating me, it’s unsettling. With hindsight, it was one of the reasons I was finding it tough to get up and move on. If something is broken, I fix it! I don’t leave it shattered in a million pieces.

But knowing that the only other person I’ve dated seems to think I’m actually not the biggest asshole in the world has given me a boost. I mean, that relationship didn’t last very long, and was a long time ago. But still. 

I know with my ex I made some bad decisions, but honestly? Not that bad. I made amends for my mistakes as best as I could, and tried to be understanding. If that relationship was going to be successful in the long term these problems would have been things we would have worked through together.

Another thing I learned that night was that this cool couple were maybe looking to get… A Playstation. No! Cool people don’t do that! How can I sleep at night if I let such a stylish, outgoing and handsome household end up with a damn Sony Playstation. I mean, I want friends! But even I have my limits.

So I got them an Xbox. **[Series S!](https://www.xbox.com/en-NZ/consoles/xbox-series-s)**

[![handwriting.](/media/images/blog/xboxnote.jpg)](/media/images/blog/xboxnote.jpg)
_Don't diss my handwriting._

A bit of a nerdy tangent, but the Series S is an amazing console. It’s such a capable and sleek powerhouse. Last time I went up to Auckland for training I took mine with me in my suitcase - it’s small enough to fit in next to my undies. And this little black and white box doesn’t miss a beat! I’m playing through Jedi: Fallen Order, and with the next gen update it runs super smooth and looks amazing. Right now they’re $549 here in New Zealand - a little steep, but they’re still hard to find on shelves. When the demand eases up and this global semiconductor shortage is over there’ll likely be a price drop - and at $400 they'd be a must have.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/sonicscale.jpg)](/media/images/blog/sonicscale.jpg)
_Xbox Series S. Sonic the Hedgehog provided for scale._

I gifted the Xbox plus six months of Game Pass, and they’re set. I didn’t have to sweat bullets about what games to give them - they’ve got a huge library to choose from! They’re a very stylish couple, and that sleek little white console will look amazing on their mantle.

Yes, I’m a mega nerd. That’s my good deed for the week. I’ve improved their lives! I prevented them from making a bad decision that would have led them down a horrific path of sadness and despair.

Oh, she also took my phone and went on a particular dating app on my behalf. No, I’m not sharing details of how that went here. You’ll just have to guess.
git p]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lament]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/03/lament/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/03/lament/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Breaking news
A 2011 Mazda Demio is for sale. 

It's green! Yes, the original grasshopper is on the market. She served me well! I spent today removing all of my stuff, vacuuming it all out, reinstalling the back seats and giving it a wash. She’s done 150,000 kilometers, but has been serviced regularly. And after driving my White Tiger for a few weeks I realise how extremely fuel efficient the old grasshopper is.

[![Grass.](/media/images/blog/grass.jpg)](/media/images/blog/grass.jpg)
_This could be yours! All offers considered._

It’s been a solid week. There’s a huge amount of scheduled work going on, so juggling that alongside my usual day to day stuff is a challenge. I have to be in Ohakune at 8am next week, so I’m pushing my boss to let me stay over the night before. Driving those icy roads at the coldest part of the night doesn’t seem wise, even in my All-Wheel Drive machine.

Yikes, it's cold in the morning. Having my car tell me what the outside temperature isn’t very comforting. I burn money all night long keeping the heating on, and I think it’s the absolute best investment ever. Rolling out of bed would require more willpower than I currently have if my house was an ice wonderland. The cold always bothered me.

[![Cold.](/media/images/blog/cold.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cold.jpg)
_This counts as very cold._

Oh, my Instagram account got suspended! The reason? I was accused of being an imposter, pretending to be someone I’m not. Someone reported me for that! Have you seen what I post on Instagram? I mean, I do pretend to be a lively and fun person, but that’s hardly identity fraud. Maybe someone was just sharply jealous of the slice I reviewed.


[![Cold.](/media/images/blog/ban.jpg)](/media/images/blog/ban.jpg)
_And I'm not even a goot actor._

Oh, and of the lament I broadcast about my ex.

Yes, I know what you’ll say. Get over it! Or, as one friend put it, “Y u miss that skank anyway”. I’ll get there! However I’m not going to sit around and lie to myself. Hey, I’m an emotionally attached person! Moving on from the love of my life isn’t something to be rushed. You can’t hurry love, and you also can’t hurry falling out of love. But then again, my ex once did catch me Googling “Can you fall in love with someone in a week”. 

I have boatloads of regrets, but even if I had a time machine I wouldn’t be confident I could make better choices for it to work.

**[But I’d die to find out.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQt6jIKNwgU)**

We might be ultimately incompatible, but for some strange reason that doesn’t make moving on easier for me. 

Do I still have feelings for her, after all of this? That’s classified.

But hey, I am feeling way more confident these days. I’m happy with how stuff is going, really. Nothing special, but I’m not some sad heartbroken shrew anymore. I’m a confident, successful, smiling, hard working and… heartbroken badger! Yes, some things haven't changed. Badgers are better than shrews.

In the months since the messy breakup I have gotten out there on that dating scene a bit, but with no luck. Every date I’ve ever been on was through online dating, specifically Tinder. I’m very much wanting to try out the more old fashioned approach, but I wouldn’t know how to go about that. Party in the club? I’m taking applications for a wingman! Or wingwoman. The hourly rate is good, plus all drinks are provided.

But, like I wrote last week, not having a partner right now is ok with me. My boss must love it, because it’s letting me dive head first into work! After this is pushed live I’ll be finishing off a training guide on a new bit of hardware my company is deploying. Doing it isn’t part of my job, but oddly? I enjoy it.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's a game of give and take]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/26/it-s-a-game-of-give-and-take/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/26/it-s-a-game-of-give-and-take/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
My first day off in about three weeks? I slept a lot!

My plan was to clean out my old car and put the back seats back in it, but the weather didn’t play ball. Vacuuming in the rain isn’t a smart idea, and my garage is full of… stuff. Work stuff, rubbish stuff and my sister's stuff.

How are you, anyway? What's happening with everyone out there in the world? I've been on a rollercoaster with work, so I want to know what everyone else has been up to lately.

Continuing my journey of being a more secure person, I realize I need to put effort into being more assured and even happy on my own. I am on my own! I work and live by myself, and if I really think about it that's not a bad thing. I have so much agency over everything I do.

It is annoying sometimes, especially figuring out what to eat for dinner. Lately it's been a small bit of meat and a bag of salad, trying to stay away from carbs and high calorie options - I've got to trim down!

Back on topic, I cannot let myself feel empty or lacking because I'm single or not leading a lively social life. Those things can be really comforting and beneficial things, but I'm going to be bad at them if I feel like I have a desperate need for them just to be happy. 

My history proves that. My insecure nature made me demanding and needy, and this frustrated the people I cared about and pushed them away. I remember saying how I felt the stuff I did was unappreciated, but that's… dumb. Don't do nice stuff for cool people to get affection and appreciation, do it because it's a nice thing to do.

Just giving myself permission to be happy and self assured on my own has been a revelation. Since my relationship crashed and burned I was trying to find something to fill that gap in my life. But now? I don't need that. If that stuff comes my way, great! It could be something amazing. It's just not something I need, but I do know if it comes my way I'll be in a better headspace to make it work.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/C9IwBJYTwQ0`

You’re a smart man, Phil Collins. But I have to disagree with you on some points.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Never Know What It's Like]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/24/you-can-never-know-what-it-s-like/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/24/you-can-never-know-what-it-s-like/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It’s never two years.

I’ve missed it by a few days, but it’s been two years since my Dad died. Even though my life and my lifestyle have changed so much, it still doesn’t feel like two whole years. I'm definitely not the same person I was back then, I've learned and experienced a lot! But still.

[![gus.](/media/images/blog/gus.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gus.jpg)
_These two loved a midday snooze._

I miss Dad. He was just an awesome person, and someone that I'm still very proud of. 

And I know he'd like the company car they gave me. A big white Subaru Outback. It's actually making my days a lot less exhausting. I've got ample space to fit giant parts in so I'm not always juggling stuff around. Plus driving it is a lot less stressful. The fancy adaptive cruise control just means a lot less fidgeting about. If there's a car ahead of you, just lock it in and it'll keep pace with it. It makes my many, many hours of driving each day just seem a little bit less like work.

[![car.](/media/images/blog/car.jpg)](/media/images/blog/car.jpg)
_White Tiger Subaru Power!_

Oh, but I need to be careful. On the way back from Dannevirke earlier in the week I eagerly passed two semi trucks in a short passing lane. The Subaru did it well! I zoomed passed, smooth as butter! But, it's a company car, and if I speed my boss gets a notification. 

It was a bad judgement call on my end. Call it the excitement of a new toy! But now I take a much more relaxed approach to driving. I won't be having that need for speed again.

And, in another revelation, I'm incredibly insecure. Talking with a friend really got me to realize this. Here I am being and working alone, and I'm just not… confident and sure of myself. It's probably why my past (and only) two relationships didn't work out. I just was always demanding so much reassurance and compassion from the other person that it pushed them away. I become possessive and somewhat obsessive, and put so much pressure on the other person. 

I have to learn to be more assured in myself and my life in general. A needy and insecure me cannot be part of a happy and healthy relationship, no matter how cool, funny, smart, caring, good looking and interesting I am. 

I'm all of those things, by the way. Just in case you didn't already notice! 

And, you know what? Stuffs going pretty damn good for me. I've got a job I enjoy, I'm good at and that pays well. Many people live long lives never having that. I also have a house, a company car and extremely cool shoes.

[![car.](/media/images/blog/shoes.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shoes.jpg)
_I got style, I got class._

Work is very fulfilling, being the world's most bestest uncle is the most satisfying thing ever! And I love to be able to do nice things for cool people.

But to succeed? To get what I want? I need to work on finding gratification from within me, rather than external sources. And that actually sounds like something I can do. 
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anxiety]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/08/anxiety/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/08/anxiety/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Do you get anxious?

I'm realizing that I do, and it's frustrating because I'm not entirely sure why.

Last night and all this morning I found myself bubbling away with anxiety. I was a little bit scared and apprehensive about going to work. It wasn't crippling - I know many people can become completely disabled when overwhelmed with anxiety. This was just a not very nice feeling that I couldn't shake.

Looking back, I have had anxiety issues since I was a teenager. When I was coming to terms with my Asperger's I would get overwhelmed with social anxiety. It reached a point where I had to leave school just because I couldn't cope. For years after that I had to live the life of a hermit, lest I get consumed by fear and dread. I never socialized!

But, I worked through that. I learned, through a huge amount of conscious effort, to cope and even thrive in reasonable social situations. It's still exhausting! I might behave all zany and loud sometimes, but that's not because I'm a wild and free extravert - it's just my way of taking command of a situation. Taming the beast.

On something more recent, I think my anxiety boiling under the surface was a big contributing factor to the downfall of my relationship. We dove into buying a house together, and I just couldn't help but sweat bullets over all the little details. Buying a house and renovating it is stressful anyway, and me being like that made it worse. 

I made some bad decisions, not just bad for the relationship but also bad for me. When my hopes and dreams were starting to fall apart I really struggled. I couldn't sleep well and constantly felt like I was being crushed into little pieces. I still find myself getting consumed by a feeling of dread and fear that, because I failed so badly in that relationship, I can never be successful in any relationship. I miss what I had and stress that I'll never have anything like it again, and it's all my fault. 

And now it's my job. Last night I was just stressing about work. I had a dozen non-urgent tasks to get to, and got anxious trying to figure out what exactly I should do - and the seemingly dire consequences for making the wrong choice. My fear is that I'll dive in deep on a job, be half way through then suddenly get assigned an urgent job that will drag me away . It's silly! I know I have options of what I can do in that situation, but it just makes me dread that I'll make the wrong choice of what to do in the morning.

Going to bed tonight? It's not a problem. An urgent job has come up that I'll need to travel to first thing in the morning. It's such a relief! I'll jump out of bed knowing exactly what I need to do, and as it's a priority one job nothing can stand in my way!

Writing about it here? It makes it all seem so silly. I know I'm not going to get punished for making the wrong choice of what to do in the morning, and my bosses have been clear that I've been doing a good job with the work I do. 

But I think that's often true with anxiety - it's often irrational! I'll be fine, I just need to stay…

Grounded in reality.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Staging]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/25/staging/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/25/staging/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
What a fun start to the week.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/flying.jpg)](/media/images/blog/flying.jpg)
_Soaring, Flying, Breaking Free!_

Right now I'm flying back home after another visit to Auckland for training. I seem to be up here more and more frequently these days! It's really nice. I enjoy heading into the office and being able to see all the awesome people I normally only email or phone.

No drunken shenanigans this time; I didn't get locked out of the hotel room in my undies.

That caramel slice I made? I took it to the office and it all went! I was pleased at how well it survived transport in my carry-on bag. My boss, my boss’s boss, my boss’s boss’s boss and Karl all liked it! The secret is all in the caramel. Maybe my ego is just getting too big, but I'm very proud.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/slicegone.jpg)](/media/images/blog/slicegone.jpg)
_And those last four pieces were gone before I left._

Speaking of bosses, I realised just how much the management at my work really goes into bat for me. I work hard and scarcely get any feedback, but when I asked about how it was looking for me to get a full time salaried job, he showed me a PowerPoint presentation he was going to present to international senior management basically stating how they'd better hire me and a few other contractors before we jump ship!

Someone loves me, even if my ex doesn't.

I also spoke to another boss about my hours - he's asked me to come up with a working roster for after-hours work. He's really given me the freedom to choose what hours I want to do (within reason!). I absolutely want to keep doing the late shift - sometimes when I get home early, I get bored sitting there eagerly waiting for jobs to come in of an evening. I'm just not sure if I want to keep doing five days a week 8 till 11, or if I want to transition to alternating weeks on call. I'll have to think about it.

The CBD area around the office and the hotel I stay at has become so familiar to me. It's entrenched with memories - not of Auckland, but of what has been happening in my life when I've been here. 

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/streets.jpeg)](/media/images/blog/streets.jpeg)
_Written on these streets are the stories that I can't explain._

The first time I was up here? I was on top of the world! I felt amazing. I remember places where I bought Christmas presents, and where I was when I was on the phone to a certain someone. I remember feeling guilty that I was away yet having such a good time up here.

The second time I was here I was at an all time low, struggling to recover and having booze for the first time in 10,000 years. Yeah, I’m still embarrassed about what happened, especially when I found out that everyone in the office knows! Does it count as office gossip if everyone already knows what happened?

This time? I'm good. I mean, I'm not great! But I can't complain about how stuff is going right now. I still have a massive empty hole in me, but somehow I seem okay to not be in a rush to fill it. Everyone says it will happen, from my skepical best friend Mark to my kick ass colleague Jazz. Thank you! You empower me heaps.

Being around myself every day, I don't really have a view on how I've progressed, but having these semi-annual trips away acts as a kind of checkpoint. It gives me an opportunity to reflect on who I am, where I've come from and maybe even where I'm going.

I might be moving forward. I might be moving sideways. Heck, I might just be staying in one place dancing really awkwardly! But right now I can absolutely say I'm not moving backwards.

And that's an achievement worth unlocking.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The appalling state of Caramel in this country]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/23/the-appalling-state-of-caramel-in-this-country/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/23/the-appalling-state-of-caramel-in-this-country/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
As some of you may already know, I have a vendetta: The quality of caramel slices in this country is appalling.

As a “hobby”, to keep me sane during my long working days (which involve a lot of driving), I've been stopping off at bakeries and cafes around the area and sampling the caramel slice available. I got into caramel slice last year when I curated a range from all over the region to put together gift packages! It was very interesting just to see how diverse the offerings are. 

So far, Dannevirke has won. One bakery there had a gooey, oozy caramel in a crunchy and yum slice. But other places? Horrific. Wanganui, Palmerston North, Hunterville, Foxton, Eketahuna - all terrible, and definitely below par. Sometimes it’s crumbly and old, and at other times it just… tastes like porridge.

No more! It’s very clear that I need to show people how it’s done.

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL108VewJBdOA_OfLkchSuUgJumDqZTGPe" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>

Oh, I’m not an expert - I just like talking big. I’m going to ride that hype train! I’d rather boost myself up and let you, my readers, be disappointed. I will set your hopes way too high. But maybe, this one time, you should trust me.

First, put caster sugar and water into a giant pot. Yes, that’s right: White sugar and water. No butter, no brown sugar. Trust me here.

Let that bubble away on a medium heat for about 10 minutes, stirring all the time. It’ll develop a nice dark brown colour. Be careful: The colour will change very quickly! Pay attention, and don’t let it get away on you.

Now, pour in some cream. Not too much! Be careful, as the sugar solution will bubble up and put on quite a show. Remember to keep stirring. It’ll eventually settle down, and you’ll be left with a very concentrated brown caramel solution.

Next, add a can of condensed milk. Turn the heat down to low, and keep stirring. At this point you’re reducing the moisture and caramelising the sugars from the condensed milk. Here it’s all about the consistency you want - the longer you simmer it for, the thicker and harder the caramel will set. For slices you don’t want it to be very runny, but if you were making this as a sauce you’d simmer it for a shorter time.

[![Caramel.](/media/images/blog/caramel.jpg)](/media/images/blog/caramel.jpg)
_Ooooooooh._

And then it’s done! Wasn’t that easy? It’s a gooey caramel, full of flavour. You’ll love it, I promise.

With this batch, I put together a caramel slice. I sandwiched a thick layer of caramel between two vanilla cookie sheets, and then covered it with a thin layer of a dark chocolate and butter icing.

[![Caramel.](/media/images/blog/slice.jpg)](/media/images/blog/slice.jpg)
_It looks a bit... messy, but this would blow your mind!_

I swear I’m a humble person - sometimes - but this is just an order of magnitude better than most of the caramel based bakery treats I’ve had over the past year. The flavour is just amazing, and it’s got that ultimate smooth, gooey toffee texture. I may be hopeless at so many things, but this time? I’ve won!
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Mother, My Mother and Me]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/09/my-mother-my-mother-and-me/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/09/my-mother-my-mother-and-me/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, that was one hell of a week. My work days were long hours, but it was, frustratingly, a lot of waiting around. Oddly, I’d rather be working hard for 14 hours than trying to sort out scheduling and logistics.

I’m at peace with taking on long hours for now. My boss’s boss phoned me up when it reached him through the grapevine that I was doing crazy hours. I’m waiting to hear back, but I’m hoping I can come out of it with something like a week on week off schedule for on call after hours work.

And hey! It’s not like I have anything better to do with my time, so I might as well be out there raking in the cash. #SingleLife. Maybe that’ll change sometime, but God only knows when.

Here in New Zealand today is Mother’s day (Did you know in Norway it’s in February? Scandinavia is crazy!). All the well wishes and celebrations being shared about on social media have got me thinking about something I haven’t really brought up here before - my mother.

[![My mother.](/media/images/blog/mum1.jpg)](/media/images/blog/mum1.jpg)
_About 12 years ago. Wellington bays!_

Many years ago, she was an awesome mother. I was fortunate enough to have her around a lot, as she took up the role of a stay at home mum. It was great for me, she was always around and always supportive. She had a lot of health conditions that drained her of energy during most of my youth, but she still pushed hard to doing everything she could for me and my sister.

I went through a rough ordeal coming to terms with my… uniqueness in my late teenage years. I worked hard to push through my autism and social anxiety, and every single step of the way my mother was there. She provided me with the support and reassurance that I needed, coming to every appointment and being extremely patient with me. There’s a good chance that, without her support, I’d still be the wreck I was, rather than the semi-functional human being I am today.

About 15 years ago my mother started to deteriorate with Alzhimers disease. It was very gradual at first, often something my Dad and I would laugh at. She just did and said weird stuff! 

We kept on top of it, even when it started to get worse. I was studying at the time, so my Dad was at home with her, keeping an eye on things during the day. I remember she started to want to go to bed at about 6pm in the winter -  I don’t have an issue with people going to bed that early, but it’d mean she’d be up in the middle of the night, and one of us would need to be up with her.

My Dad and I worked so hard. Near the end it was constant and round the clock. I’d sit on the floor all night, sometimes getting an uncomfortable sleep but making sure I’d wake up if she got out of bed. It was exhausting for both of us, and with my Dad's health not being so great we just couldn’t go on. We had to place mum into specialised dementia care.

My mother hated us for doing that. She still had just enough marbles to know what was going on, and her emotions ranged from extremely sad to angry at the idea that we were making her leave her home. For about the first year, every time we visited her, she thought we were there to take her home to live. It was so hard, and I know my Dad struggled with that too.

For the first few years we visited every day, with only the rare exception. Sometimes we’d take her out in the car. On one of the last times we did that, she got extremely uneasy. She didn’t want to be in the car, and tried to open the door and reach over for the steering wheel. She was confused, and thought that something bad was happening. I had to restrain her in the back seat with quite a lot of force, while my Dad sped back to the rest home.

We didn’t dare take her out after that, it was just too much of a risk. We couldn’t handle her.

[![My mother.](/media/images/blog/mum2.jpg)](/media/images/blog/mum2.jpg)
_My mother today._

Her deterioration continued, and is still ongoing. Mentally she has completely gone now. She has no perception of what’s going on around her, and very little means to communicate with anyone. She spends her days in the dementia ward at her rest home just existing, and nothing more. She can barely walk without assistance, but is still often restless. The nurses and staff that look after her do a remarkable job, and I thank them greatly.

It’s tough. The strongest memories I have of my mother are from well into her path of deterioration. I remember the struggles my Dad and I had dealing with her, more than I remember the good times when I was younger. It was such a relief when she went into care that I wasn’t really aware that it was the end of my mother in the way that she used to be. I never got to mourn the loss.

I admire mothers. I love being around my nephew when he calls out to his mum. He loves his mum, and she does an excellent job being a mother. In my past relationship it was really nice to be around a family unit again, and I appreciate being made to feel so welcome.

The lesson here? Mums are awesome. Don’t take your mother for granted. Appreciate her while you still can.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trying out video: Life Update]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/02/trying-out-video-life-update/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/02/trying-out-video-life-update/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, rather than writing I opted for a video update this time. 4 minutes of it!

Big thanks to all the cool kids who've been helping me out over these past few weeks! Best friends, work colleagues and ex dating pals. You know who you are.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8f7ti-BLtU`]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rate My Tinder Profile]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/24/rate-my-tinder-profile/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/24/rate-my-tinder-profile/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I am still sick.

At least I’m no longer in a constant state of feeling horrible. Now it’s just a case of feeling sweaty and tired all the time. I’m half way through my antibiotics and it’s definitely working, but no one said it was going to be an easy ride. I have now managed to sleep a whole night without waking up in a pool of cold sweat, so there’s progress now where there once was none.

I miss work! Being sore and tired all day is flipping boring. I’m adamantly hoping that I can get back into it on Monday. I’m also hoping I can go out and visit friends tomorrow, that’d be very uplifting - but I don’t want to be a cesspit of sweat and disease.

In my newly found spare time I’ve been catching up with some shows. Oddly, the time just disappears when you’re sitting around being sick, so I haven’t been binging much, but here are a few things I’m tuning into:

* #### For All Mankind
Hard science fiction, maybe? It’s an alternate history TV series based on the idea that the Soviet Union made it to the moon first, and this let the space race escalate in crazy ways. It seems to be trying to be scientifically accurate, but it’s just a facade. The most frustrating thing is how it seems to paint all the astronauts as highly emotionally unstable people, turning it into a soap opera. The affairs and personal lives have become more of a focus than boldly going. Still, it’s nice to see long forgotten concepts like the Sea Dragon and nuclear propulsion realised.

* #### Taskmaster
This is the best show on TV right now. Get some mediocre comedians to do obscure and specific tasks against the clock! It seems like a low budget concept, but the amount of planning and time that goes into this show would be way more than you’d expect. The highlight of the most recent series has been moustached contestant Mike Wozniak. I’ve never heard of him before, but he’s the most strange and eccentric personality I’ve ever seen.

* #### The Falcon and the Winter Soldier
This is a buddy cop show, and it only works due to the actors in the lead roles. They’re awesome! They hate each other in the best way. It might be a full on, intense action show but the best part of it so far has been the two main super heroes renovating a fishing boat.

Plus there’s another thing I’ve been sweating bullets over in my spare time: an online dating profile. Tinder is still the hot stuff, right? I should wait til I’m feeling a bit… healthier, but I don’t want to wait around. I’ve so far had advice from two very unlikely people: my friend that’s been married for nearly 23 years, and my ex ex-girlfriend that I dated many moons ago. They've both been super nice, and I’ll take all the help I can get. Having that kind of support means a lot, especially when you’ve had your heart crushed and burned.

[![spoilers.](/media/images/blog/aboutaaron.jpg)](/media/images/blog/aboutaaron.jpg)
_Now what way would you swipe?_

Don’t worry, I still have some secrets. My personal life isn’t an open book! That’ll happen when I’m offered six figures for my memoirs.

Still, I bet all the coolest people around are reading this post and follow me on Facebook. Tell a friend? Wait, I don't think that's how matching on Tinder works.

Send all advice my way! I’ll take anything anyone is willing to offer.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I got Tonsillitis]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/21/i-got-tonsillitis/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/21/i-got-tonsillitis/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I came back from training in Auckland last week feeling awful - sweaty, sore, weak and disoriented. It had been slowly escalating during the week, but after my flight back it was destroying me.

I got home and then went to the after hours doctor, who very quickly diagnosed me with tonsillitis. He got me to use my phone to take a photo of the back of my throat and I could see an inflamed area of welting flesh weeping pus.

I’m on a double dose of antibiotics to kill whatever is doing this to me. They’re knocking me about! The doctor warned me they would. After 3 days I’m finally able to get a solid bit of sleep, so stuff is definitely improving.

It’s very inconvenient too! After my time training at the office I was feeling very eager to get back out in the field for work, but instead it’s been a week of being sweaty and exhausted (In a bad way!).

In other news, the house stuff is all done. My lawyer agreed to meet over Zoom to sign and finalize stuff - a big help, as there is no way I could do an in person meeting.

It feels good to finally have that all behind me. I’m excited! Optimistic! Looking forward to moving forward. When I’m feeling better, at least. Right now being optimistic is hoping I’ll sleep all night without waking up sore and sweaty.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uninteresting]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/15/uninteresting/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/15/uninteresting/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, training here is going well! It's intimidating to understand a big and complicated machine, but the boss man Karl ensures us it's not as bad as it looks. It's all sensors and belts and mechanicalness.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/belts.jpg)](/media/images/blog/belts.jpg)
_Does anyone really know what all that is?!._

I got frustrating news too. I had high hopes of getting a company vehicle provided to me, and I could take it back with me from Auckland while I'm up here. Currently I'm using an old Mazda 2 with the back seat taken out. It's…. Dying, and extremely frustrating to use for work. I just got the news that, despite my boss being optimistic, they can't provide me with a vehicle right now. I'm tempted to buy something myself! But then they'll probably force a company car on me a few months after I've shelled out for some kind of SUV. 

I had a night out on Tuesday. I think it might be the first one… ever? It was in the city and I was actually drinking rather than being the sober driver.

It was good to hang out with a colleague, that was really nice! But holy crap, I should get my phone taken off me when I'm a bit sloshed.

I ended up getting locked out of my hotel room, and I had people phoning me worrying about what I was doing when I wasn't answering my phone. I left messages with… someone that made them be very concerned about me.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/drink.jpg)](/media/images/blog/drink.jpg)
_All fun and games to start with._

I'm sorry! I didn't mean to cause distress. That's for caring about me. Also, thank your mum for caring about me too.

The whole day after I felt…. Sunburned. Is that odd? First hangover in 15 years, what an odd feeling.

If you've followed my ravings over the last few weeks you'll see things like affection, trust, love and loyalty being these huge building blocks of relationships. I can give all I've got in these areas, and I've discovered just how amazing of a feeling that is. Doing loving things for someone I love is better than I ever imagined.

But hell, I missed a big one. I'm so boring. Given the things I do for fun, I doubt anyone would tolerate me being the #1 person in their life for an extended period.  
 
I got told by someone that all this emotional distress I've been over recently had driven me to be a person I'm totally not.

Maybe that's a good thing. I need to be more fun and interesting, even if that pushes me way out of my comfort zone and makes me do things I just don't like to do. I mean, I don't want to just be… happy and content with who I am. That's not working! If I want to be around people I need to suck it up and do what they do - what all the kids say are fun! I just hope I don't become down and depressed, or arrogant and an asshole. But maybe that could even be better for me?

I'll leave my phone at home.

My head hurts. I miss my former girlfriend so much.

Everyone tells me I should move on. My friend Mark says he'd lock me in his basement if I ever got back with her! A colleague here I shared my story of heartbreak with said I can do better, but I think she was just being nice. Just this morning boss man Karl asked if I was married yet. Owch, that hurt. Last time I was up here in November I wouldn't shut up about my amazing girlfriend and our huge plans, now I only bring it up when drunk and stupid.

I love her, but I really shouldn’t - for her benefit and mine. Right now I'd saw my leg off to be back with her, but that'd be fruitless as it's more and more clear every day that she just isn't interested at all. And that kills me a tiny bit.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/nZXRV4MezEw`

But hey, anyone have great advice for moving on? Other than drink. That didn't work out so well for me.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cookies]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/11/cookies/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/11/cookies/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Eat your heart out, Toffee Pops.

As promised, I’m going to start sharing my baking experiences. This sure makes a nice change from emotional heartbreak and despair - I’m branching out!

I’m not sure I’m good enough to have a signature dish, but this would be the closest thing I have. It’s my take on Toffee Pops, but turned up to 11.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies1.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies1.jpg)
_In two styles._

You’ll need:

* Sweet Short Pastry
* Condensed Milk
* Butter
* Brown Sugar
* Compound chocolate of your choice
* Any toppings for extra flair

First, here is my best cheat ever. Rather than making a biscuit from scratch, I just use a cookie cutter on sheets of frozen sweet short pastry. It doesn’t come out anything like what you’d expect pastry to be; it’s a crumbly crunchy cookie base.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies2.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies2.jpg)
_This works. Don't question me!_

Take your sheet, cut it into small circles and place it on a lined baking tray. Bake it at 200 degrees celsius for 10 minutes. After 10 minutes they might still look underdone, but this is deceptive! They’ll firm up and set while they’re cooling. If you bake them for much longer, you’ll end up with a horrible burnt taste on them.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies3.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies3.jpg)
_Fully baked, even if they look pale._

Leave these to cool on the baking tray. If you try to move them while they are cooling, they might fall apart.

Now here is the tricky part - making caramel. It’s volatile stuff. Up there with enriched uranium and antimatter. Be attentive when doing this or it will burn!

Melt a little bit of butter and twice as much brown sugar in a big pot. Keep it on the heat til the butter and the sugar are all combined and bubbling a little. Now, add a full can of condensed milk and stir. Lower the heat to low, and keep gently stirring for about 15 minutes. It’s a long time! If you’re tempted to go do something else? Don’t. The sugar content in the caramel can burn super fast if you stop stirring. You’ll be able to tell when it’s done when the caramel is a nice dark colour and it’s started to thicken.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/YabLEQF73XI`

Leave it to cool a little bit, but not all the way to room temperature. You need it to still be a little bit runny for the next step.

Get a mug of hot water and dip a spoon in it. One cookie at a time, spoon a heap of caramel on top. It’s sticky, messy stuff! Between each cookie, dip the spoon back into the hot water to help the caramel slide off easier. You can use a butter knife to smooth out the caramel if you want, but it’s also nice to have that uneven homemade aesthetic.
Leave these to cool, and the caramel should become hard but still gooey.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies4.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies4.jpg)
_All Caramel but still topless._

Now for the chocolate topping. Don’t buy a block of standard chocolate from the confectionary aisle. You need to get compound chocolate, also called cooking chocolate. Normal chocolate has a tendency to split when heated, meaning the fats start to separate out. It’s super tricky to deal with and get a nice response. Compound chocolate has been emulsified with vegetable fats, and this makes it so much more resilient to being melted.

Melt your cooking chocolate over a very low heat in a pot. When it’s turned to liquid I use a teaspoon to drizzle it over each cookie. A long time ago I tried dipping each cookie into the chocolate, but things just fell apart and made a big mess.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies5.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies5.jpg)
_The right cooking chocolate doesn't split!_

Leave it to set and you’re good to go. I’d recommend not putting them in the fridge, or you can end up with cookies that taste like fridge.

You can do neat things too! With the batch I made today I did two varieties: standard Milk Chocolate topped, and my signature Cookies and Cream. For those I crushed up Oreos and sprinkled it over some white chocolate topped cookies while the chocolate was still semi melted.

And there we go! It’s super easy, even if it does get a bit messy.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies6.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies6.jpg)
_Too many._

I made way too many of these on a Sunday afternoon, and have no one to share them with. I doubt these will survive in my carry-on luggage up to Auckland. Anyone want some cookies?
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can you feel life tangle you up inside]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/10/can-you-feel-life-tangle-you-up-inside/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/10/can-you-feel-life-tangle-you-up-inside/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I’m good!

I can’t really complain, as much as I want to.

Last time I was emotionally distraught was when my father passed, and just like last time I’m getting by with a little help from my friends. Gin and Ice Cream also help.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/gin.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gin.jpg)
_I regretted this combination._

I’m such a juvenile. I had such a sheltered upbringing, and for many years of my life I didn’t really get out much. When you’re a full time caregiver, living with your elderly dad? Social life takes a back seat. I didn’t complain, I’m hardly a social animal.

But now that leads to here. Kids these days have probably had their heart broken a handful of times before they start to drive! Here I am north of 30 dealing with this for the first time. I just need to grow up.

(I’m not old! Just getting that way.)

Yes, it’s hard! It’s painful, stressful, depressing, sad, full of regret, anxiety ridden and many other things.

And that’s OK. Life is about calculated risks, and this is the consequence of that. Fortune favours the bold! Things that you think happen for the worst are sometimes just making room for the best to happen (Thanks, Jackie!). When you’re in the deepest pit of despair it seems impossible that things will get better and you’ll feel good again, but that’s just illogical. My worst could always be worse, and my normal is better than many peoples. 

I think I’ll always miss what I had, just because it was so…. Perfect. For a while there it really was the dream. But maybe that can be fuel to motivate me to strive towards something even better. Is that even possible? I don’t know, but I’ll find out.

I hate it when a plan doesn't come together. I hate the responsibility of making decisions, but I get really uncomfortable when I’ve got no idea what is going on. I like to be aware of my surroundings. Renovating a house? It’s full of surprises! Nothing goes to plan, and to succeed you have to adapt. I wasn’t prepared for that. I find it tough with work too. Sometimes I have a good idea of how my day will go, but then I get swamped with a heap of remedial calls that changes everything I had planned.

Being more dynamic and adapting to changes rapidly is a skill I’m slowly getting better at.

I’m really getting out of shape. While I was a caregiver for my dad I put a huge amount of effort into exercise. I would run once a day and would watch what I eat. These days I’m working a lot, and often eat when I’m out and about. It’s not good! Lately I’ve just been skipping meals altogether. I just can’t summon the motivation to eat. It doesn’t help - when I do finally eat it’s normally something horrid. I’ll work on it.

Next week I’m off to Auckland for work. I’m looking forward to it. Day to day I never see any colleagues, it’s just me out there on my own getting stuff done. When I was up there last year I got to know a lot of the staff that work out of the head office. It’ll be good to catch up with them.

Onward and Upward. To the future.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tell me the song and I'll sing it]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/04/tell-me-the-song-and-i-ll-sing-it/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/04/tell-me-the-song-and-i-ll-sing-it/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Well, that was helpful.

Turns out this writing thing is really beneficial, I’m glad I can get back into it again.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/N2ICtCO8TCw`

I really appreciate all the friends and family that reached and out offered support. Over the past few months I have been making myself really isolated. I was fighting a battle on many fronts, and made decisions based on getting advice from a million different people rather than thinking for myself. Because I was wanting to avoid conflict I just kept to myself - but then I shattered that line of thinking and posted here for all the world to see!

I hate feeling stupid, but often I deserve to.

I know many will think of me as an idiot for a recent choice I’ve made, but I own my decision. I’m at peace, and I don’t think I would be if I had made a different choice. 

Yes, I’m being a little vague! I’m sure the smart people reading this will figure out what I’m referring to.

One thing I failed to mention before was the biggest source of joy in my life right now: being the #1 Uncle!

[![My Dad.](/media/images/blog/uncle.jpg)](/media/images/blog/uncle.jpg)
_Censored to protect the brave and bold._

My nephew is awesome. He’s such an energetic, clever and positive character. I say character just because he’s so dang interesting! He’s not some boring lame-o boy, but a super interesting, dynamic and sharp little man. He’s fun to be around, even if a bit exhausting. When I’m around him I try to give him all my attention, as opposed to most boring adults!

He’s like a better version of me! He’s into everything I was at his age - Dinosaurs, Batman, Pokemon, Video games - but he doesn’t have any of my aspergic shortcomings. He thinks I’m awesome, and it’s quite the boost to my ego! I often visit at the end of the day after I finish work close to his place, and everytime he wants me to have a sleepover. 

Emotional Support Animals are a thing, so maybe I’ve just got an Emotional Support Nephew. I highly recommend it.

I have a lot of idle time with work. I’m often waiting around to get access to a site or waiting for a machine to reboot. Now that this here blog site is back up and running I might use some of that time to write stuff. I promise it won’t all be about the failings of my personal life! I’m sure everyone is interested in my adventures in experimental baking.

[![My Dad.](/media/images/blog/chocy.jpg)](/media/images/blog/chocy.jpg)
_Caramel chocky goodness._
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[And I am feeling so small]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/03/and-i-am-feeling-so-small/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/03/and-i-am-feeling-so-small/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It's an odd dichotomy.

It feels like the status quo of me living on my own, working and maintaining this house has been this way forever, but at the same time it feels so recent that my Dad passed away. It's coming up on two years. Two years! I still find myself wanting to talk to him about everything. I see stuff at the supermarket and still, instinctively, ask myself if I should get it for him. 

[![](/media/images/blog/dadflit.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dadflit.jpg)
_It still feels like very recent history._

It still hurts when I dwell on it, but in a way I’m glad it does. It means I still remember everything about him so well, and I hope I always do. Sometimes people tell me how proud my dad would be of me, with my work and how I’ve pushed on with life. But the most important thing to me is hoping my Dad knew just how proud I was of him. 

And Work? My job sure is something! Some days it can be extremely long, leaving at 7am and getting home at 10pm. It's tough, but I don't mind hard work, especially when I don't have much else to do. 

I’m a Field Engineer! I drive around the wider area fixing things that are broken. It’s impossible to plan out a day. If something is broken? I have as little as four hours to get to the machine and fix it, no matter what the fault might be. Sometimes it feels like I'm being stretched in 10 different directions, really struggling to hit targets.

I drive all over the wider area, some days racking up more than 500 kilometers of driving. When you've got the field service management team barking at you to get to three different urgent jobs ASAP that are two hours of driving from each other, I do sometimes feel like I'm going to be torn apart! 

[![](/media/images/blog/badge.jpg)](/media/images/blog/badge.jpg)
_It's a real job! I have a name badge._

But it's a good job. I feel very fortunate that I was able to get it. I started the job by being thrown in the deep end, and through much stress and struggle I learned to swim. I’m proud of what I do, and always do the best work I can. I know I’ve still got a lot to learn, but I’m getting there. It's always a goal to get a job you enjoy and are good at, and I think this is the closest I'll ever get to that.

Right now, long and exhausting days at work are a helpful distraction from other, more heartbreaking things in life.

I met the love of my life. It hasn’t gone too well. We dove into buying a "renovators delight" house together way too early in our relationship, and the stress and tension that came from that was too much.

[![](/media/images/blog/houseimage3.jpg)](/media/images/blog/houseimage3.jpg)
_Memories are made of art._

Sad is an apt word to use, but it's also extremely… frustrating. I was in a loving, affectionate relationship with the only person I've ever met that I would want to spend the rest of my life with.  My list of regrets is huge. I would give anything to have a time machine to travel back to make better decisions and hope that it would lead to me being a better partner. In the stress of everything, I did and said things that hurt her. 

#### **[And I will stumble and fall. I’m still learning to love, just starting to crawl.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-2U0Ivkn2Ds)**


We split up over a month ago, and I sold her my half of the house at cost. I still care about her. If I could have any superpower, any magic spell or any wish, I would want for me to be exactly what she wants and needs. Right now I just need to have patience and give her space.

For now? I’m in a holding pattern. Being hopeful and taking one day at a time. Let’s see where this ongoing battle between hope and despair we all call “Life” takes me.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About me.]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/10/19/about-me/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/10/19/about-me/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
This is not your usual About Me page, but I’m sharing here five things about me that aren’t very common knowledge. These include things I’m not very comfortable publishing, but I’m hoping getting them out there will, in some strange way, take a small bit of the load off me.

### 1. I take medication for my mental health.

This is something I’m not eager to admit. Seeing [local TV personality Matt Chisholm talk about his struggles with mental health](https://twitter.com/MattChisTVNZ/status/1177127318977798145) makes it seem…  acceptable to be more open about this. 

I hate it. Despite the compassion and reassurance from media personalities and health professionals that it’s an okay thing to do, I still don’t like it. Even if it is irrational, I feel weak and defective because of it. I’ve never gotten into drugs or alcohol, as having substances alter my mental state is something I’m not a fan of.

But since I lost my Dad earlier this year I just haven’t been coping very well. Functioning day-to-day can be a huge challenge, and going against the advice of my doctor would only make it worse.


### 2. I hate printed stuff on clothing.

This is an odd one. None of my clothes feature writing or graphics printed on them, unless it’s something that was given to me. I don’t like being a walking sign, whether it’s for a clothing brand’s logo or some quirky slogan on a t-shirt. Also, the feeling of screen printing on fabric is uncomfortable.

### 3. I am very poorly traveled.

The total area that I’ve traveled over in the past 10 years:

[![travel.](/media/images/blog/travel.png)](/media/images/blog/travel.png)
_It's the bit in red. Look closer._	

Before that, the distance wasn’t much further than a few family holidays three hours drive away from the small town I live in. It’s not that I don’t want to travel, but between being very introverted in nature and looking after my father for many years, the opportunity never came up. Due to my work being on a very casual basis right now, I doubt I’ll have the means to go on epic long distance voyages any time soon. Besides, I wouldn’t want to travel for whimsical reasons. I’m not a tourist.

### 4. I’d rather walk than drive.

Driving is tedious. While I do it as required, if there is an option to walk I’d much rather do that. If I need something from the supermarket or have an errand to run, I’ll strap my boots on and march there under my own power. It saves money and saves the planet!

### 5. I have Asperger syndrome.

I hate admitting this, mainly because I’m not a fan of giving people labels. I was diagnosed in my late teens, soon after leaving school. I think my parents were relieved that there was an actual reason as to why I was so… weird. 

If you’re interested in what this is all about, [the Wikipedia article here is generally relatable to me.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asperger_syndrome) It’s not at all fun, but I like to think I’m used to it. Things people do without thinking, like most social interactions, are things I’ve had to focus on learning how to do properly. 

I’m still not good at it. It’s probably one of many reasons as to why I’ve been struggling to find employment. It’s a bit upsetting, but I understand.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Printer Troubleshooting]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/26/printer-troubleshooting/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/26/printer-troubleshooting/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I was recently contacted to help an elderly person in my small town get his printer working. The printer was consistently printing poorly, with text coming out very blurry and smudged.

My troubleshooting plan was to start simple, and work from there.

[![spoilers.](/media/images/blog/spoilers.jpg)](/media/images/blog/spoilers.jpg)
_Spoilers: My hands get dirty!_

First was a printer head clean, which was accessed using the touch screen menu on the printer. Running this diagnostic would also print a test pattern to help me see what the specific problem could be. It took a while, but the resulting pattern was rather fuzzy. The edges of fonts had blurry trails and lacked any sharp edges. This matched how the problem had been described to me!

I tried using the printer's auto alignment function next. This function does all kinds of magic to make sure the software is aware of exactly where the print heads are, and can compensate for their position to improve accuracy. This at least seemed to improve things slightly, but unfortunately didn't resolve the issue entirely.

Next up was a manual head align. This is a process where the printer outputs an A4 page full of different patterns, and you inspect each of them and apply the settings to the printer based on which patterns are the most well aligned. This process is done for each printing head: Black, Cyan, Magenta and Yellow.

The trouble is that none of the resulting patterns were good enough. Now it was time to get a little dirty...

I disassembled the printer to get access to the actual print heads, and removed them from the printer. The heads didn't seem too dirty, but could definitely be improved.

[![cart.](/media/images/blog/cart.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cart.jpg)
_The polished printer heads._

I used cotton swabs and isopropyl alcohol to clean up the heads. Surprisingly, a lot of built-up dried ink came off that wasn't obvious with a simple visual inspection. After cleaning the assembly, I left it out to dry for an hour. When I put it back in the printer I tried another head clean.

The result was an improvement, but still not ideal.

I went in much deeper and disassembled the printing head assembly. It was flooded with excessive ink. Googling for more information showed me that a plastic plate inside the head should be clean and white, but this one was soaked in ink. I cleaned it out as best as I could, but still couldn't get it shiny and white like most example photos online showed.

[![white.](/media/images/blog/shouldbewhite.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shouldbewhite.jpg)
_That should be completely white._

I put it all back together, and another test page showed very little improvement.

I was now reasonably sure that the fault was either with the ink cartridges or a defect in the printing head. No amount of cleaning was going to resolve this issue, and any further diagnosis would require extra parts to test if my ideas had any merit.

So, not a great result. Still, the printer was better than when I started! It's unfortunate that getting replacement parts for this printer could very well cost more than an entirely new printer, one that would likely be an updated model with better features.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chrome App Mode: webapps with elegance]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/23/chrome-app-mode-webapps-with-elegance/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/23/chrome-app-mode-webapps-with-elegance/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Browser-based apps have progressed a lot since the laggy and unresponsive experience that Google Docs was when it launched over a decade ago. Thanks to the power of HTML5, tasks from office suites to video editing now perform well enough that the browser can be a viable app platform for daily use.

However, having all this functionality tied to a tab in your Chrome or Opera browser can make it somewhat inelegant, especially if you're like me and many tabs open. Additionally, the address and navigation bars  just aren't needed for most web apps, and take up valuable screen space unnecessarily.

Thankfully, there is a feature in Chrome that can allow you to setup a web app to behave more like a traditional Windows program - app mode. This mode takes away the navigation, address and settings controls that most browsers have, and leaves you with a clean, dedicated window for your browser based apps.

Setting up is easy. Make a new shortcut to the Chrome browser, and add in the “--app” modifier along with the address of the web app you want to use.

Changing the shortcut target from:

```
C:\GoogleChromePortable64\GoogleChromePortable.exe
```

To

```
C:\GoogleChromePortable64\GoogleChromePortable.exe --app=https://docs.google.com
```

[![Shortcut.](/media/images/blog/portableshortcut.png)](/media/images/blog/portableshortcut.png)
_Shortcut menu, accessed by right clicking the shortcut and going into properties._

This trick also works with an offline website - just use the Windows file path of the home page in the Chrome shortcut, rather than a web address.

Running Chrome in app mode also changes the icon that displays in the taskbar. It no longer displays the Chrome compass, but instead uses the favicon.ico of the website. This goes a long way to hiding completely that the program is a browser-based app, making it seem more like a standard Windows program to the user.

If you're using a browser-based web app for anything mission critical or where security is a requirement, you can also have an independent instance of the Chrome browser specifically for running an app. This can be on the same machine as a standard Chrome installation without making any unwanted changes to your installed Chrome browser. To do this, just install **[the PortableApps version of the Chrome browser](https://portableapps.com/apps/internet/google_chrome_portable)** to a local directly on the machine. After it's installed just right click on the Chrome executable, click “Send To”, then click “Desktop (create shortcut)”. Now add the app parameter to your newly created desktop icon. Before doing this, you can run the portable version of Chrome normally and tweak any settings you want the webapp's browser environment to have - ideal if you want to completely lock it down for security, such as never remembering passwords, only accepting specific security certificates, or flushing all saved and cached data when exiting the app.

[![browser.](/media/images/blog/browser.png)](/media/images/blog/browser.png)
_A clean experience, you might not know it's a browser based app!_

You can install as many instances of the PortableApps version of Chrome as you need, and perform the same shortcut trick for each one. If you have several browser-based web apps in use, and want them all completely independent from other browsing activities, you can deploy the portable version of Chrome as many times as required.

Using this PortableApps method also allows you to use a different account for each installed copy. This can be very useful: you can have access to both a personal and a business Google Docs suite in two different windows without having to cycle between logins.

There are some other modifiers you can add to the shortcut to further tweak the way the webapp works. Adding --incognito will make the browser run in, as you'd expect, incognito mode. You can also enter chrome://flags into the address bar while the browser is running in normal mode to get access to an extensive range of additional settings.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IT: Getting an old Windows machine running]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/22/it-getting-an-old-windows-machine-running/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/22/it-getting-an-old-windows-machine-running/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
After throwing my friend Mark a surprise birthday party yesterday, I was given the task of getting a decade old Windows machine working and running Windows 10. I was given a Windows 7 Ultimate N key and this computer - a four hard drive behemoth - and set to work.

[![mynemesis.](/media/images/blog/nemesis.png)](/media/images/blog/nemesis.png)
_My nemesis for an evening._

I plugged it in and turned it on. The lights came on and the fans spun up. The monitor sprung to life!

There was a black screen, no POST beep codes and after a few seconds then everything shut down. Before the fans could spin down entirely, the computer started up again! This was an endless loop that it had got locked into.

My initial hunch was that it was a power supply issue, but a suggestion given to me was that the problem was more likely to be with the memory. I juggled the four memory DIMMs in the four slots available, and managed to fix the issue by having just a single 1GB stick out of 4GB in the machine. Even after this the machine was only intermittently working, sometimes entering the same loop seemingly at random. It still entered the boot loop, but reseating the memory again fixed it. After a while of playing around, the issue seemed to occur less frequently.

Yay, progress!

Next up was sorting out the drives. There were four in this machine, and I was told that the operating system would need to be on the smallest one. I tried removing the drives to look at the labels, but an awkward case design made this difficult. To ensure I knew what size each drive was, I unplugged all but one at a time and then proceeded to boot into the BIOS to get the model numbers, and these included the capacity of each drive.

There was a 1000 GB, a 1500 GB, a 2000 GB and a 250 GB. Easy choice!

I plugged in nothing but that 250GB drive, plugged in my Windows 10 USB installation media, and hit F12 during boot to see the boot menu.

I was presented with odd, 2008 era menu options. I had to choose between USB-HDD, USB-FDD, USB-ZIP, and USB-CDROM. Boot from a ZIP drive! That's a blast from the past. Unfortunately none of them worked for booting from the USB drive. So I bridged the jumpers on the CMOS to reset the BIOS settings, but still no cigar. Going through all the settings in the BIOS and changing everything related to booting and USB support still had no luck.

So I booted up what was on that 250GB drive. It started to load Windows, but it just hung. I rebooted into safe mode and it worked! After a quick Google, I found that disabling all programs and services that start on boot and doing a “clean boot” was a common trick to getting normal Windows to start.

It worked! Here I was in Windows…. 7. Unactivated. The key I was given didn't work. I tried running an upgrade to Windows 10, but that either required an activated version of Windows 7 or a valid Windows 10 key.

Looking carefully, I noticed that they key I had was for Windows 7 Ultimate N. I wondered if the N made a difference to the keys working. I couldn't see any reference to this N version in the Control Panel, so on my laptop I headed over to **[archive.org and downloaded a Windows 7 Ultimate N ISO](https://archive.org/details/Win7UltimateNSP1)** and wrote it to my USB memory stick using the **[Windows USB/DVD Tool](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=56485)**.

I ran a clean install of Windows 7, and after an extremely slow install process I entered the activation key. I didn't have much hope.

But it worked! Windows 7 Ultimate N was activated.

Installing Windows 10 using the current activation credentials should be a straightforward process. Downloading and executing the official Media Creation Tool for Windows 10 gives the option not only to make a bootable USB memory stick, but also to upgrade the current machine. On the first try, the installer wouldn't get very far: Windows 10 demands a minimum of 2GB memory. I crossed my fingers and slotted in another memory module. Yay, luck was with me and there was no boot loop.

 It took a few hours to complete the install process, but afterwards I was presented with this:

[![didntwork.](/media/images/blog/windowserror.png)](/media/images/blog/windowserror.png)
_It didn't work._

Ugh. Another Google search showed this error can happen sometimes, and a common solution was just to try again. And it worked! After another few hours Windows 10 Pro N was cleanly installed and activated.

It was a 10 year old PC, so Windows 10 runs rather slowly. I figured that what would help would be getting the PC back to its full 4GB of memory! I went back into the BIOS and tweaked any settings related to memory to try to get it working, hoping the issue wasn't something hardware related. I installed another stick of memory, and it booted. Going all the way, I put all four in - the evil boot loop showed up again. I took that last memory module out and reseated it very firmly, really pushing it down and engaging the clips in the sides.

And with luck being a lady, it booted into Windows 10 and showed all 4GB of installed memory. While I don't want to risk testing it, my guess is that either the memory sticks or slots on the motherboard are a bit flakey and abused with age. A little wiggle or shake might make them misbehave, but the hope is that keeping the machine stationary and stable will give it the best chance of running without fault.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pearson Vue, Microsoft and Upskilling]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/05/pearson-vue-microsoft-and-upskilling/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/05/pearson-vue-microsoft-and-upskilling/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
On my quest to upskill, I decided to take exams online to gain some Microsoft certified qualifications. Starting at the beginning, I opted for **[MS-900: Microsoft 365 Certified Fundamentals.](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/learning/exam-ms-900.aspx)** I signed up to take the exam with the online provider **[Pearson Vue](https://home.pearsonvue.com/)** at 9pm this Thursday night, and spent the last few days doing not much else other than studying. These exams are not free: $184 in local (NZ) currency. It might not seem like much, but money is tight for me right now.

I was a bit nervous, but I was feeling good! Understanding the ins and outs of Microsoft's cloud platform took a little bit of grasping, but I got there. I was very confident leading up to the exam, but still went over the material many times in preparation. I even took hand-written notes! Surely that helps with information retention.

I went through the setup process at 8:30pm, just like it told me - be there half an hour early! During the setup process I had to:
- Position to get my webcam to get a clear view of my desk
- Take multiple photos of my desk, the space behind it and to the left and right
- Take clear photographs of my government issued ID, front and back.

That all went well, and I was all set and ready to go. The last step was to read and accept the Non-Disclosure Agreement.

I tried to click “Yes” to agree. I couldn't, clicking yes did nothing.

I tried to scroll. I couldn't.

I use a big 4K TV as a monitor with 100% display scaling, I think this meant that all the text in the agreement was on the screen at the same time. The program for taking the exam had gone full screen, covering everything including the start bar, meaning I was unable to change any Windows settings.

No matter what I did, I could not progress.

All the preparation material warned me not to have any other applications open or to close the exam application at any time. The only option I had was to click the “Chat” button to get help.

After waiting a bit, an exam proctor chatted with me.

“You need to scroll down in the agreement before you can click yes and accept it”

I can't scroll down. The scroll bar is greyed out.

There was a timer counting down in the top right corner: I had five minutes to accept the agreement.

I started to panic. I tried clicking many times. I tried scrolling down. I tried using tab to highlight the “Yes” option, but I couldn't.

A voice came over my speakers. It was the exam proctor, now trying to help over voice chat. No matter what I did, I could not scroll down and I couldn't click yes.

Then the time ran out. The screen now told me I had failed: scoring 0 out of 700.

Before the voice chat ended I was told that I had to contact customer support to resolve this issue.

I asked if there was a way I could lower my screen resolution or switch to my laptop to try and take the exam. That wasn't an option, the only thing I could do is to submit a case where I would get a result in 3-5 business days. I pleaded to let me re-take the exam sooner - I was prepared and ready, having spent the week getting to this point. Nope, it's 3-5 business days or nothing. I don't even know if the case will be in my favour.

At a guess, the agreement page had a trigger to enable the Yes option when the page has been scrolled to the bottom. However, as my high resolution display could show the whole document at once there was no way to scroll down and no way to enable the Yes button.

It was impossible for me to start the exam.

I hate this. I felt like throwing up, but now I just feel frustrated, a little bit angry and extremely disappointed. I would think that a place that focuses on IT training and exams wouldn't have issues like this. It's very sloppy.

[![exam.](/media/images/blog/exam.png)](/media/images/blog/exam.png)
_I didn't take any exam._

I'm eager to get this exam done! This might seem like a little thing, but for me it's crushing.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Information on Veon 4K TV's]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/08/02/information-on-veon-4-k-tv-s/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/08/02/information-on-veon-4-k-tv-s/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Since restarting my blogging venture last year the post that I've received the most feedback on [was my budget Veon TV review.](/blog/2018/11/28/veon-4-k-tv-review) I still get emails nearly a year later with people asking questions while they're looking into buying one, or wanting help with different settings and features. There is very little information on these TV's available online, [The Warehouse](https://www.thewarehouse.co.nz/) doesn't  provide any documentation and there are very few professional reviews available.

[![Veon.](/media/images/blog/veonmaster.jpg)](/media/images/blog/veonmaster.jpg)
_Veon: A brand shrouded in mystery._

Over the past few years I've had a few dealings with this ultra low cost brand, from my first 32” about 8 years ago to my recent acquisition of the rather large (65”) one now sitting in my lounge.

Because of these factors I've put together a FAQ, hopefully providing helpful information to people thinking about buying a Veon TV. If you can think of any other questions worth including, [feel free to drop me a line.](mailto:aaronights@gmail.com)

# Veon 4K TV FAQ

### Do the 4K models actually support full 4K?

Yes, based on my experience they can take a full 3840x2160 (4K) resolution signal at 60hz. They also support HDCP 2.2 copy protection, meaning 4K BluRay players and most streaming devices for Netflix and YouTube work fully.

There are a variety of options to take full advantage of this. Some choices are the Chromecast Ultra, DishTV Android media players, Xbox One S or X, Playstation 4 Pro and the 5th generation Apple TV - most things that output at 4K pair well with these TV's. Devices that don't support 4K will also work perfectly fine, but just don't get to take advantage of the TV's full resolution.

[![Streaming services like Netflix work very well.](/media/images/blog/netflix.jpg)](/media/images/blog/netflix.jpg)
_Streaming services like Netflix work very well._

### What features are built in?

Other than standard video signal inputs, the feature set is limited. Video playback from USB works, but doesn't support playing files at 4k resolution - the maximum appears to be 1080p. The built in TV tuner supports New Zealand Freeview in HD over a UHF aerial. Satellite Freeview support is not built in. There is limited functionality for recording Freeview TV to a USB drive, but this is limited to recording what is currently being watched.

There are some new Veon Smart TV models that are advertised as supporting Netflix and YouTube, but I haven't used one.

### How is the sound quality?

The audio coming out of the built in speakers is fine for dialog on a talk show, or the evening news, but for movies and gaming it's not great. Fortunately, every Veon TV I've used has many options for connecting an external sound system - HDMI Audio Return Channel (ARC), digital optical out, analog line level out and a headphone jack.

### Are the TVs wall mountable?

Yes, they work with a standard VESA mount. Based on listings online, 50 inch and smaller TVs use the 200mm by 200mm size mount, and the bigger TVs use 400mm by 200mm.

### What's the 3 year warranty like?

Veon TVs come with a 3 year warranty against defects. If an issue develops you take the TV, along with a purchase receipt, into a Warehouse store - even if the TV was purchased online. At the store the TV will be plugged in and turned on to identify the defect. If it's clear there is a fault with the TV (at least a fault that isn't caused by user error, like a cricket bat impact) it will be sent away for assessment. From my experience it will either be repaired or replaced, or the purchase price will be refunded.

Keep in mind you will need the purchase receipt to make a warranty claim! As soon as you have that receipt in your hand take a snap of it with your phone, and keep that photo safe.

### What are the optimal settings?

The menu isn't extensive, but going through and tweaking the settings is the best way to get the most out of these Veon TVs.

#### Picture settings

- *Picture Mode:*
To get the best picture quality possible, the picture mode needs to be set to “User” and each option needs to be adjusted manually. Getting the perfect picture will need differing settings for different models, and also the viewing environment the TV will be used in. In my experience the most benefit comes from lowering the Sharpness setting to 0. Most other settings work well near 50, with the Contrast working well at 55, and the Brightness and Colour slightly below in the low 40s.

- *Aspect Ratio:*
Generally, unless you are using older devices that don't output a widescreen image, this setting should always be set to “Just Scan”. This makes the TV use all of the incoming signal, without cropping the edges of the picture or adding any unnecessary image processing - this is the best option for most modern digital video devices. Old games consoles, VHS players and even early DVD players work well with a Veon TV, but this aspect ratio setting might need adjusting to get an undistorted picture with them.

- *Colour Temperature:*
Keeping these Red, Green and Blue values all at 50 is OK, but I found bringing down the Red just a little to around 45 makes the picture a little more balanced.

- *Noise Reduction:*
Unless you're using a really low quality video source, such as an older DVD player or home videos, this is best kept off.


#### Sound settings

- *Sound Mode:*
Keeping this on the Standard preset is best for the internal speakers - adding more bass just adds distortion. If using an external speaker system, adjust the audio settings on that rather than the TV.

- *Balance:*
If you only want sound coming out of one speaker for some reason? It's not a setting most people need to touch.

- *Auto Volume:*
This setting is meant to keep the volume levels somewhat normalised, but I can't really notice it doing anything.

- *Surround Sound:*
This adds an effect to the audio that is meant to “simulate” surround sound. I think it just makes everything sound like it was recorded in a large bathroom - not a very useful feature

- *SPDIF Mode:*
This setting changes the audio output format that is sent over HDMI and digital optical. If using a two channel stereo system like a sound bar, set this to PCM. If you have a surround sound home theatre system then setting this to Auto will allow the TV to pass through 5.1 channel Dolby Digital surround sound.

- *SPDIF Audio Delay:*
When using the digital sound outputs, this setting can be used to add a delay to the audio output to keep the picture in sync with the sound. Leave this on the default unless you notice issues with audio and video not lining up.

#### Option settings:

Here the settings are mainly about what language the menu and subtitles are in, but there are two settings here worth paying attention to: HDMI CEC and EDID.

HDMI CEC is a part of the HDMI connection that enables you to control devices, like DVD Players or Freeview boxes, using the TV's remote control. This is great at eliminating clutter, letting you control various HDMI devices all with one remote.

- *HDMI CEC:* Enables general CEC functionality

- *HDMI ARC:* Audio Return Channel. If you have a surround sound system or sound bar, you should connect it to the physical HDMI port on the Veon TV labeled “HDMI (ARC)” and turn this setting on. Using HDMI ARC will also enable the volume of the external sound system to be controlled with the Veon remote.

- *Auto Standby or Auto TV On:* Allows both for a Veon TV to turn on a connected HDMI device when it is turned on, and for a connected device to wake up the Veon TV from standby. This is great for allowing one button to turn on the TV, DVD Player and surround sound system together.

- *Device Control:* Enables the main point of CEC, allowing the Veon TV to control connected devices and vice versa. Generally, this must be enabled to allow other CEC based features to work.

- *Device List:* Shows a list of HDMI devices the TV has detected that support CEC. If you have an HDMI device that isn't listed here, try going into the menu options for that device and find a setting to turn CEC on. Keep in mind that not all HDMI devices support CEC.

[![CEC.](/media/images/blog/cec.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cec.jpg)
_CEC can allow easy control of HDMI devices with just one remote._

EDID, or Extended Display Identification Data, is the way the TV talks to attached HDMI devices to tell it what settings it supports. Leave this set to *EDID 2.0* unless you have an HDMI device that is outputting the wrong resolution or not working at all.


### Do they work well as a computer monitor?

Yes, I would recommend them. For nearly a year I've been using my 50” model as my monitor at my desk. Using the “Just Scan” aspect ratio setting makes the TV do one-to-one pixel mapping from my desktop computer. Fonts are very crisp and clear, and having such a big screen running at a high 3840x2160 resolution lets me use one monitor similar to how a multi monitor setup would work. I normally have a web browser, a document, messenger and a video displaying side by side, taking advantage of all the screen real estate. If you have the space for one at a workplace it's a low cost option worth considering. Keep in mind you'll need a computer with an HDMI port that is capable of outputting at 4k resolution.

[![Veon 4K TV as a desktop monitor.](/media/images/blog/monitor.jpg)](/media/images/blog/monitor.jpg)
_A Veon 4K TV as a desktop monitor._

### What's this Secret Menu I've heard about?

There is a hidden settings menu used by the factory to test and tweak these TVs. It has several hundred options that allow you to adjust just about any parameter you could imagine, but none of these options are named well and the menu is difficult to navigate.

If you want to use this menu, do so at your own risk! You could very well change a setting that makes your TV completely unusable.

The secret menu is accessed by pressing the Input/Source button on your remote, followed by 2, 5, 8 and 0.

### Finally, are these Veon TV's any good?

Yes, I think so. The picture quality is really, really good but you can notice flaws if you look for them - the black levels are slightly grey and the backlight isn't completely even. The casing is made out of plastic that doesn't feel very premium, but the bezel around the screen is so slim you'd never notice once you've set it up. Even the built-in menu looks rather crude, but in most scenarios you won't be navigating these very often.

[![_.](/media/images/blog/green4k.jpg)](/media/images/blog/green4k.jpg)
_A very good picture for a low cost display._

A budget Veon is not going to have the same picture quality or feature set as a branded TV that costs three times as much, but with tweaking and tuning the settings you can be pleasantly surprised at how good it can be for the price.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It doesn't go away, it changes]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/07/24/it-doesn-t-go-away-it-changes/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/07/24/it-doesn-t-go-away-it-changes/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### It's odd


The grief and feeling of missing Dad doesn't go away or lessen at all, it just changes.

In day to day life I find myself wanting to talk to Dad, share stuff with him, chat with him about things I know he'd be interested in. I go from being happy about finding out something, to less than a second later knowing I don't have my best friend to share it with.

It's simple things. Finding out about a concert at the local library, or a Railway documentary from Australian TV, are the kinds of things I've honed into seeking out for him. It's an automatic sense I've developed over many years, and it'll be a long time before it fades away.

One show my Dad and I regularly watched was Outback Truckers, a show all about long-haul truck drivers who drive across Australia. In a recent episode one of the star drivers, Sludge, was on his second working holiday here in New Zealand. When he's back in Australia Sludge drives a purple fuel tanker he named The Phantom, but here his task was to drive a big fruit truck from Cromwell in the South Island right up to Auckland. During the journey he had to stop for technical difficulties with the refrigeration unit, and ended up sleeping overnight right here in my home town, at the Levin railway yard.

Yes, the show Dad and I have watched was filmed just down the road. If we had known we would have both been there in a flash. Seeing this on the show was huge! I messaged everyone I could when I watched the episode, but it's upsetting that I can't share it with Dad.

[![Sludge was here.](/media/images/blog/railwayyard.jpg)](/media/images/blog/railwayyard.jpg)
_Sludge was here._

That railway yard is of special significance. My grandfather was a railway worker, and for the first 40 years of my Dad's life he lived in a house right there inside the yard. He always liked going there, if we were out and saw the signals indicating that a train would be passing soon we would park up and watch it speed past.

I'm slowly getting used to living on my own.

It's nice to have command over the house. Dad worked hard in his life to get the house, so I'm putting a lot of effort into keeping it clean and organised. I'm not going to slack off like a deadbeat bachelor, I want to keep this home in a condition that he would be proud of. In a way, keeping his house well-kept is a tribute to him.

I've still yet to go and sort through the stuff in his bedroom, but that'll be a big and rather emotional task that I'll probably need help with.

Being in this house alone wasn't entirely new, as during his last 6 weeks Dad was either in the hospital or the care home. In that time I was so occupied with visiting him, and attending to his logistics and his needs that I didn't stop to think about not only living without Dad, but even just living alone. It's something I wasn't anticipating, but I think it's going to be okay. Dad and I got on so well living together for many years, the idea of living with someone else right now isn't appealing.

One day at a time. Now that Dad's no longer around, I miss the small talk. To any friends and family reading this, please call in anytime you want. I'd appreciate it.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Good Deals 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/07/14/good-deals-2019/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/07/14/good-deals-2019/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
This chain of events started off on one of those long nights I was spending at the care home, staying up all night next to my Dad during his final weeks. I couldn't watch TV or play any kind of sound, nor did I want to put headphones on. I was there for Dad, and wanted to be alert. I sat there browsing my phone, mainly as a way to keep distracted from the gravity of his situation.

Talking to my friend Mark about sound systems, and the nuance of fidelity and connections, got me browsing the Facebook trading groups. One unit caught my eye - it was a Samsung 5.1 Blu-ray based sound system, listed as defective. Apparently the owner's daughter had been opening and closing the disc tray for fun, and it had eventually stuck closed. This wouldn't matter to me, because as long as the device would play audio from an external source over a digital connection, I could live without the disc tray.

Forty dollars later, and thanks again to Mark for running an errand for me to pick it up, it was mine. Other than the noted issue, it seemed to work well when I got it home and plugged it in. I took it apart easily, in case there was some way I could fix it, but couldn't see any way to get the drive to open at all. Nothing looked broken or out of place, but that thing was stuck solid.

So, with nothing to lose, I gave it some welly. By giving it more force than I felt comfortable with, I managed to pull the disc tray out! It was now rolling free. After putting it all back together, I was 50/50 about whether I'd broken the drive entirely, but a negative outcome wouldn't have made anything worse. As it turned out, the device now functions flawlessly, opening and closing, and reading all sorts of discs without error.

## Good Deal #1

Getting on this track got me hooked on wheeling dealing. I looked around for a TV to upgrade my lounge, to make it more suitable for social viewing and gaming events.

Remember the Veon TV I reviewed last year? It's still going well. Interestly, unlike most other brands, the budget Veons come with a full 3 year warranty. Someone in the Hutt Valley was selling a 65” Veon that had developed an issue - a thin seam of light down the middle. It was a 2016 model, so I was reasonably sure it was still in its warranty period. I messaged the seller to make sure they still had the receipt - the TV was originally ordered online, so he was able to print out a copy for me. The seller was asking $500 for it, but me feeling cheeky, I offered $350.

It was accepted!

The next time I was down that way, Mark and I went in his car and picked up the TV, and then immediately dropped it off at my local Warehouse store for a warranty claim. I was unsure if my claim would go through, but after about an hour of sorting out paperwork the store took the TV away for an inspection and repair.

## Good Deal #2

Knowing that I had a giant TV coming home at some point, I went searching for some way of mounting it. I looked into wall mounting - it would work well, but it's a fairly permanent solution. Plus an array of cables dangling down the wall doesn't look good. A cabinet would be nice, but just having something as big as a 65” TV resting on top of the cabinet felt like it would be rather unsafe.

Again, looking at the used listings, I came across a compromise - a cabinet with a fully built-in mount stand at the rear to secure a TV to - far safer than free-standing it. The seller was asking for $150, but I got him down to $100. I was happy, especially knowing the shop price of a new one is around $799 right now.

## Good Deal #3

I went around to pick up the stand, and it was in really good condition. Unfortunately there was no way it was fitting in my little Mazda. Mark again to the rescue! He kindly picked it up in his small, but surprisingly roomy, car.

On Wednesday I received a call from the TV store. My TV was deemed uneconomical to repair, so I needed to head into the store to sort things out.

I expected to be offered a gift card of some value, or maybe another refurbished replacement. At a stretch, possibly a new unit of the same model.

Nope, I was given a full refund of the original purchase price - $1000. I had just gained $650, given that I had purchased the TV a few days before for $350.

I still wanted a new TV, but with no good sales in The Warehouse or anywhere else I opted to wait. Now it's Friday, and once again I'm browsing online, this time on TradeMe. I noticed something interesting - someone was selling a 65” Veon TV, 8 months old, barely used and still with the box. She was asking $680. I offered $650, and they accepted.

## Good Deal #4

See what happened there? I got a near new, still under warranty, 65” 4K TV for…

Free! Well, other than the cost of all of this wheeling and dealing!

I'm here now, waiting on Mark. He has kindly offered to come and pick up the TV in his car just hours after I purchased it. The guy is amazing, did I ever say that? Between these errands and helping me with the death of my father, he is just such a kind, generous and good friend. I'd offer to paint his house, but he knows too well the many ways I'd screw that up. I hope I can help him out some day.

These deals all relied a lot on sheer luck. At any step in the process it could've all fallen apart. The first TV might have outright died and not have been claimable under warranty, the sound system could have not worked at all with a failed drive, and I could have been without transport to get any of it to my house.

Kenny Rogers was right when he sang about knowing when to hold ‘em and when to roll them, but even the best gambler must always be aware of the risks involved. These deals turned out amazing, but could have all hit the fan with a slight tweak to reality.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>