<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>aarond.me</title>
        <link>https://aarond.me/</link>
        <description>The blog of Aaron Davies</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 11:01:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Gridsome Feed Plugin</generator>
        <atom:link href="https://aarond.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This what I do on weekdays!]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/19/this-what-i-do-on-weekdays/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/19/this-what-i-do-on-weekdays/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Ever wondered what my work day is like? Well, unfortunately you’re about to find out!

My title is a Customer Engineer for a wide range of machines that process money: repairing, servicing and installing them in the lower North Island.  I get around! This is my exciting travel diary for Monday 19 July 2021.

The first thing I did while on the clock was finish off some documentation I was working on. It's a guide on how to clean and service some new hardware we’re rolling out. I enjoy writing, as you probably know, so I'm glad I can do some of that for work.

After sending that off, I jumped in my white Subaru and hit the road. I'm going to work!

You might think of a workplace as an office or workshop, but not for me. I have two places I can realistically claim to be my place of work: my car, and a storage unit.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/shed.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shed.jpg)
_Luxury workplace, no expense spared._

The storage unit is just a small garage sized lockup where I keep spare parts for work. Not overly glamorous, but fit for purpose. Today I had to ship a part that another engineer needed for a job somewhere else in the country. Oh, parts and logistics. What fun.

On my way driving to this shed I was assigned my first urgent job of the day.

In my line of work I have urgent jobs for things that are broken and need to be fixed ASAP, and also jobs that aren’t urgent, like servicing and cleaning of hardware.

The job that came in this morning was top tier urgent, and far away in Waiouru! After shipping out the spare part, I went on a road trip.

The most direct route I can take is a horrible windy wide road, but it has the nice benefit of this: Stormy Point Lookout. It's a huge viewpoint that lets you see the rolling rural land for miles and miles. I always try to pull over for 30 seconds to take a photo.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/stormy.jpg)](/media/images/blog/stormy.jpg)
_A view for miles and miles and miles._

After 2 hours of driving I hit Waiouru. It's very cold here! The job ended up being much more in depth than I expected, but I got it done.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/tank.jpg)](/media/images/blog/tank.jpg)
_Tanks for the fun, Waiouru._

Before I even started this job, I had another assigned to me: Dannevirke. Unfortunately, before I even could start driving to this job, another job with a higher priority came into my queue: Masterton.

That's a hell of a drive! But the idea of seeing the giant gumboot gave me the boost I needed.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/booty.jpg)](/media/images/blog/booty.jpg)
_I'm a big fan of a big booty._

Waiouru to Masterton is almost the longest drive I have for work. Before, when I was driving my old personal car, it was exhausting to go on such long voyages. But now I have this new machine with the power and features, it's so much more enjoyable.

Oh, in terms of time? I started work at my desk this morning at 8am, and now it's 6pm and I've still got two urgent jobs to finish.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/plane.jpg)](/media/images/blog/plane.jpg)
_I found this yellow aeroplane on my way to Masterton._

Masterton is a nice town! I've been here a lot lately, for both business and pleasure. The one thing I've learned is that everything shuts early, and it becomes a ghost town. To prove this point I took a selfie in the middle of the main street. I could have pitched a tent there.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/masterton.jpg)](/media/images/blog/masterton.jpg)
_No nightlife, not even early evening... life._

I often have delays in getting access to the machines I need to work on, and at Masterton I arrived 30 minutes before I could get access. I spent that time writing the majority of this blog post, and going for a brisk walk around downtown. It was extremely cold.

I was able to resolve the job at Masterton, but due to an ongoing issue with it I’ll be back - either tomorrow or the next day. And it’ll be a very complicated and long task.

I departed for Dannevirke, and by this point it was dark outside. Doing these long days is so much easier in the summer!

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/dannevirke.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dannevirke.jpg)
_Thor says hi._

The Dannevirke job was easy, just a matter of reseating a cable. After doing that it was getting close to 9pm, and I was hoping no new jobs came in - I wanted to go home!

I was tempted to get some unhealthy takeaways now, as I hadn’t eaten much all day. But no! I got home soon after 10pm and had Weet-Bix with some peanut butter for my dinner.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/dinner.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dinner.jpg)
_Meal of Champions._

I’m tired now. I’d better shower and get some sleep before I do it all over again tomorrow. Goodnight, kids!


]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dulling the sensors with shots and socks]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/18/dulling-the-sensors-with-shots-and-socks/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/18/dulling-the-sensors-with-shots-and-socks/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
What a fun time! Regular viewers will know that I had a mid-winter Christmas at my good friend Mark’s place last weekend. It was so fun! I opted to do something very unusual for me and partake of the alcoholic beverages. I stopped off at the booze shop on my way over, and ended up getting this.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/shots.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shots.jpg)
_A bucket of shots._

As you already know, the most high class and professional drinks all come in buckets. Turns out they weren’t horribly offensive, and they all went! I had… some.

And it actually went down okay! Being a little bit tipsy is better when you’re not feeling down and mopey. I did frustrate everyone around me by always redirecting conversation to two topics: my personal life, and how big the present I bought for the dice roll gift-giving game is.

Sorry to everyone that put up with that! I’ll leave that rambling here, where reading is optional. In social situations I need to shut up more.

And now the big exciting reveal of what the giant present was.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W13T6MjhXo8`

A Bear in a Chair! I haggled the chair on Facebook marketplace from $25 to $10, and got the giant teddy bear for $4 at a local op shop. I’m sure the handsome man that ended up with this awesome gift is currently enjoying it. As for me? I got the most awesome thing I could imagine.

[![socks.](/media/images/blog/socks.jpg)](/media/images/blog/socks.jpg)
_Pokemon socks! Not pictured: Batman socks._

Even if I did rave on, the beautiful people around me were very kind and generous with listening. A few takeaways:

* I should shut up and move on.
* Most people have gone through what I’m going through, this isn’t special.
* Get out there and meet people.

Whomever is… lucky enough to be in a relationship, or even just be friends, with me in the future? I don't want to frustrate them with how incredibly dense and stupid I am. I'll beg them to yell at me and hammer how they're feeling into my stupid wee head.

(Metaphorically. I actually have a big head.)

And I'll listen! I will shut up and listen, and also not bounce between extremes. Everyone gets pissed off with me, difficult times will come! But I need to have the… mental discipline to not start feeling hated because a partner or even a friend expresses how upset they are. I won't jump to the conclusion that they hate me - it'll be a grey area, not hot or cold! Tepid, lukewarm. In other words, nice! And also sustainable.

I really like doing things for people.

I help and do everything I can to make people happy and, as you'd imagine, that is amplified a hundred times over when I have a committed partner. And now I know that, even with all the affection, flowers and effort I put in, I just missed the obvious stuff I should be doing as a partner. The “are you happy?” and “what can I do to support you?” stuff. 

With everything going on, I lost track of how the other half was coping with stress and life. 

With hindsight? It didn’t even cross my mind as something I should be aware of. Despite the effort and time I was putting into the relationship, my constant worrying and my behaviour made the stresses worse. I was extremely selfish and now I’m embarrassed about how bad of a boyfriend I was, even though I would have done anything to make her happy and to make us work.

It sucks that I couldn't be what I so desperately wanted to be.

Live and learn. Due to a number of factors, that old relationship was probably doomed before it began, and now I know that I’m in a much better place to make whatever comes next for me succeed. I’m still full of problems, but hopefully now that I’m more aware of what they are I’m better equipped to mitigate them.

One last thing: I’m really wanting to help friends and family more. If you’re reading this? You count as friends! Is there anything I can write here that you’d like? Not about me - doing that only helps one person. Do you want a guide on how to do something tech related? More baking ideas? Reviews of movies, shows, food or wigs?

I’m here and, like Frasier Crane, I’m listening. If anyone just wants someone to talk to about anything at all, please reach out.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is me learning]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/16/this-is-me-learning/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/16/this-is-me-learning/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I know most people see this on Facebook and what not, but I like putting it here. It's more organized!

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5inAzzvq9tA`]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Check your emails]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/14/check-your-emails/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/14/check-your-emails/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, that was fun. I got up bright and early for a job in sunny (cold) Otaki. I was sitting in the car for 20 minutes, waiting for my security escort to show up before I went to my phone to figure out why it was so late.

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/otaki.jpg)](/media/images/blog/otaki.jpg)
_Not pictured: The cold and the wind._

The job had been delayed from 9am till midday. My work phone is appalling with notifications, and I didn't get the email that morning telling me about the delay.

Oh well, live and learn.

It's very cold. When I've been matching on Tinder somehow I always end up bringing up the weather. Yep, impressing girls with my slick and sexy weather banter! It's just… the weather is something I know we have in common. No one likes the cold! Well, maybe crazy ice queens. Do I want to date a crazy ice queen?!

Sure!

If anyone has advice on that whole conversation front, bring it! I’d be open to anything. Sometimes the conversation is just the best! It’s fun and it flows like butter on a hot grill. I don’t know, maybe when it’s difficult to get things rolling it’s a clear and present sign that stuff just won’t go anywhere.

I went back home to catch up on what I will call office work. Office work for me involves being frustrated with the worst part of my job - logistics. Getting parts, job details and stock status is a never ending fight. Sometimes I think this company is held together with string and staples given how some of this behind the scenes stuff is. 

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/officework.jpg)](/media/images/blog/officework.jpg)
_Home office._

I hate it when work is slow. I like working hard! The satisfaction of doing a good job is something I’m riding high on these days. Yep! Diving headfirst into work. First it was to distract from soul crushing regret and heartbreak, now it’s just… to distract from nothing? Hey! Focusing on nothing isn’t very fun.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logistics]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/13/logistics/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/13/logistics/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Today was Tuesday. I'm striving to just write about my days more often here, at least when work allows me to. I really don't think anyone will be that interested in it! It's more of a journal - but putting it out here for the world to see is a good way to keep me accountable.

I had a few minutes free today, waiting at home for a part to be delivered for work. Rather than sitting about, I organized my work bag. It's embarrassing to open up my bag in front of a customer when it's so cluttered! They gave me a car to look more professional, so having a toolbag that is orderly probably helps with that too.

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/shoe.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shoe.jpg)
_Hey! I've been busy._

This thing is falling to bits. I've had it for just over a year, and she's had a hard life.

Oh, I also magnetized my screwdrivers. 

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/gif.gif)](/media/images/blog/gif.gif)
_She asked me if I'd like to magnetize._

My head is very much not screwed on properly. Remember all those years ago when I wrote about how **[Dating is hard and I am very awkward?](https://aarond.me/blog/2017/04/11/dating-is-hard-and-i-am-very-awkward/)** Well, that hasn't changed.

I'm far more confident now. Wait, that might be wrong. I am far less nervous now? Yeah, more accurate. I'm  confident about who I am, but I'm not at all confident that a girl brave enough to get a drink with me will enjoy my company. I don't get anxious, I'm very blasé about it.

I do have anxiety attacks, but they're generally about work being overwhelming. For the longest time I was often crippled with anxiety about the failure of my relationship. I was still deeply in love, even when she pushed me away, and I really thought I'd ruined the only good thing that would ever happen to me. I was lucky to get such an amazing woman, and I royally screwed up.

But hey! I'm older and wiser now. It's not too bad, it's now just enough to make me take my job and my… life more seriously. 
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When I get that feeling]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/12/when-i-get-that-feeling/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/12/when-i-get-that-feeling/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It's been a little slow at work these past few weeks. I've had a few early starts, but other than that I've generally been home by about 7pm. It's unsettling! When work gets intense I can be out until close to midnight, but when there are no urgent calls coming in I just sit around at home… waiting. 

I find it difficult to do stuff when I'm on call like this. Can I bake? Watch a movie? Learn a new dance? Not really, if a priority one call comes in I've normally got to be out the door in 10 minutes just to meet resolution targets.

I dance far worse than I sing, so it's a very scary thought.

To be honest? While I'm single and alone I'd rather be working long hours than just loafing about at home. I just feel way less productive and accomplished when I'm sitting around home "relaxing" when I could be out there earning cash and fixing stuff!

And I love complaining about how much I work. I inherited my love of complaining from my Dad, so at this point it's a tradition.

My Instagram is still banned. I got suspended as someone reported me as an imposter. I think they were just jealous of my… wild and exciting life? Nope, maybe not that. It sucks, I liked posting my bad singing and torturing all the people following me! I've done the appeal process to try and get it back, but given how these companies work I'm not holding out hope.

But hey, to make up for it I put this on my dating profile.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkabUfWmzWk`

How the hell am I still single?!

It kind of worked? Some match with me and ask "What's up with that video?!" Others find it funny. Either way? It's something unique!

Right! Out the door at 6am tomorrow. I have to get to site for a scheduled job, but want to participate in the weekly meeting for work. Only way to make it fit is to leave very early, then sit in the car tuning into the exciting meeting from my phone.

Shit it's going to be cold!]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turns out? I'm not an asshole]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/11/turns-out-i-m-not-an-asshole/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/11/turns-out-i-m-not-an-asshole/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Shit I’m old. I turned a grand age of 34 on Monday. But let’s not panic, I’m not frail and fatigued yet!

I was resigned just to have a night in, but I got invited out. A girl I dated many moons ago took me out to a really nice local place with her partner. It was an awesome night: Pizza, Beer and Banter. Turns out just hanging out with cool people is a fun thing to do!

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/drinks.jpg)](/media/images/blog/drinks.jpg)
_And I didn't used to like beer! Times they are changing._

And after that? I’m slowly realising I might not be the biggest asshole in the world. 

My ex thinks I wronged her in so many ways and never wants to have anything to do with me again. That got to me! I don’t like people hating me, it’s unsettling. With hindsight, it was one of the reasons I was finding it tough to get up and move on. If something is broken, I fix it! I don’t leave it shattered in a million pieces.

But knowing that the only other person I’ve dated seems to think I’m actually not the biggest asshole in the world has given me a boost. I mean, that relationship didn’t last very long, and was a long time ago. But still. 

I know with my ex I made some bad decisions, but honestly? Not that bad. I made amends for my mistakes as best as I could, and tried to be understanding. If that relationship was going to be successful in the long term these problems would have been things we would have worked through together.

Another thing I learned that night was that this cool couple were maybe looking to get… A Playstation. No! Cool people don’t do that! How can I sleep at night if I let such a stylish, outgoing and handsome household end up with a damn Sony Playstation. I mean, I want friends! But even I have my limits.

So I got them an Xbox. **[Series S!](https://www.xbox.com/en-NZ/consoles/xbox-series-s)**

[![handwriting.](/media/images/blog/xboxnote.jpg)](/media/images/blog/xboxnote.jpg)
_Don't diss my handwriting._

A bit of a nerdy tangent, but the Series S is an amazing console. It’s such a capable and sleek powerhouse. Last time I went up to Auckland for training I took mine with me in my suitcase - it’s small enough to fit in next to my undies. And this little black and white box doesn’t miss a beat! I’m playing through Jedi: Fallen Order, and with the next gen update it runs super smooth and looks amazing. Right now they’re $549 here in New Zealand - a little steep, but they’re still hard to find on shelves. When the demand eases up and this global semiconductor shortage is over there’ll likely be a price drop - and at $400 they'd be a must have.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/sonicscale.jpg)](/media/images/blog/sonicscale.jpg)
_Xbox Series S. Sonic the Hedgehog provided for scale._

I gifted the Xbox plus six months of Game Pass, and they’re set. I didn’t have to sweat bullets about what games to give them - they’ve got a huge library to choose from! They’re a very stylish couple, and that sleek little white console will look amazing on their mantle.

Yes, I’m a mega nerd. That’s my good deed for the week. I’ve improved their lives! I prevented them from making a bad decision that would have led them down a horrific path of sadness and despair.

Oh, she also took my phone and went on a particular dating app on my behalf. No, I’m not sharing details of how that went here. You’ll just have to guess.
git p]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lament]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/03/lament/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/03/lament/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Breaking news
A 2011 Mazda Demio is for sale. 

It's green! Yes, the original grasshopper is on the market. She served me well! I spent today removing all of my stuff, vacuuming it all out, reinstalling the back seats and giving it a wash. She’s done 150,000 kilometers, but has been serviced regularly. And after driving my White Tiger for a few weeks I realise how extremely fuel efficient the old grasshopper is.

[![Grass.](/media/images/blog/grass.jpg)](/media/images/blog/grass.jpg)
_This could be yours! All offers considered._

It’s been a solid week. There’s a huge amount of scheduled work going on, so juggling that alongside my usual day to day stuff is a challenge. I have to be in Ohakune at 8am next week, so I’m pushing my boss to let me stay over the night before. Driving those icy roads at the coldest part of the night doesn’t seem wise, even in my All-Wheel Drive machine.

Yikes, it's cold in the morning. Having my car tell me what the outside temperature isn’t very comforting. I burn money all night long keeping the heating on, and I think it’s the absolute best investment ever. Rolling out of bed would require more willpower than I currently have if my house was an ice wonderland. The cold always bothered me.

[![Cold.](/media/images/blog/cold.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cold.jpg)
_This counts as very cold._

Oh, my Instagram account got suspended! The reason? I was accused of being an imposter, pretending to be someone I’m not. Someone reported me for that! Have you seen what I post on Instagram? I mean, I do pretend to be a lively and fun person, but that’s hardly identity fraud. Maybe someone was just sharply jealous of the slice I reviewed.


[![Cold.](/media/images/blog/ban.jpg)](/media/images/blog/ban.jpg)
_And I'm not even a goot actor._

Oh, and of the lament I broadcast about my ex.

Yes, I know what you’ll say. Get over it! Or, as one friend put it, “Y u miss that skank anyway”. I’ll get there! However I’m not going to sit around and lie to myself. Hey, I’m an emotionally attached person! Moving on from the love of my life isn’t something to be rushed. You can’t hurry love, and you also can’t hurry falling out of love. But then again, my ex once did catch me Googling “Can you fall in love with someone in a week”. 

I have boatloads of regrets, but even if I had a time machine I wouldn’t be confident I could make better choices for it to work.

**[But I’d die to find out.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQt6jIKNwgU)**

We might be ultimately incompatible, but for some strange reason that doesn’t make moving on easier for me. 

Do I still have feelings for her, after all of this? That’s classified.

But hey, I am feeling way more confident these days. I’m happy with how stuff is going, really. Nothing special, but I’m not some sad heartbroken shrew anymore. I’m a confident, successful, smiling, hard working and… heartbroken badger! Yes, some things haven't changed. Badgers are better than shrews.

In the months since the messy breakup I have gotten out there on that dating scene a bit, but with no luck. Every date I’ve ever been on was through online dating, specifically Tinder. I’m very much wanting to try out the more old fashioned approach, but I wouldn’t know how to go about that. Party in the club? I’m taking applications for a wingman! Or wingwoman. The hourly rate is good, plus all drinks are provided.

But, like I wrote last week, not having a partner right now is ok with me. My boss must love it, because it’s letting me dive head first into work! After this is pushed live I’ll be finishing off a training guide on a new bit of hardware my company is deploying. Doing it isn’t part of my job, but oddly? I enjoy it.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's a game of give and take]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/26/it-s-a-game-of-give-and-take/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/26/it-s-a-game-of-give-and-take/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
My first day off in about three weeks? I slept a lot!

My plan was to clean out my old car and put the back seats back in it, but the weather didn’t play ball. Vacuuming in the rain isn’t a smart idea, and my garage is full of… stuff. Work stuff, rubbish stuff and my sister's stuff.

How are you, anyway? What's happening with everyone out there in the world? I've been on a rollercoaster with work, so I want to know what everyone else has been up to lately.

Continuing my journey of being a more secure person, I realize I need to put effort into being more assured and even happy on my own. I am on my own! I work and live by myself, and if I really think about it that's not a bad thing. I have so much agency over everything I do.

It is annoying sometimes, especially figuring out what to eat for dinner. Lately it's been a small bit of meat and a bag of salad, trying to stay away from carbs and high calorie options - I've got to trim down!

Back on topic, I cannot let myself feel empty or lacking because I'm single or not leading a lively social life. Those things can be really comforting and beneficial things, but I'm going to be bad at them if I feel like I have a desperate need for them just to be happy. 

My history proves that. My insecure nature made me demanding and needy, and this frustrated the people I cared about and pushed them away. I remember saying how I felt the stuff I did was unappreciated, but that's… dumb. Don't do nice stuff for cool people to get affection and appreciation, do it because it's a nice thing to do.

Just giving myself permission to be happy and self assured on my own has been a revelation. Since my relationship crashed and burned I was trying to find something to fill that gap in my life. But now? I don't need that. If that stuff comes my way, great! It could be something amazing. It's just not something I need, but I do know if it comes my way I'll be in a better headspace to make it work.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/C9IwBJYTwQ0`

You’re a smart man, Phil Collins. But I have to disagree with you on some points.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Never Know What It's Like]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/24/you-can-never-know-what-it-s-like/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/24/you-can-never-know-what-it-s-like/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It’s never two years.

I’ve missed it by a few days, but it’s been two years since my Dad died. Even though my life and my lifestyle have changed so much, it still doesn’t feel like two whole years. I'm definitely not the same person I was back then, I've learned and experienced a lot! But still.

[![gus.](/media/images/blog/gus.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gus.jpg)
_These two loved a midday snooze._

I miss Dad. He was just an awesome person, and someone that I'm still very proud of. 

And I know he'd like the company car they gave me. A big white Subaru Outback. It's actually making my days a lot less exhausting. I've got ample space to fit giant parts in so I'm not always juggling stuff around. Plus driving it is a lot less stressful. The fancy adaptive cruise control just means a lot less fidgeting about. If there's a car ahead of you, just lock it in and it'll keep pace with it. It makes my many, many hours of driving each day just seem a little bit less like work.

[![car.](/media/images/blog/car.jpg)](/media/images/blog/car.jpg)
_White Tiger Subaru Power!_

Oh, but I need to be careful. On the way back from Dannevirke earlier in the week I eagerly passed two semi trucks in a short passing lane. The Subaru did it well! I zoomed passed, smooth as butter! But, it's a company car, and if I speed my boss gets a notification. 

It was a bad judgement call on my end. Call it the excitement of a new toy! But now I take a much more relaxed approach to driving. I won't be having that need for speed again.

And, in another revelation, I'm incredibly insecure. Talking with a friend really got me to realize this. Here I am being and working alone, and I'm just not… confident and sure of myself. It's probably why my past (and only) two relationships didn't work out. I just was always demanding so much reassurance and compassion from the other person that it pushed them away. I become possessive and somewhat obsessive, and put so much pressure on the other person. 

I have to learn to be more assured in myself and my life in general. A needy and insecure me cannot be part of a happy and healthy relationship, no matter how cool, funny, smart, caring, good looking and interesting I am. 

I'm all of those things, by the way. Just in case you didn't already notice! 

And, you know what? Stuffs going pretty damn good for me. I've got a job I enjoy, I'm good at and that pays well. Many people live long lives never having that. I also have a house, a company car and extremely cool shoes.

[![car.](/media/images/blog/shoes.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shoes.jpg)
_I got style, I got class._

Work is very fulfilling, being the world's most bestest uncle is the most satisfying thing ever! And I love to be able to do nice things for cool people.

But to succeed? To get what I want? I need to work on finding gratification from within me, rather than external sources. And that actually sounds like something I can do. 
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anxiety]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/08/anxiety/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/08/anxiety/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Do you get anxious?

I'm realizing that I do, and it's frustrating because I'm not entirely sure why.

Last night and all this morning I found myself bubbling away with anxiety. I was a little bit scared and apprehensive about going to work. It wasn't crippling - I know many people can become completely disabled when overwhelmed with anxiety. This was just a not very nice feeling that I couldn't shake.

Looking back, I have had anxiety issues since I was a teenager. When I was coming to terms with my Asperger's I would get overwhelmed with social anxiety. It reached a point where I had to leave school just because I couldn't cope. For years after that I had to live the life of a hermit, lest I get consumed by fear and dread. I never socialized!

But, I worked through that. I learned, through a huge amount of conscious effort, to cope and even thrive in reasonable social situations. It's still exhausting! I might behave all zany and loud sometimes, but that's not because I'm a wild and free extravert - it's just my way of taking command of a situation. Taming the beast.

On something more recent, I think my anxiety boiling under the surface was a big contributing factor to the downfall of my relationship. We dove into buying a house together, and I just couldn't help but sweat bullets over all the little details. Buying a house and renovating it is stressful anyway, and me being like that made it worse. 

I made some bad decisions, not just bad for the relationship but also bad for me. When my hopes and dreams were starting to fall apart I really struggled. I couldn't sleep well and constantly felt like I was being crushed into little pieces. I still find myself getting consumed by a feeling of dread and fear that, because I failed so badly in that relationship, I can never be successful in any relationship. I miss what I had and stress that I'll never have anything like it again, and it's all my fault. 

And now it's my job. Last night I was just stressing about work. I had a dozen non-urgent tasks to get to, and got anxious trying to figure out what exactly I should do - and the seemingly dire consequences for making the wrong choice. My fear is that I'll dive in deep on a job, be half way through then suddenly get assigned an urgent job that will drag me away . It's silly! I know I have options of what I can do in that situation, but it just makes me dread that I'll make the wrong choice of what to do in the morning.

Going to bed tonight? It's not a problem. An urgent job has come up that I'll need to travel to first thing in the morning. It's such a relief! I'll jump out of bed knowing exactly what I need to do, and as it's a priority one job nothing can stand in my way!

Writing about it here? It makes it all seem so silly. I know I'm not going to get punished for making the wrong choice of what to do in the morning, and my bosses have been clear that I've been doing a good job with the work I do. 

But I think that's often true with anxiety - it's often irrational! I'll be fine, I just need to stay…

Grounded in reality.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Staging]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/25/staging/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/25/staging/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
What a fun start to the week.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/flying.jpg)](/media/images/blog/flying.jpg)
_Soaring, Flying, Breaking Free!_

Right now I'm flying back home after another visit to Auckland for training. I seem to be up here more and more frequently these days! It's really nice. I enjoy heading into the office and being able to see all the awesome people I normally only email or phone.

No drunken shenanigans this time; I didn't get locked out of the hotel room in my undies.

That caramel slice I made? I took it to the office and it all went! I was pleased at how well it survived transport in my carry-on bag. My boss, my boss’s boss, my boss’s boss’s boss and Karl all liked it! The secret is all in the caramel. Maybe my ego is just getting too big, but I'm very proud.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/slicegone.jpg)](/media/images/blog/slicegone.jpg)
_And those last four pieces were gone before I left._

Speaking of bosses, I realised just how much the management at my work really goes into bat for me. I work hard and scarcely get any feedback, but when I asked about how it was looking for me to get a full time salaried job, he showed me a PowerPoint presentation he was going to present to international senior management basically stating how they'd better hire me and a few other contractors before we jump ship!

Someone loves me, even if my ex doesn't.

I also spoke to another boss about my hours - he's asked me to come up with a working roster for after-hours work. He's really given me the freedom to choose what hours I want to do (within reason!). I absolutely want to keep doing the late shift - sometimes when I get home early, I get bored sitting there eagerly waiting for jobs to come in of an evening. I'm just not sure if I want to keep doing five days a week 8 till 11, or if I want to transition to alternating weeks on call. I'll have to think about it.

The CBD area around the office and the hotel I stay at has become so familiar to me. It's entrenched with memories - not of Auckland, but of what has been happening in my life when I've been here. 

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/streets.jpeg)](/media/images/blog/streets.jpeg)
_Written on these streets are the stories that I can't explain._

The first time I was up here? I was on top of the world! I felt amazing. I remember places where I bought Christmas presents, and where I was when I was on the phone to a certain someone. I remember feeling guilty that I was away yet having such a good time up here.

The second time I was here I was at an all time low, struggling to recover and having booze for the first time in 10,000 years. Yeah, I’m still embarrassed about what happened, especially when I found out that everyone in the office knows! Does it count as office gossip if everyone already knows what happened?

This time? I'm good. I mean, I'm not great! But I can't complain about how stuff is going right now. I still have a massive empty hole in me, but somehow I seem okay to not be in a rush to fill it. Everyone says it will happen, from my skepical best friend Mark to my kick ass colleague Jazz. Thank you! You empower me heaps.

Being around myself every day, I don't really have a view on how I've progressed, but having these semi-annual trips away acts as a kind of checkpoint. It gives me an opportunity to reflect on who I am, where I've come from and maybe even where I'm going.

I might be moving forward. I might be moving sideways. Heck, I might just be staying in one place dancing really awkwardly! But right now I can absolutely say I'm not moving backwards.

And that's an achievement worth unlocking.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The appalling state of Caramel in this country]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/23/the-appalling-state-of-caramel-in-this-country/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/23/the-appalling-state-of-caramel-in-this-country/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
As some of you may already know, I have a vendetta: The quality of caramel slices in this country is appalling.

As a “hobby”, to keep me sane during my long working days (which involve a lot of driving), I've been stopping off at bakeries and cafes around the area and sampling the caramel slice available. I got into caramel slice last year when I curated a range from all over the region to put together gift packages! It was very interesting just to see how diverse the offerings are. 

So far, Dannevirke has won. One bakery there had a gooey, oozy caramel in a crunchy and yum slice. But other places? Horrific. Wanganui, Palmerston North, Hunterville, Foxton, Eketahuna - all terrible, and definitely below par. Sometimes it’s crumbly and old, and at other times it just… tastes like porridge.

No more! It’s very clear that I need to show people how it’s done.

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL108VewJBdOA_OfLkchSuUgJumDqZTGPe" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>

Oh, I’m not an expert - I just like talking big. I’m going to ride that hype train! I’d rather boost myself up and let you, my readers, be disappointed. I will set your hopes way too high. But maybe, this one time, you should trust me.

First, put caster sugar and water into a giant pot. Yes, that’s right: White sugar and water. No butter, no brown sugar. Trust me here.

Let that bubble away on a medium heat for about 10 minutes, stirring all the time. It’ll develop a nice dark brown colour. Be careful: The colour will change very quickly! Pay attention, and don’t let it get away on you.

Now, pour in some cream. Not too much! Be careful, as the sugar solution will bubble up and put on quite a show. Remember to keep stirring. It’ll eventually settle down, and you’ll be left with a very concentrated brown caramel solution.

Next, add a can of condensed milk. Turn the heat down to low, and keep stirring. At this point you’re reducing the moisture and caramelising the sugars from the condensed milk. Here it’s all about the consistency you want - the longer you simmer it for, the thicker and harder the caramel will set. For slices you don’t want it to be very runny, but if you were making this as a sauce you’d simmer it for a shorter time.

[![Caramel.](/media/images/blog/caramel.jpg)](/media/images/blog/caramel.jpg)
_Ooooooooh._

And then it’s done! Wasn’t that easy? It’s a gooey caramel, full of flavour. You’ll love it, I promise.

With this batch, I put together a caramel slice. I sandwiched a thick layer of caramel between two vanilla cookie sheets, and then covered it with a thin layer of a dark chocolate and butter icing.

[![Caramel.](/media/images/blog/slice.jpg)](/media/images/blog/slice.jpg)
_It looks a bit... messy, but this would blow your mind!_

I swear I’m a humble person - sometimes - but this is just an order of magnitude better than most of the caramel based bakery treats I’ve had over the past year. The flavour is just amazing, and it’s got that ultimate smooth, gooey toffee texture. I may be hopeless at so many things, but this time? I’ve won!
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Mother, My Mother and Me]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/09/my-mother-my-mother-and-me/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/09/my-mother-my-mother-and-me/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, that was one hell of a week. My work days were long hours, but it was, frustratingly, a lot of waiting around. Oddly, I’d rather be working hard for 14 hours than trying to sort out scheduling and logistics.

I’m at peace with taking on long hours for now. My boss’s boss phoned me up when it reached him through the grapevine that I was doing crazy hours. I’m waiting to hear back, but I’m hoping I can come out of it with something like a week on week off schedule for on call after hours work.

And hey! It’s not like I have anything better to do with my time, so I might as well be out there raking in the cash. #SingleLife. Maybe that’ll change sometime, but God only knows when.

Here in New Zealand today is Mother’s day (Did you know in Norway it’s in February? Scandinavia is crazy!). All the well wishes and celebrations being shared about on social media have got me thinking about something I haven’t really brought up here before - my mother.

[![My mother.](/media/images/blog/mum1.jpg)](/media/images/blog/mum1.jpg)
_About 12 years ago. Wellington bays!_

Many years ago, she was an awesome mother. I was fortunate enough to have her around a lot, as she took up the role of a stay at home mum. It was great for me, she was always around and always supportive. She had a lot of health conditions that drained her of energy during most of my youth, but she still pushed hard to doing everything she could for me and my sister.

I went through a rough ordeal coming to terms with my… uniqueness in my late teenage years. I worked hard to push through my autism and social anxiety, and every single step of the way my mother was there. She provided me with the support and reassurance that I needed, coming to every appointment and being extremely patient with me. There’s a good chance that, without her support, I’d still be the wreck I was, rather than the semi-functional human being I am today.

About 15 years ago my mother started to deteriorate with Alzhimers disease. It was very gradual at first, often something my Dad and I would laugh at. She just did and said weird stuff! 

We kept on top of it, even when it started to get worse. I was studying at the time, so my Dad was at home with her, keeping an eye on things during the day. I remember she started to want to go to bed at about 6pm in the winter -  I don’t have an issue with people going to bed that early, but it’d mean she’d be up in the middle of the night, and one of us would need to be up with her.

My Dad and I worked so hard. Near the end it was constant and round the clock. I’d sit on the floor all night, sometimes getting an uncomfortable sleep but making sure I’d wake up if she got out of bed. It was exhausting for both of us, and with my Dad's health not being so great we just couldn’t go on. We had to place mum into specialised dementia care.

My mother hated us for doing that. She still had just enough marbles to know what was going on, and her emotions ranged from extremely sad to angry at the idea that we were making her leave her home. For about the first year, every time we visited her, she thought we were there to take her home to live. It was so hard, and I know my Dad struggled with that too.

For the first few years we visited every day, with only the rare exception. Sometimes we’d take her out in the car. On one of the last times we did that, she got extremely uneasy. She didn’t want to be in the car, and tried to open the door and reach over for the steering wheel. She was confused, and thought that something bad was happening. I had to restrain her in the back seat with quite a lot of force, while my Dad sped back to the rest home.

We didn’t dare take her out after that, it was just too much of a risk. We couldn’t handle her.

[![My mother.](/media/images/blog/mum2.jpg)](/media/images/blog/mum2.jpg)
_My mother today._

Her deterioration continued, and is still ongoing. Mentally she has completely gone now. She has no perception of what’s going on around her, and very little means to communicate with anyone. She spends her days in the dementia ward at her rest home just existing, and nothing more. She can barely walk without assistance, but is still often restless. The nurses and staff that look after her do a remarkable job, and I thank them greatly.

It’s tough. The strongest memories I have of my mother are from well into her path of deterioration. I remember the struggles my Dad and I had dealing with her, more than I remember the good times when I was younger. It was such a relief when she went into care that I wasn’t really aware that it was the end of my mother in the way that she used to be. I never got to mourn the loss.

I admire mothers. I love being around my nephew when he calls out to his mum. He loves his mum, and she does an excellent job being a mother. In my past relationship it was really nice to be around a family unit again, and I appreciate being made to feel so welcome.

The lesson here? Mums are awesome. Don’t take your mother for granted. Appreciate her while you still can.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trying out video: Life Update]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/02/trying-out-video-life-update/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/02/trying-out-video-life-update/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, rather than writing I opted for a video update this time. 4 minutes of it!

Big thanks to all the cool kids who've been helping me out over these past few weeks! Best friends, work colleagues and ex dating pals. You know who you are.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8f7ti-BLtU`]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rate My Tinder Profile]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/24/rate-my-tinder-profile/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/24/rate-my-tinder-profile/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I am still sick.

At least I’m no longer in a constant state of feeling horrible. Now it’s just a case of feeling sweaty and tired all the time. I’m half way through my antibiotics and it’s definitely working, but no one said it was going to be an easy ride. I have now managed to sleep a whole night without waking up in a pool of cold sweat, so there’s progress now where there once was none.

I miss work! Being sore and tired all day is flipping boring. I’m adamantly hoping that I can get back into it on Monday. I’m also hoping I can go out and visit friends tomorrow, that’d be very uplifting - but I don’t want to be a cesspit of sweat and disease.

In my newly found spare time I’ve been catching up with some shows. Oddly, the time just disappears when you’re sitting around being sick, so I haven’t been binging much, but here are a few things I’m tuning into:

* #### For All Mankind
Hard science fiction, maybe? It’s an alternate history TV series based on the idea that the Soviet Union made it to the moon first, and this let the space race escalate in crazy ways. It seems to be trying to be scientifically accurate, but it’s just a facade. The most frustrating thing is how it seems to paint all the astronauts as highly emotionally unstable people, turning it into a soap opera. The affairs and personal lives have become more of a focus than boldly going. Still, it’s nice to see long forgotten concepts like the Sea Dragon and nuclear propulsion realised.

* #### Taskmaster
This is the best show on TV right now. Get some mediocre comedians to do obscure and specific tasks against the clock! It seems like a low budget concept, but the amount of planning and time that goes into this show would be way more than you’d expect. The highlight of the most recent series has been moustached contestant Mike Wozniak. I’ve never heard of him before, but he’s the most strange and eccentric personality I’ve ever seen.

* #### The Falcon and the Winter Soldier
This is a buddy cop show, and it only works due to the actors in the lead roles. They’re awesome! They hate each other in the best way. It might be a full on, intense action show but the best part of it so far has been the two main super heroes renovating a fishing boat.

Plus there’s another thing I’ve been sweating bullets over in my spare time: an online dating profile. Tinder is still the hot stuff, right? I should wait til I’m feeling a bit… healthier, but I don’t want to wait around. I’ve so far had advice from two very unlikely people: my friend that’s been married for nearly 23 years, and my ex ex-girlfriend that I dated many moons ago. They've both been super nice, and I’ll take all the help I can get. Having that kind of support means a lot, especially when you’ve had your heart crushed and burned.

[![spoilers.](/media/images/blog/aboutaaron.jpg)](/media/images/blog/aboutaaron.jpg)
_Now what way would you swipe?_

Don’t worry, I still have some secrets. My personal life isn’t an open book! That’ll happen when I’m offered six figures for my memoirs.

Still, I bet all the coolest people around are reading this post and follow me on Facebook. Tell a friend? Wait, I don't think that's how matching on Tinder works.

Send all advice my way! I’ll take anything anyone is willing to offer.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I got Tonsillitis]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/21/i-got-tonsillitis/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/21/i-got-tonsillitis/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I came back from training in Auckland last week feeling awful - sweaty, sore, weak and disoriented. It had been slowly escalating during the week, but after my flight back it was destroying me.

I got home and then went to the after hours doctor, who very quickly diagnosed me with tonsillitis. He got me to use my phone to take a photo of the back of my throat and I could see an inflamed area of welting flesh weeping pus.

I’m on a double dose of antibiotics to kill whatever is doing this to me. They’re knocking me about! The doctor warned me they would. After 3 days I’m finally able to get a solid bit of sleep, so stuff is definitely improving.

It’s very inconvenient too! After my time training at the office I was feeling very eager to get back out in the field for work, but instead it’s been a week of being sweaty and exhausted (In a bad way!).

In other news, the house stuff is all done. My lawyer agreed to meet over Zoom to sign and finalize stuff - a big help, as there is no way I could do an in person meeting.

It feels good to finally have that all behind me. I’m excited! Optimistic! Looking forward to moving forward. When I’m feeling better, at least. Right now being optimistic is hoping I’ll sleep all night without waking up sore and sweaty.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uninteresting]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/15/uninteresting/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/15/uninteresting/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, training here is going well! It's intimidating to understand a big and complicated machine, but the boss man Karl ensures us it's not as bad as it looks. It's all sensors and belts and mechanicalness.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/belts.jpg)](/media/images/blog/belts.jpg)
_Does anyone really know what all that is?!._

I got frustrating news too. I had high hopes of getting a company vehicle provided to me, and I could take it back with me from Auckland while I'm up here. Currently I'm using an old Mazda 2 with the back seat taken out. It's…. Dying, and extremely frustrating to use for work. I just got the news that, despite my boss being optimistic, they can't provide me with a vehicle right now. I'm tempted to buy something myself! But then they'll probably force a company car on me a few months after I've shelled out for some kind of SUV. 

I had a night out on Tuesday. I think it might be the first one… ever? It was in the city and I was actually drinking rather than being the sober driver.

It was good to hang out with a colleague, that was really nice! But holy crap, I should get my phone taken off me when I'm a bit sloshed.

I ended up getting locked out of my hotel room, and I had people phoning me worrying about what I was doing when I wasn't answering my phone. I left messages with… someone that made them be very concerned about me.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/drink.jpg)](/media/images/blog/drink.jpg)
_All fun and games to start with._

I'm sorry! I didn't mean to cause distress. That's for caring about me. Also, thank your mum for caring about me too.

The whole day after I felt…. Sunburned. Is that odd? First hangover in 15 years, what an odd feeling.

If you've followed my ravings over the last few weeks you'll see things like affection, trust, love and loyalty being these huge building blocks of relationships. I can give all I've got in these areas, and I've discovered just how amazing of a feeling that is. Doing loving things for someone I love is better than I ever imagined.

But hell, I missed a big one. I'm so boring. Given the things I do for fun, I doubt anyone would tolerate me being the #1 person in their life for an extended period.  
 
I got told by someone that all this emotional distress I've been over recently had driven me to be a person I'm totally not.

Maybe that's a good thing. I need to be more fun and interesting, even if that pushes me way out of my comfort zone and makes me do things I just don't like to do. I mean, I don't want to just be… happy and content with who I am. That's not working! If I want to be around people I need to suck it up and do what they do - what all the kids say are fun! I just hope I don't become down and depressed, or arrogant and an asshole. But maybe that could even be better for me?

I'll leave my phone at home.

My head hurts. I miss my former girlfriend so much.

Everyone tells me I should move on. My friend Mark says he'd lock me in his basement if I ever got back with her! A colleague here I shared my story of heartbreak with said I can do better, but I think she was just being nice. Just this morning boss man Karl asked if I was married yet. Owch, that hurt. Last time I was up here in November I wouldn't shut up about my amazing girlfriend and our huge plans, now I only bring it up when drunk and stupid.

I love her, but I really shouldn’t - for her benefit and mine. Right now I'd saw my leg off to be back with her, but that'd be fruitless as it's more and more clear every day that she just isn't interested at all. And that kills me a tiny bit.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/nZXRV4MezEw`

But hey, anyone have great advice for moving on? Other than drink. That didn't work out so well for me.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cookies]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/11/cookies/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/11/cookies/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Eat your heart out, Toffee Pops.

As promised, I’m going to start sharing my baking experiences. This sure makes a nice change from emotional heartbreak and despair - I’m branching out!

I’m not sure I’m good enough to have a signature dish, but this would be the closest thing I have. It’s my take on Toffee Pops, but turned up to 11.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies1.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies1.jpg)
_In two styles._

You’ll need:

* Sweet Short Pastry
* Condensed Milk
* Butter
* Brown Sugar
* Compound chocolate of your choice
* Any toppings for extra flair

First, here is my best cheat ever. Rather than making a biscuit from scratch, I just use a cookie cutter on sheets of frozen sweet short pastry. It doesn’t come out anything like what you’d expect pastry to be; it’s a crumbly crunchy cookie base.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies2.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies2.jpg)
_This works. Don't question me!_

Take your sheet, cut it into small circles and place it on a lined baking tray. Bake it at 200 degrees celsius for 10 minutes. After 10 minutes they might still look underdone, but this is deceptive! They’ll firm up and set while they’re cooling. If you bake them for much longer, you’ll end up with a horrible burnt taste on them.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies3.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies3.jpg)
_Fully baked, even if they look pale._

Leave these to cool on the baking tray. If you try to move them while they are cooling, they might fall apart.

Now here is the tricky part - making caramel. It’s volatile stuff. Up there with enriched uranium and antimatter. Be attentive when doing this or it will burn!

Melt a little bit of butter and twice as much brown sugar in a big pot. Keep it on the heat til the butter and the sugar are all combined and bubbling a little. Now, add a full can of condensed milk and stir. Lower the heat to low, and keep gently stirring for about 15 minutes. It’s a long time! If you’re tempted to go do something else? Don’t. The sugar content in the caramel can burn super fast if you stop stirring. You’ll be able to tell when it’s done when the caramel is a nice dark colour and it’s started to thicken.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/YabLEQF73XI`

Leave it to cool a little bit, but not all the way to room temperature. You need it to still be a little bit runny for the next step.

Get a mug of hot water and dip a spoon in it. One cookie at a time, spoon a heap of caramel on top. It’s sticky, messy stuff! Between each cookie, dip the spoon back into the hot water to help the caramel slide off easier. You can use a butter knife to smooth out the caramel if you want, but it’s also nice to have that uneven homemade aesthetic.
Leave these to cool, and the caramel should become hard but still gooey.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies4.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies4.jpg)
_All Caramel but still topless._

Now for the chocolate topping. Don’t buy a block of standard chocolate from the confectionary aisle. You need to get compound chocolate, also called cooking chocolate. Normal chocolate has a tendency to split when heated, meaning the fats start to separate out. It’s super tricky to deal with and get a nice response. Compound chocolate has been emulsified with vegetable fats, and this makes it so much more resilient to being melted.

Melt your cooking chocolate over a very low heat in a pot. When it’s turned to liquid I use a teaspoon to drizzle it over each cookie. A long time ago I tried dipping each cookie into the chocolate, but things just fell apart and made a big mess.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies5.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies5.jpg)
_The right cooking chocolate doesn't split!_

Leave it to set and you’re good to go. I’d recommend not putting them in the fridge, or you can end up with cookies that taste like fridge.

You can do neat things too! With the batch I made today I did two varieties: standard Milk Chocolate topped, and my signature Cookies and Cream. For those I crushed up Oreos and sprinkled it over some white chocolate topped cookies while the chocolate was still semi melted.

And there we go! It’s super easy, even if it does get a bit messy.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/cookies6.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cookies6.jpg)
_Too many._

I made way too many of these on a Sunday afternoon, and have no one to share them with. I doubt these will survive in my carry-on luggage up to Auckland. Anyone want some cookies?
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can you feel life tangle you up inside]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/10/can-you-feel-life-tangle-you-up-inside/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/10/can-you-feel-life-tangle-you-up-inside/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I’m good!

I can’t really complain, as much as I want to.

Last time I was emotionally distraught was when my father passed, and just like last time I’m getting by with a little help from my friends. Gin and Ice Cream also help.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/gin.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gin.jpg)
_I regretted this combination._

I’m such a juvenile. I had such a sheltered upbringing, and for many years of my life I didn’t really get out much. When you’re a full time caregiver, living with your elderly dad? Social life takes a back seat. I didn’t complain, I’m hardly a social animal.

But now that leads to here. Kids these days have probably had their heart broken a handful of times before they start to drive! Here I am north of 30 dealing with this for the first time. I just need to grow up.

(I’m not old! Just getting that way.)

Yes, it’s hard! It’s painful, stressful, depressing, sad, full of regret, anxiety ridden and many other things.

And that’s OK. Life is about calculated risks, and this is the consequence of that. Fortune favours the bold! Things that you think happen for the worst are sometimes just making room for the best to happen (Thanks, Jackie!). When you’re in the deepest pit of despair it seems impossible that things will get better and you’ll feel good again, but that’s just illogical. My worst could always be worse, and my normal is better than many peoples. 

I think I’ll always miss what I had, just because it was so…. Perfect. For a while there it really was the dream. But maybe that can be fuel to motivate me to strive towards something even better. Is that even possible? I don’t know, but I’ll find out.

I hate it when a plan doesn't come together. I hate the responsibility of making decisions, but I get really uncomfortable when I’ve got no idea what is going on. I like to be aware of my surroundings. Renovating a house? It’s full of surprises! Nothing goes to plan, and to succeed you have to adapt. I wasn’t prepared for that. I find it tough with work too. Sometimes I have a good idea of how my day will go, but then I get swamped with a heap of remedial calls that changes everything I had planned.

Being more dynamic and adapting to changes rapidly is a skill I’m slowly getting better at.

I’m really getting out of shape. While I was a caregiver for my dad I put a huge amount of effort into exercise. I would run once a day and would watch what I eat. These days I’m working a lot, and often eat when I’m out and about. It’s not good! Lately I’ve just been skipping meals altogether. I just can’t summon the motivation to eat. It doesn’t help - when I do finally eat it’s normally something horrid. I’ll work on it.

Next week I’m off to Auckland for work. I’m looking forward to it. Day to day I never see any colleagues, it’s just me out there on my own getting stuff done. When I was up there last year I got to know a lot of the staff that work out of the head office. It’ll be good to catch up with them.

Onward and Upward. To the future.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tell me the song and I'll sing it]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/04/tell-me-the-song-and-i-ll-sing-it/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/04/tell-me-the-song-and-i-ll-sing-it/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Well, that was helpful.

Turns out this writing thing is really beneficial, I’m glad I can get back into it again.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/N2ICtCO8TCw`

I really appreciate all the friends and family that reached and out offered support. Over the past few months I have been making myself really isolated. I was fighting a battle on many fronts, and made decisions based on getting advice from a million different people rather than thinking for myself. Because I was wanting to avoid conflict I just kept to myself - but then I shattered that line of thinking and posted here for all the world to see!

I hate feeling stupid, but often I deserve to.

I know many will think of me as an idiot for a recent choice I’ve made, but I own my decision. I’m at peace, and I don’t think I would be if I had made a different choice. 

Yes, I’m being a little vague! I’m sure the smart people reading this will figure out what I’m referring to.

One thing I failed to mention before was the biggest source of joy in my life right now: being the #1 Uncle!

[![My Dad.](/media/images/blog/uncle.jpg)](/media/images/blog/uncle.jpg)
_Censored to protect the brave and bold._

My nephew is awesome. He’s such an energetic, clever and positive character. I say character just because he’s so dang interesting! He’s not some boring lame-o boy, but a super interesting, dynamic and sharp little man. He’s fun to be around, even if a bit exhausting. When I’m around him I try to give him all my attention, as opposed to most boring adults!

He’s like a better version of me! He’s into everything I was at his age - Dinosaurs, Batman, Pokemon, Video games - but he doesn’t have any of my aspergic shortcomings. He thinks I’m awesome, and it’s quite the boost to my ego! I often visit at the end of the day after I finish work close to his place, and everytime he wants me to have a sleepover. 

Emotional Support Animals are a thing, so maybe I’ve just got an Emotional Support Nephew. I highly recommend it.

I have a lot of idle time with work. I’m often waiting around to get access to a site or waiting for a machine to reboot. Now that this here blog site is back up and running I might use some of that time to write stuff. I promise it won’t all be about the failings of my personal life! I’m sure everyone is interested in my adventures in experimental baking.

[![My Dad.](/media/images/blog/chocy.jpg)](/media/images/blog/chocy.jpg)
_Caramel chocky goodness._
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[And I am feeling so small]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/03/and-i-am-feeling-so-small/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/04/03/and-i-am-feeling-so-small/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It's an odd dichotomy.

It feels like the status quo of me living on my own, working and maintaining this house has been this way forever, but at the same time it feels so recent that my Dad passed away. It's coming up on two years. Two years! I still find myself wanting to talk to him about everything. I see stuff at the supermarket and still, instinctively, ask myself if I should get it for him. 

[![](/media/images/blog/dadflit.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dadflit.jpg)
_It still feels like very recent history._

It still hurts when I dwell on it, but in a way I’m glad it does. It means I still remember everything about him so well, and I hope I always do. Sometimes people tell me how proud my dad would be of me, with my work and how I’ve pushed on with life. But the most important thing to me is hoping my Dad knew just how proud I was of him. 

And Work? My job sure is something! Some days it can be extremely long, leaving at 7am and getting home at 10pm. It's tough, but I don't mind hard work, especially when I don't have much else to do. 

I’m a Field Engineer! I drive around the wider area fixing things that are broken. It’s impossible to plan out a day. If something is broken? I have as little as four hours to get to the machine and fix it, no matter what the fault might be. Sometimes it feels like I'm being stretched in 10 different directions, really struggling to hit targets.

I drive all over the wider area, some days racking up more than 500 kilometers of driving. When you've got the field service management team barking at you to get to three different urgent jobs ASAP that are two hours of driving from each other, I do sometimes feel like I'm going to be torn apart! 

[![](/media/images/blog/badge.jpg)](/media/images/blog/badge.jpg)
_It's a real job! I have a name badge._

But it's a good job. I feel very fortunate that I was able to get it. I started the job by being thrown in the deep end, and through much stress and struggle I learned to swim. I’m proud of what I do, and always do the best work I can. I know I’ve still got a lot to learn, but I’m getting there. It's always a goal to get a job you enjoy and are good at, and I think this is the closest I'll ever get to that.

Right now, long and exhausting days at work are a helpful distraction from other, more heartbreaking things in life.

I met the love of my life. It hasn’t gone too well. We dove into buying a "renovators delight" house together way too early in our relationship, and the stress and tension that came from that was too much.

[![](/media/images/blog/houseimage3.jpg)](/media/images/blog/houseimage3.jpg)
_Memories are made of art._

Sad is an apt word to use, but it's also extremely… frustrating. I was in a loving, affectionate relationship with the only person I've ever met that I would want to spend the rest of my life with.  My list of regrets is huge. I would give anything to have a time machine to travel back to make better decisions and hope that it would lead to me being a better partner. In the stress of everything, I did and said things that hurt her. 

#### **[And I will stumble and fall. I’m still learning to love, just starting to crawl.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-2U0Ivkn2Ds)**


We split up over a month ago, and I sold her my half of the house at cost. I still care about her. If I could have any superpower, any magic spell or any wish, I would want for me to be exactly what she wants and needs. Right now I just need to have patience and give her space.

For now? I’m in a holding pattern. Being hopeful and taking one day at a time. Let’s see where this ongoing battle between hope and despair we all call “Life” takes me.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About me.]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/10/19/about-me/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/10/19/about-me/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
This is not your usual About Me page, but I’m sharing here five things about me that aren’t very common knowledge. These include things I’m not very comfortable publishing, but I’m hoping getting them out there will, in some strange way, take a small bit of the load off me.

### 1. I take medication for my mental health.

This is something I’m not eager to admit. Seeing [local TV personality Matt Chisholm talk about his struggles with mental health](https://twitter.com/MattChisTVNZ/status/1177127318977798145) makes it seem…  acceptable to be more open about this. 

I hate it. Despite the compassion and reassurance from media personalities and health professionals that it’s an okay thing to do, I still don’t like it. Even if it is irrational, I feel weak and defective because of it. I’ve never gotten into drugs or alcohol, as having substances alter my mental state is something I’m not a fan of.

But since I lost my Dad earlier this year I just haven’t been coping very well. Functioning day-to-day can be a huge challenge, and going against the advice of my doctor would only make it worse.


### 2. I hate printed stuff on clothing.

This is an odd one. None of my clothes feature writing or graphics printed on them, unless it’s something that was given to me. I don’t like being a walking sign, whether it’s for a clothing brand’s logo or some quirky slogan on a t-shirt. Also, the feeling of screen printing on fabric is uncomfortable.

### 3. I am very poorly traveled.

The total area that I’ve traveled over in the past 10 years:

[![travel.](/media/images/blog/travel.png)](/media/images/blog/travel.png)
_It's the bit in red. Look closer._	

Before that, the distance wasn’t much further than a few family holidays three hours drive away from the small town I live in. It’s not that I don’t want to travel, but between being very introverted in nature and looking after my father for many years, the opportunity never came up. Due to my work being on a very casual basis right now, I doubt I’ll have the means to go on epic long distance voyages any time soon. Besides, I wouldn’t want to travel for whimsical reasons. I’m not a tourist.

### 4. I’d rather walk than drive.

Driving is tedious. While I do it as required, if there is an option to walk I’d much rather do that. If I need something from the supermarket or have an errand to run, I’ll strap my boots on and march there under my own power. It saves money and saves the planet!

### 5. I have Asperger syndrome.

I hate admitting this, mainly because I’m not a fan of giving people labels. I was diagnosed in my late teens, soon after leaving school. I think my parents were relieved that there was an actual reason as to why I was so… weird. 

If you’re interested in what this is all about, [the Wikipedia article here is generally relatable to me.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asperger_syndrome) It’s not at all fun, but I like to think I’m used to it. Things people do without thinking, like most social interactions, are things I’ve had to focus on learning how to do properly. 

I’m still not good at it. It’s probably one of many reasons as to why I’ve been struggling to find employment. It’s a bit upsetting, but I understand.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Printer Troubleshooting]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/26/printer-troubleshooting/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/26/printer-troubleshooting/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I was recently contacted to help an elderly person in my small town get his printer working. The printer was consistently printing poorly, with text coming out very blurry and smudged.

My troubleshooting plan was to start simple, and work from there.

[![spoilers.](/media/images/blog/spoilers.jpg)](/media/images/blog/spoilers.jpg)
_Spoilers: My hands get dirty!_

First was a printer head clean, which was accessed using the touch screen menu on the printer. Running this diagnostic would also print a test pattern to help me see what the specific problem could be. It took a while, but the resulting pattern was rather fuzzy. The edges of fonts had blurry trails and lacked any sharp edges. This matched how the problem had been described to me!

I tried using the printer's auto alignment function next. This function does all kinds of magic to make sure the software is aware of exactly where the print heads are, and can compensate for their position to improve accuracy. This at least seemed to improve things slightly, but unfortunately didn't resolve the issue entirely.

Next up was a manual head align. This is a process where the printer outputs an A4 page full of different patterns, and you inspect each of them and apply the settings to the printer based on which patterns are the most well aligned. This process is done for each printing head: Black, Cyan, Magenta and Yellow.

The trouble is that none of the resulting patterns were good enough. Now it was time to get a little dirty...

I disassembled the printer to get access to the actual print heads, and removed them from the printer. The heads didn't seem too dirty, but could definitely be improved.

[![cart.](/media/images/blog/cart.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cart.jpg)
_The polished printer heads._

I used cotton swabs and isopropyl alcohol to clean up the heads. Surprisingly, a lot of built-up dried ink came off that wasn't obvious with a simple visual inspection. After cleaning the assembly, I left it out to dry for an hour. When I put it back in the printer I tried another head clean.

The result was an improvement, but still not ideal.

I went in much deeper and disassembled the printing head assembly. It was flooded with excessive ink. Googling for more information showed me that a plastic plate inside the head should be clean and white, but this one was soaked in ink. I cleaned it out as best as I could, but still couldn't get it shiny and white like most example photos online showed.

[![white.](/media/images/blog/shouldbewhite.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shouldbewhite.jpg)
_That should be completely white._

I put it all back together, and another test page showed very little improvement.

I was now reasonably sure that the fault was either with the ink cartridges or a defect in the printing head. No amount of cleaning was going to resolve this issue, and any further diagnosis would require extra parts to test if my ideas had any merit.

So, not a great result. Still, the printer was better than when I started! It's unfortunate that getting replacement parts for this printer could very well cost more than an entirely new printer, one that would likely be an updated model with better features.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chrome App Mode: webapps with elegance]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/23/chrome-app-mode-webapps-with-elegance/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2019/09/23/chrome-app-mode-webapps-with-elegance/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Browser-based apps have progressed a lot since the laggy and unresponsive experience that Google Docs was when it launched over a decade ago. Thanks to the power of HTML5, tasks from office suites to video editing now perform well enough that the browser can be a viable app platform for daily use.

However, having all this functionality tied to a tab in your Chrome or Opera browser can make it somewhat inelegant, especially if you're like me and many tabs open. Additionally, the address and navigation bars  just aren't needed for most web apps, and take up valuable screen space unnecessarily.

Thankfully, there is a feature in Chrome that can allow you to setup a web app to behave more like a traditional Windows program - app mode. This mode takes away the navigation, address and settings controls that most browsers have, and leaves you with a clean, dedicated window for your browser based apps.

Setting up is easy. Make a new shortcut to the Chrome browser, and add in the “--app” modifier along with the address of the web app you want to use.

Changing the shortcut target from:

```
C:\GoogleChromePortable64\GoogleChromePortable.exe
```

To

```
C:\GoogleChromePortable64\GoogleChromePortable.exe --app=https://docs.google.com
```

[![Shortcut.](/media/images/blog/portableshortcut.png)](/media/images/blog/portableshortcut.png)
_Shortcut menu, accessed by right clicking the shortcut and going into properties._

This trick also works with an offline website - just use the Windows file path of the home page in the Chrome shortcut, rather than a web address.

Running Chrome in app mode also changes the icon that displays in the taskbar. It no longer displays the Chrome compass, but instead uses the favicon.ico of the website. This goes a long way to hiding completely that the program is a browser-based app, making it seem more like a standard Windows program to the user.

If you're using a browser-based web app for anything mission critical or where security is a requirement, you can also have an independent instance of the Chrome browser specifically for running an app. This can be on the same machine as a standard Chrome installation without making any unwanted changes to your installed Chrome browser. To do this, just install **[the PortableApps version of the Chrome browser](https://portableapps.com/apps/internet/google_chrome_portable)** to a local directly on the machine. After it's installed just right click on the Chrome executable, click “Send To”, then click “Desktop (create shortcut)”. Now add the app parameter to your newly created desktop icon. Before doing this, you can run the portable version of Chrome normally and tweak any settings you want the webapp's browser environment to have - ideal if you want to completely lock it down for security, such as never remembering passwords, only accepting specific security certificates, or flushing all saved and cached data when exiting the app.

[![browser.](/media/images/blog/browser.png)](/media/images/blog/browser.png)
_A clean experience, you might not know it's a browser based app!_

You can install as many instances of the PortableApps version of Chrome as you need, and perform the same shortcut trick for each one. If you have several browser-based web apps in use, and want them all completely independent from other browsing activities, you can deploy the portable version of Chrome as many times as required.

Using this PortableApps method also allows you to use a different account for each installed copy. This can be very useful: you can have access to both a personal and a business Google Docs suite in two different windows without having to cycle between logins.

There are some other modifiers you can add to the shortcut to further tweak the way the webapp works. Adding --incognito will make the browser run in, as you'd expect, incognito mode. You can also enter chrome://flags into the address bar while the browser is running in normal mode to get access to an extensive range of additional settings.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>