<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>aarond.me</title>
        <link>https://aarond.me/</link>
        <description>The blog of Aaron Davies</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 04:51:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Gridsome Feed Plugin</generator>
        <atom:link href="https://aarond.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vans]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2022/09/25/vans/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2022/09/25/vans/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Ever had issues with your job? OI course you have! 

When I talk about my job I have a tendency to rave about the amount of driving I do. It’s epic! For work I cover an area from Ohakune to Otaki. A while ago now, I transitioned from being a contractor to a bona fide full time employee. As part of that, I switched from using my personal car to being provided with a company car.

I named her White Tiger! Please don’t laugh at the name, I thought it was cool.

[![levin.](/media/images/blog/whitetiger.jpg)](/media/images/blog/whitetiger.jpg)
_I've spent a lot of time in this car._

When signing all the forms for being a full time employee, I did attempt to negotiate for a better salary. I thought what I was being offered was rather… low ball. I wasn’t successful here, but as a consolation I was sold on the additional perks of the job. One of these was being able to use the provided company car for full personal use. This was great! I could get rid of my current car and all the expenses that go along with it. White Tiger here would be perfect for everything - supermarket runs, sober driving friends around and taking a certain awesome nephew out and about.

This specific perk was sold to me rather hard. After thinking about it, I thought it was a good deal. Cars are expensive things to run, so not having to do that would almost kind of equal a bit of a pay boost.

But now that’s all up for change.

My work is forcing through a switch from Wagon style vehicles to giant, ugly, two seater Diesel Vans.

[![levin.](/media/images/blog/freecandy.jpeg)](/media/images/blog/freecandy.jpeg)
_Not exactly accurate, but very close._

I don’t want this. All these benefits for personal use are gone. 

I also mega, super duper very much do not want to do the job I do now in a giant van. Every single working day I drive over some of the worst roads, and doing that in a front wheel drive Diesel tank would make my working life much less bearable.

I work flipping hard at my job! It’s extremely demanding with very long hours. My family tells me all the time that I work far too much. I think I push myself hard  due to a combination of enjoying the work and being a bit… loyal to my employer. This change in vehicles really feels like a slap in the face to that loyalty. There was no consultation or negotiation at all, it was just forced upon us. 

It’s especially sleazy given my employers constant lip service to being environmentally friendly. All EV’s by 2030! But we are switching from hybrids to these toxic trucks for now.

Anyone want to hire an experienced field engineer? I’m good at my job! Well, at least some people tell me that I am. All words of advice are welcome - anyone know a lawyer?
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's Tradition]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2022/04/17/it-s-tradition/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2022/04/17/it-s-tradition/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Many years ago, it must be at least 10 now, my dad and I had a tradition. On the top tier public holidays, like Christmas Day or Good Friday, we would go for a walk through town to see what was going on when everything was closed. It was interesting to see the scarce handful of shops that were open, and the rare car that went through.

He would have wanted to go for a walk every day during the height of lockdown.

On Good Friday this year I was loafing about on standby for work, and thought it'd be good to go for a jog. While not much retail was happening, the traffic going through this small town was more than any given Friday. All those years ago you could have pitched a tent on the main street! Oh, times are changing.

[![levin.](/media/images/blog/levin.jpg)](/media/images/blog/levin.jpg)
_Small town Levin isn't usually this scarce._

I've been on standby for work this long holiday weekend, waiting for my phone to make a beep to send me off on a job. It's been busy enough, but not overwhelming.

Is it… expected to feel valued at work? Or is that an old tradition for people with weak willpower? For a while now, my job has been feeling sour. The message and vibe is always "Work hard and long hours, or else. If you don't, we'll track you down." Some of the messages coming from management make it feel like a witch hunt is going on. Oh well! I push myself to have rampant enthusiasm with my job, but it’s been more and more challenging in recent times. Apparently big meetings are happening next month, deciding future plans!  I’d love to put my dress suit on and be involved somehow, but I’ll probably find out results months later. If I’m lucky.

Besides! Maybe, just maybe, something far more special, fulfilling and absolutely wonderful is going on.

Oh, some of you could be there wondering about house updates! No change. The lounge and dining room are all completely finished, and the kitchen is mostly done. I still need to get a splashback of some kind installed, and I need to put up the bit that goes around the fridge. It's so very nice to have a fully functional kitchen again, but I still end up using that dinky little air fryer for a number of meals. It feels like a waste to power up a full oven for one person.

[![fridge.](/media/images/blog/fridge.jpg)](/media/images/blog/fridge.jpg)
_Almost done. Almost._

The toilet is still flood damaged. I got the payout from insurance, but still have to find the drive to actually get it done.  Bathrooms are hard, and plumbers are difficult to come by! I really need to overhaul the bathroom/toilet/laundry, not just patch it up.

But no rush. I'll get to that when I can. For now I'll just focus on cushions. They count as interior decorating!
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[House and Body Renovations.]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2022/01/15/house-and-body-renovations/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2022/01/15/house-and-body-renovations/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
My work is ramping up for a Global Fitness Challenge later this month. To quote the email:

_“During this 10-week journey, employees will commit to improving their overall health and wellbeing and are encouraged to set and strive toward personal health and wellness goals. “._

Doesn’t it sound fun? It’s an opportunity at least. Since this time last year when my relationship stuff hit the fan, I have gone down a rather unhealthy path. I wasn’t feeling great, and just lacked the motivation to… not be a fat pieman. But now I’m wildly optimistic! I’ve registered and I’m ready to go! I have a constant notification on my work phone telling me that it’s counting my steps, every second of every day.

[![wall.](/media/images/blog/wall.jpg)](/media/images/blog/wall.jpg)
_A less messy photo is coming... later_

My lounge? It's done! More or less. It looks amazing. It’s all new on the inside, every bit of old furniture has gone, and now I have a sophisticated and beautiful living room to live my life in.

The wallpaper choice is so perfect. I showed a dear friend what the wallpaper was before it went up, and he suggested it was more appropriate for a bathroom! But even he has seen it since it’s been put up, and he agrees it works very well. My giant TV also works well at hiding the old hearth, where the gas heater was, and I think the bookcase below and behind it looks really good - even if it was a Kmart job. I went out on a limb and selected the couches on my own. Hey, my amazing designer was busy! It’s worked out well, the blue and grey balance each other out very well.

And a shoe rack is something that everyone should have. I mean, an actual place to store shoes that isn’t the floor? Genius!

[![shoerack.](/media/images/blog/shoerack.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shoerack.jpg)
_Rack and bench seat! So useful._

But the two biggest things that make a room? Carpet and Curtains. I was iffy about replacing the carpet, thinking the 10 year old job my parents put down many moons ago would clean up ok. I’m so glad I didn’t! Having nice, soft premium carpet makes the ‘experience’ of being in that room feel so much better. The blue-grey texture in the curtains is subtle, but brings the whole room together.

Finally, the kitchen. The other reason I took leave today was to wait here for my epic new kitchen to be delivered. It’s getting close to 2pm, but I’m assured it’ll arrive today. When it’s here I’ll be assessing how viable it is for me to fit it myself. The lovely people at Mitre 10 assure me, except for the electrical and plumbing, I can easily do it myself. Plus I have offers for help from friends and family for assistance. I’m sure, somehow, I’ll get there.


[![barekitchen.](/media/images/blog/kitchenbare.jpg)](/media/images/blog/kitchenbare.jpg)
_Running on empty._

So, something else happened. As most of you are aware, I came home the other week to find the inlet to my toilet’s cistern leaking galore and flooding the room. Fortunately, a good friend was able to get a plumber to attend at very short notice to get it fixed, but the damage had already been done. I had to take today off work, and now I’m waiting for the builder to show up to give a quote on how much the repairs will be. It’s good though, the insurance assessor has been and they’ll be covering the cost. Based on what she said, it’ll be new walls, new floorboards and new flooring. I had planned to do the exterior of my house next, but now it’ll be the bathroom. 

[![wateryfloor.](/media/images/blog/waterfloor.jpg)](/media/images/blog/waterfloor.jpg)
_Such a damaged, watery floor._

I’m going to take this opportunity to change things up. I plan to smash the wall separating the toilet and bathroom to make it one big space. Right now the bathroom is awkwardly small, especially when using the shower. There is also no wash basin in the toilet, so you’re forced to go into the bathroom anyway. I’m having pizza and beers with my expert designer tonight! I’m sure bathroom styles will be a vital topic of conversation.

And as a bonus breaking update? The kitchen arrived after I first penned this! Well, everything except the benchtop. It’s been a fun time putting it together! I’m getting there, but I’m sure I’ll hit a roadblock before too long.

[![barekitche.](/media/images/blog/gettingthere.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gettingthere.jpg)
_I have a kitchen now! Some assembly required._
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intense!]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/10/31/intense/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/10/31/intense/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Design skills? I have none. 

I'm trying to be less indecisive in life - trusting my gut and own judgement. I usually nag friends and others around me for advice on every little thing, but I'm now striving to be more independent.

But not for all the design choices going on here! That's one area I absolutely rely on an awesome friend.

Thanks so much, Jaymie! You have so much style, and without your help I know my house would be an ocean of clashing colours and impractical layouts.

Plans are getting locked in!

I've got an awesome wallpaperer locked in, I'm seeing a highly recommended flooring guy early next week, and hopefully maybe potentially I have a plumber. But I'm doing what I can on my own, and it's a lot of work!

Demolishing stuff brings a lot of joy. I've started smashing out the old junk in the kitchen to make way for the wallpaper. A whole set of hanging cupboards and the pantry are all gone, and the greasy wallpaper behind it has been scraped away. After I’ve put stuff back in order, the next step is more sanding and painting.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/bomb.jpg)](/media/images/blog/bomb.jpg)
_It's a bomb site._

If anyone wants to come and paint ceilings, skirting boards and throwing stuff in a skip this weekend, give me a buzz! Beer, food and appreciation will be provided. I'm taking this Friday off work just so I can #getshitdone. I'm sure it'll be a fun time, right here in Levin!

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/cheap.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cheap.jpg)
_Do NOT buy cheapo paint brushes. Holy crap, they cause so much pain._

It has been a rough time lately. For over a decade I’ve been on medication for anxiety and, well, my mood. But recently? I wasn't coping, stuff was just getting to me, I was oozing with anxiety and wild depression. I saw a local GP, and we opted to change up what I’m taking.

It didn't go well. I really hit an all time low in just how bad I was feeling. This hit me just as this renovation got intense, and other stuff in my life was coming back into view. It took a lot of willpower just to keep up with work! 

Oh, and my face was breaking out wildly. Gross, I know.

I started to look for other reasons why I’d be feeling like this. Did I actually hate my job? Did I need 12 hours of sleep every night? Was the dread of loneliness and mortality finally becoming apparent to me?!

Nah, just a change in medication. I’ve spoken with the nurse, and we changed stuff up a bit. Now I’m much more lively, spritely and happy. Back to normal? I don’t know what normal is anymore.

But maybe I don’t want to. With how stylish and amazing my house will look, I’ll be hitting a new and better normal!

I’m off tonight, going to Brew Union in Palmerston North. See, I made a bet with my epic designer and she won massively - I think she has a time machine or ability to predict the future somehow. Unfortunately, you humble readers will never know the details of that bet. It’s… of a personal nature. I’ll just say that! Speculate away.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Art]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/10/03/art/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/10/03/art/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Just a brief update today - talking about style!

I've been arting up my house. I'm really keen to paint and renovate this place extensively, but there just isn't anyone available to do it. I got told I had a one year lead time on getting a new kitchen renovated and installed. I very much want to paint and redecorate my entire house - it's the best investment I can make!

So, while I wait for tradespeople to be available, I'm getting into… art.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/nook.jpg)](/media/images/blog/nook.jpg)
_I'm glad I don't have to repay more debt to this guy!_

You've already seen my coloured giraffe, but now Tom Nook sits below him! It's a cool cushion, and as the summer months get here and the old gas heater is never used, he'll be a nice decoration for the unused appliance.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/beach.jpg)](/media/images/blog/beach.jpg)
_Surf's up._

The beach! It's a nice canvas print, and adds a bit of spice to the room.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/darkflowers.jpg)](/media/images/blog/darkflowers.jpg)
Dark Flowers._

In the dining room I've got a dark floral print. It's flowers without being flowery! I like the tone; it contrasts well with the afternoon sun that shines in.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/mars.jpg)](/media/images/blog/mars.jpg)
_Oppotunity._

Finally, it's Opportunity! The Mars Rover is in the hallway. It's a fabric print - I'm not too pleased with how it looks framed, so I'll try to find a better solution sometime.

The next thing I want to do is overhaul all my curtains. Here in the living room they're very… brown. Plastering and painting might be a year away, but I'm sure I can fit new curtains myself!

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/curtains.jpg)](/media/images/blog/curtains.jpg)
_Anything would be an improvement over this!_

Any tips? What's the best place to shop for curtains in the area? I want something notable. Striking, even! Much less brown, much more impact.

I sold my old car today. It's good to finally have it gone! It was never getting use now that I have the company car, and it's nice to be able to cancel the insurance. That green machine was the last car my dad bought and even drove, so it's a little bit of personal history that has gone. With work I spent a lot of time in that car, and even had some fun in it. Oh, the fun! But those details aren't things I can share here. Use your imagination.

So, give me your curtain suggestions! All suggestions related to design and colour are appreciated - I have no trust in my own skills in this area. I’ll be having a go at stripping and painting the house, starting with the living room, but if anyone knows someone that can remove and install a kitchen? Send them my way!
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Neurotypical Bed]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/09/26/a-neurotypical-bed/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/09/26/a-neurotypical-bed/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
After long shipping delays, it finally arrived.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/newbed.jpg)](/media/images/blog/newbed.jpg)
_Comfortable to the extreme._

Yes! Brand new bed, now with significantly less cat urine smell. It’s incredibly comfortable. I should have done this many moons ago.

I’ve been accused of being cheap, mega super cheap - and, while that has its benefits, it needs to have limits! I work hard enough and have a damn good job, so I need to be happy to throw funds at stuff to make my existence more… better. More comfortable!

I need to get around to paying someone to decorate and overhaul my house. I would trust the choices of someone with much better artistic flair than me. Based on my experience I just suck at choosing colours and styles.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/gir.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gir.jpg)
_But I make a start!_

And work? Work is good. Lately it’s been a lot of scheduled projects and new installs. It’s kind of nice to know exactly what I’m doing the next day when I go to bed at night, rather than being at the whim of whatever machine happens to break down on any given day.

Having a company car is the best. It’s expressly allowed to be for personal use, without limits! In the pitch to me coming over to a full time employee my boss even said that if I want to joy ride around the country on a holiday, all my fuel and vehicle expenses are covered. I’m due for four new tyres, and all I have to do is drop the car off at the tyre shop for an hour.

And having a nice and comfortable car is very useful, because I do a lot of driving. I’ve had this Subaru Outback White Tiger since June 20, and I’ve put close to 35,000 kilometers on the clock, putting me over 2,000 kilometers a week on average! My job is driving, with a little bit of engineering in the middle.

And on that, [I've finally listed the old Green Mazda. Buy it! It’s a good deal.](https://www.facebook.com/marketplace/item/807479799922396/) I don’t want to keep a personal car around, it’ll never get used and it’ll just deteriorate.

Finally, a good friend of mine has put a word into my head - neurotypical.

I’m not neurotypical, not at all! At my friend’s suggestion, I took a very in depth online quiz to try and evaluate better just where I sit on this spectrum. [Try it for yourself!](https://rdos.net/eng/Aspie-quiz.php)

I hate these labels.

[![New Bed.](/media/images/blog/neuro.png)](/media/images/blog/neuro.png)
_What a... horrible shape._

After taking this “Aspie Quiz”, It turns out I’m extremely Aspie and not very neurotypical - AKA normal. That little bump in the chart seems to indicate I swing most towards neurotypicality when it comes to relationships. That’s odd, I suck at relationships! But then again, I suspect it might just be optimistic and wishful thinking while I was taking the quiz. I’m not good at evaluating myself, no matter how hard I try to imagine how I come off from an observer's perspective.

Besides, all that damn relationship stuff is on the back burner. I just don’t have much of a desire for it, at least not right now. I’ve got friends, family and even work, and they all feel way more important to me.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How are you? Coping Okay?]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/09/05/how-are-you-coping-okay/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/09/05/how-are-you-coping-okay/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I bet lockdown has been tough! You're either isolated, or stuck around the same people in the same building for most of the day. What have you done to help push you along, to keep on trucking along?

Kids are a handful! A never ending source of joy and wonder, but also… so much energy. With my nephew, getting him outside running for a bit every day is a requirement. I totally understand that: being stuck inside with three grumpy and smelly adults for days on end is a drain, alright.

For those that usually work at an office, what's it like now working from home? Do you find it tough to adapt and get motivation to work with all the distractions and comforts of home around you, or is it something you prefer?

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/haircut.jpg)](/media/images/blog/haircut.jpg)
_Enjoying being out there working, but very much need better lockdown grooming!_

Shout out to all the essential workers out there! It sure is eerie to drive around those empty roads. It's a tad embarrassing to compare my work - fixing cash machines - to all the absolutely life and death critical workers. From doctors, nurses and firefighters to supermarket workers and couriers. Without them we all would get sick, get burnt, get extremely hungry and get nothing delivered. I know nurses have an extremely demanding and stressful job as it is, but this must bump it up a level!

For me? Work has picked up. I'm actually really enjoying having family stay with me now - it got a bit intense to be stuck at home with them for days on end. But now I enjoy knowing I'm coming home to my family. Maybe I'll miss them when they move out to their new house.

Except the dog poop everywhere. I won't miss that.

What would help you? What could I, or someone else, do to make your lockdown experience better? I'm here! Right now I'm in Foxton waiting for an escort to fix a machine - I'm out there, driving about, and am happy to assist anyone that needs it. I can also chat! My conversation skills aren't great, but if you need to vent to someone that isn't in the same house as you, I'm all ears.

But the highlight of my week? Well, at midnight Tuesday one of the local fish and chip shops opened as soon as the lockdown in my area was lowered one level…

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/midnightsnack.jpg)](/media/images/blog/midnightsnack.jpg)
_Socially distanced midnight snack. It was popular!_

Hey! Don't judge. I’ve been running a lot more during lockdown, so this is just catch up! I'll get back to trying to shed the excess flab right away. Besides, I felt heavy and horrible after that pile of fried food. It taught me a lesson.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't shit in my bed and tell me everything's ok.]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/29/don-t-shit-in-my-bed-and-tell-me-everything-s-ok/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/29/don-t-shit-in-my-bed-and-tell-me-everything-s-ok/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
#### "Are you doing ok?"

#### "No."

#### "Oh, okay."

That's probably what any realistic conversation with me will be like right now. 

Last level 4 lockdown I had at least 50 hours of work coming in each week, I had my first relationship trucking along still in the happy phase and I went for a run most days. Yeah, the lockdown was frustrating, but it seemed much more… novel. I rode those 4 weeks almost on an adrenaline high! It was neat to be out there in a strange world.

This lockdown sucks. I barely have any work coming in, I feel defeated not just in my most recent relationship but… all areas related to that, and I just can't summon the drive to do much. I should run more and eat much better, I have gotten a bit fat. It's difficult to care.
 
I'm realizing just how hard it is for me to integrate with other people. 

Having 3 additional humans and 3 pets in my house is almost as much of a trial as my relationship falling apart. I can't handle it as much as I thought I would. It's an inescapable tirade of sounds and movements. I know I wasn't the happiest version of me lately, but now I'm that on top of… not being able to think. I'm sure it'd be much, much more tolerable if they or even if I could go out and do… stuff, but it's not even an option now. 

It's not on them. My sister, her husband and my nephew are as good as anyone could expect for housemates, but I just can't shake the feeling of being an inconvenient guest in this place. I doubt I'll suddenly spring back and be a happy chap when this is over - I'm very aware that my own headspace is the biggest contributing factor to how I'm feeling right now, not the people around me.

I can't relax. I struggle to poop properly, and I can't even go to a public toilet for this. They're all closed!

I miss work. Right now I'd work long and exhausting 14 hour days for free. Getting out there and fixing stuff is an incredibly satisfying thing! My job is what I've immersed myself in when I needed to get buy. I got to  an extremely dark and scary place a few months ago, and I depended on my job to push me along. I have no doubt I'd be in a very, very different place if I didn't have the pride and drive in my work to keep me ticking along. Wish I had it now. 

I have 23 jobs in my queue right now that I would absolutely love to get out there and complete, but lockdown rules demand only priority one urgent jobs can be attended.

Can I live out of my car for a few days, is that… allowed? It'd certainly avoid what happened last night. I was heading to bed and was met with a surprise.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/dogpoo.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dogpoo.jpg)
_Censored. I talk shit here, I don't show photos of it._

Someone had left a present, right there where I was about to snooze. Still don't know if the gift was left by a cat, a dog or a person. I wouldn't put it past my sister to do this, she finds weird stuff funny. 

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/dogcake.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dogcake.jpg)
_I made a cake, too. Poo Dog gets none._

If anyone wants to know, here are the top 5 TV shows of lockdown:

* Below Deck Mediterranean - Don't know what this is really, a documentary set on a boat? It's addictive, apparently.

* Westside - A New Zealand original, set in the 80s? I'm not sure, but I approve of the hair styles.

* Stargate SG-1 - Finally, a show worth watching. A 15 foot high metal ring takes you to other planets!

* The Originals - French vampires? Yes, I'll go with that.

* Ghost Whisperer - Someone that can talk to the dead, but only very quietly? I think it's what Ghostbusters set in a strict library would be like. 

Oh, another thing. I am aware that writing and posting like this is an incredibly selfish thing to do. I’m putting me and my perspective on me out there, without any consideration of anyone else. I’m sorry. I feel I need this release now. To make up for it, please let me help you. Need anything? Want to also watch these hot lockdown shows too? Drop me a line and I’ll make magic happen.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One job a day. Oddly feeling tired.]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/21/one-job-a-day-oddly-feeling-tired/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/21/one-job-a-day-oddly-feeling-tired/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, since the start of lockdown I have averaged one job a day. During level 4 my work has called off all but priority one urgent jobs, meaning my epic 14 hour days just can’t be done right now. So it’s been closer to 2 hours a day.

I miss work.

My sister, her husband, my nephew, two dogs and a giant cat are living with me. They’re between houses, and this was meant to be a brief stopover. It’s… intense. My brother in law works from home, my sister works occasionally, and my nephew has school hours. But that was ok, I work a lot! I’m never home. Ha. Now everyone is at home.

[![Forza.](/media/images/blog/judge.jpg)](/media/images/blog/judge.jpg)
_Jackjack judges me and observes._

I’m really not cut out for this. They’re not being bad housemates, but I still feel like I’m living in a washing machine full of lead bricks. With my home and even work I’m just used to having agency over what I do! But oh well, I can hardly complain - I will just treat it as a learning experience. 

It’s absolutely making me a better person. If I can’t get through this, I’ll be a sad single bachelor forever. I’ll come out of this exhausted, but I know I’ll be better prepared for all the exciting life stuff coming for me in my post lockdown future.

I had big, epic plans to move in with my ex-girlfriend in the house we bought. We’d been in love for much less than a year, and now I know without doubt that if we’d stayed together long enough to actually move in it would have been worse. I wasn’t ready, or mature enough, to do that, but this experience with my family is helping me get there! I think I’d need to vibe and gel with someone for 3 to 4 times longer than. 6 months before spending every waking hour at home with them. 

[![Forza.](/media/images/blog/dog.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dog.jpg)
_Jojo somehow thinks this is the best spot in the house. He also smells._

Writing it down makes it seem extremely obvious that was an unwise thing to do. I think I should spend time writing down my big life decisions and then read them back to better evaluate if they’re wise or bonkers.

My gums hurt on the bottom left side of my jaw. I got aggressive with the flossing after eating some extremely tough meat. I practice exceptional dental hygiene  - I have to, it’s a family thing - so I’m sure it’ll feel better soon. Still, it’s another thing on the list.

Work might not be extensive, but I did get a break on day one of the lockdown - a job in Waiouru, about 3 hours’ drive from home. The roads are so eerie when they’re empty! It’s like a ghost movie. I took a 20 minute video of the near empty road for all of you lockdown chums to see what it’s like. 

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ekjukUeVoM0`

Oddly, there were a large number of campervans out there on the road. Emergency travel only! I’m sure they were just on rural State Highway 1 to go out for milk and toilet paper.

During the last lockdown I was given the only speeding ticket I’ve ever had in my life, out on those empty roads. This time I have to be more careful - I drive a super sexy Subaru Outback company car now, and if I speed for more than a few seconds my boss gets an alert. It’s okay, I can just put the cruise control on and sit back and enjoy the luxury ride.

I’m not normally on call for urgent work on weekends; those jobs get handed off to an external company that covers for me when my workload gets a bit much. I’m going to contact my boss to see if I can pick up that weekend work while this lockdown is in place. 

Everyone reading this - please reach out if you need help! I’m driving around in the area a lot, so I can do contactless drop off of things if you don’t want to venture out to the store.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blue Cheese! An all time high.]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/17/blue-cheese-an-all-time-high/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/17/blue-cheese-an-all-time-high/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, this was interesting.

I was messaged, via my phone number, by someone asking for someone called Frankie. It was a cute girl in the profile image, so my heart raced and I reached the obvious conclusion.

It was a scam.

But I wasn't busy at the time, so I went spelunking down the rabbit hole.

[![Forza.](/media/images/blog/smallcheese.jpg)](/media/images/blog/smallcheese.jpg)
_A flurry of hot minestrone. Frankie has a way with words._

I was Frankie! And I was glad she messaged me. The only issue I had right now was eating too much cheese. You know, that blue cheese artistically crafted to permeate the odour of foam sandals oozing with toe jam, then brewed in a concentrate of vinegar and broccoli?

Because Frankie is such an open and free guy, he didn't hold back from any detail. His fear of spending tomorrow welded to the toilet flushing out dairy and mould was a clear and present danger. 

She didn't seem dissuaded by the rancid volcano Frankie had brewing in his blue vein intestines. Eventually the scam came though - click this dodgy link to proceed! Frankie was too overwhelmed from all the cheese to muster the energy to do that, thankfully.

**[Read the entire exchange here.](https://aarond.me/media/images/blog/cheese.jpg)**

In other breaking news, I've got my sister and her family living with me for a few weeks. It's… intense. I've gone from one human being, me, living in a house, to three humans, two dogs and a cat. Things are working out though. The biggest issue I'm having is the lack of attention paid to cleaning up the dog poop. I don't want a festering fecal lawn. It's probably a good experience for me to feel like a guest in my own house. It'll teach me a life lesson. Plus it's nice to come home late from work to have the house all lit up and warm.

My nephew will never want to leave, though. He has this insane idea that I'm incredibly awesome and fun! He'll have that illusion broken as he gets older, but I'll keep that fantasy alive as long as I can.

My friend informed me the other day that I'm apparently very good with kids. It's surprising! Maybe it's my wild lack of maturity. I had plans and names for my own kids lined up not that long ago, but… circumstances changed. I'm not entirely against the idea now, but it'd very much depend on the situation. It doesn't just take two to tango - it also can take a village to raise a human being well. Right now I don't have either of those, but who knows what exciting prospects lay ahead. 

Kids are easy to get along with, they just require extensive energy. I think my nephew has a small nuclear reactor firing up inside of him, given the amount of energy he always seems to have.

Today is one of those days for me! Like riding an ocean, you get the highs and then the lows. It's at a low right now, but for no obvious reason. Stuff is good. Except for starting work at 6.30 this morning, I shouldn't have a reason to complain! 

But here I am.

[![Forza.](/media/images/blog/pahiatua.jpg)](/media/images/blog/pahiatua.jpg)
_In Pahiatua. The weather doesn't help._

I'll be fine, I'm getting better at understanding more about myself, and about the human condition in general. You can survive and prosper by riding the ups and downs like a surfer, rather than stubbornly fighting them. I wish I had reached that epiphany when I was at my all time low earlier this year. It might have helped. When things are bad, it's hard to maintain a perspective on reality that things won't always stay that way - especially when you reach that low after coming off of an...

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nn4TA-CBT4Y`

All Time High.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gaining Perspective]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/07/gaining-perspective/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/08/07/gaining-perspective/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Ideas on how to be a better person: imagine yourself in the third person.

Social situations are hard for me, and oddly I think they drive me more into myself, rather than allowing me to branch out, as happens for other people. In the anxiety of it all, I’ve always focused on me, my behaviour, and what reactions I'd get. Doing this made me miss the whole point of being social: others.

Video games.

Many hit video games allow you to change your viewing perspective. You can have the option of playing in the first person, like through the eyes of the character, or switching to playing in the third person, through the eyes of… an invisible person following you around.

[![Forza.](/media/images/blog/forza.jpg)](/media/images/blog/forza.jpg)
_Like seeing through the ideas of the driver, or following at some imaginary point behind the car._

While first person might be ideal for immersion, it hinders one very important thing: situational awareness. If you're looking through the eyes of your character, it's very difficult to gauge your surroundings and how you're interacting with the world around you.

So, recently I've adopted the attitude of trying to evaluate actions and reactions from this view. How would some imaginary person looking at me at any given time evaluate what I was doing? It's not the same as considering a particular person’s perspective, taking into account their individual personality - that's still in the too hard basket. I've gone down rabbit holes before, and reached wildly inaccurate conclusions. It'd also be a huge amount of computational effort in my little head to try and imagine being every single person I interacted with. People are hard! But my imaginary third-person person isn't.

So, now situational awareness abounds in me. That's the plan, at least. I'm sure it'll be helpful in certain scenarios, but if I start acting very strange, I hope the friends and colleagues around me are able to point it out.

Oh, I also won't start talking or writing in the third person. Aaron isn't that pretentious.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asperger's syndrome. AKA Ass Burgers]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/21/asperger-s-syndrome-aka-ass-burgers/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/21/asperger-s-syndrome-aka-ass-burgers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I put the word out last week asking for topics that you’d like to see me cover. I got a suggestion I didn't expect: Asperger's syndrome.

Or, as this person put it, Ass Burgers.

Asperger's is a type of autism. Basically, it means my brain is configured in a different way than most others. Not dramatically! I'm still human. You might think I'm odd, but when it comes down to it I just have different strengths and weaknesses than others. More on those specifics later! 

**[If you want a more objective view on this condition, this Healthline article is probably a better place to start.](https://www.healthline.com/health/aspergers-symptoms-in-adults)**

I was diagnosed and first heard of the term soon after dropping out of high school, but my… uniqueness came out far before that.

I remember when I was at primary school my parents asked in a parent teacher interview why I was so… unique. They’d raised me in the same way as my sister, but I somehow was turning out very different. During my youth I didn't associate much in big groups, and didn’t really do much else outside of school. I kept to myself, or just one or two close friends.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/young.jpg)](/media/images/blog/young.jpg)
_I can see how awkward I looked._

I didn’t like school. I found it so stressful and exhausting. I can see why everyone thought I was a massive doofus. When I tried to get in with my peers it never really worked. 

I left school prematurely, I think I snapped once teenage stuff started to really set in at high school. I went on to study at UCOL, a polytech learning kind of place. It was much smaller classrooms with older people that didn’t really want to mix socializing with their education.

And, by the time I got my degree I ended up being my Dad’s caregiver for many years. It was a very, very sheltered life. I didn’t do much at all for all of my 20’s, both because I wanted to be there for my Dad, but I was also anxious about getting out there in the world

The symptom of Asperger’s syndrome that most people know about is not being socially aware. It’s always been difficult for me to gauge people's emotions and social queues. 

I’ve had to spend time and effort just…. Learning. Figuring out people by awkwardly paying attention. I’m sure it made people uncomfortable, but now I try to do it more subtly. A common trait of people diagnosed with Asperger's syndrome is not often making eye contact, but I fought against that to force myself to pay attention to people. 

I can often hurt or upset someone and be completely oblivious to it. And, on the other side of that coin, I know I can feel underappreciated just because I can’t gauge what your reaction to the things that I do are.

You're amazing. You do all of this naturally! No effort required. You can pick up these millions of social queues to know someone is upset with you without them having to spell it out in bold font. Despite trying, I still find this tough. I annoy people by asking "are you ok?" too often.

These days I have to fight back against staring too much. It's a tough balancing act! I'm better than I was, but know for sure I will always be making progress for the rest of my life. I thought I had conquered this, but recent life experiences prove otherwise.

I spoke recently about how I’m very hot or cold on things, and can’t always grasp a middle ground. This applies to conversations. I find it hard to follow a conversation if it's a topic I can't… grasp. It makes me so uncomfortable when trying to chat about something with someone that I just can't grasp and keep in my head. What should I say? Should I ask a question? Try to contribute? Should I sympathise? Was that a joke? Are you enjoying it?

On the other hand, if it's a conversation I'm into: Woah! You can't shut me up. It's actually quite a rush when that conversational volley gets going, but I can get carried away. I'll dominate the conversation and just talk endlessly with wild enthusiasm. If I find something really exciting or interesting, I have a tendency to repeat myself.

It's brought to the forefront with dating. Often it's just an awkward, difficult mess where I feel hopeless and, no matter how I try, the batner doesn't go anywhere. But occasionally I just click with someone and it's the most amazing feeling! I just have to… restrain myself, lest I get carried away in excitement.

I still struggle. Last year I went out to the city for an all around fun time with friends in Wellington. The huge number of people, many of them I barely knew, overwhelmed me. I can often get by in these situations, but this time it got to me: not only was I feeling well out of my comfort zone, but I really felt like I was letting everyone down. I had a massive panic attack and broke down. I felt like jumping off a very high bridge.

The loudness didn't help. A common trait of people like me is sensitivity to loud and messy noises. Since a young age I've been very sensitive to loud environments. My sister would exploit this by… squealing when she wanted to get under my skin. I'm not physically claustrophobic, but when I'm in a loud, busy environment the sound of an ocean of people can make it seem like the world is crushing in around me.

Another symptom of Asperger's syndrome that I particularly identify with is empathy. I can't easily put myself in other people's shoes. It's tough for me to understand and sympathize with someone struggling if it's not something I've experienced and can relate to. If I find something easy and fun, yet it's difficult for you? Well… why? Why can’t you do it like me? I'm not fully an asshole at this kind of thing now! But given how subtle the social queues can be, I still get caught out by just not even considering ways that people around me may be struggling.

And I get frustrated and sad when I completely suck at something, and everyone else is good at it.

Not singing though, I love being bad at that.

It also means I completely suck in being proactive at helping people. I'll be so willing and eager to do things for other people. I love helping people! But if you want me to help you? I'll have no idea what to do without it being spelled out for me, and if I try on my own I'll just do something odd. Anyone that knows me is probably used to me asking multiple times over if there is anything I can do for help.

I can hurt people too by doing something they see as very hurtful or offensive when I can't comprehend it that way. I often try to express my grumpiness for something small, not not really a big deal, but I unwillingly let my words and actions get out of hand because I don’t spend enough time to stop and understand how the other person will understand what I say.

I’m also very easily excitable, and that doesn’t help here! 

My work is dynamic, with no fixed routine. I like routine! It's been a learning curve, especially with planning on my feet. Being my dad's caregiver was all about routine! All days were the same. It's been a learning curve, but now guess I've made a routine out of… not having a routine? I still appreciate going to bed at night knowing what my first job will be in the morning, rather than not knowing.

I am obsessive! If I’m hot on something I can put an extreme amount of effort into it. It can be nearly anything, if I love it? It’ll be an important part of me! Games, writing this blog, relationships, TV shows and even obscure stuff like… scientific concepts and technology theories. The nature of my obsession is part of why I can excel at such a demanding job. 

I am worried a bit about my job. It’s letting me be very socially isolated, and that’s probably not great for me. I have no colleagues to work with, and the only people I see during a workday are customers of my company that I have to smile and impress in a very uncomfortable and artificial way. Finding a social circle is an extremely intimidating idea, but I know I need to somehow.

Oh, and I'm also very clumsy. I have poor dexterity and bad handwriting. If this was a hand written blog I couldn’t even read it.

But hey! Above average IQ. Apparently. I think that only applies to ultra niche and nerdy stuff, though.

I used to not be eager about sharing this aspect of me. I used to hate the title. I felt it’d make me Mr Asperger’s, and didn’t want people to assume I’d be like how autistic people are portrayed on TV or movies. But hey, it’s part of who I am. I have to own it and learn from it. 

Please, more than ever, if you’ve got any questions get in touch! I’m very happy to talk about anything related to this at all. I’d love to do a follow up covering anything you’d want to know..
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This what I do on weekdays!]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/19/this-what-i-do-on-weekdays/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/19/this-what-i-do-on-weekdays/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Ever wondered what my work day is like? Well, unfortunately you’re about to find out!

My title is a Customer Engineer for a wide range of machines that process money: repairing, servicing and installing them in the lower North Island.  I get around! This is my exciting travel diary for Monday 19 July 2021.

The first thing I did while on the clock was finish off some documentation I was working on. It's a guide on how to clean and service some new hardware we’re rolling out. I enjoy writing, as you probably know, so I'm glad I can do some of that for work.

After sending that off, I jumped in my white Subaru and hit the road. I'm going to work!

You might think of a workplace as an office or workshop, but not for me. I have two places I can realistically claim to be my place of work: my car, and a storage unit.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/shed.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shed.jpg)
_Luxury workplace, no expense spared._

The storage unit is just a small garage sized lockup where I keep spare parts for work. Not overly glamorous, but fit for purpose. Today I had to ship a part that another engineer needed for a job somewhere else in the country. Oh, parts and logistics. What fun.

On my way driving to this shed I was assigned my first urgent job of the day.

In my line of work I have urgent jobs for things that are broken and need to be fixed ASAP, and also jobs that aren’t urgent, like servicing and cleaning of hardware.

The job that came in this morning was top tier urgent, and far away in Waiouru! After shipping out the spare part, I went on a road trip.

The most direct route I can take is a horrible windy wide road, but it has the nice benefit of this: Stormy Point Lookout. It's a huge viewpoint that lets you see the rolling rural land for miles and miles. I always try to pull over for 30 seconds to take a photo.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/stormy.jpg)](/media/images/blog/stormy.jpg)
_A view for miles and miles and miles._

After 2 hours of driving I hit Waiouru. It's very cold here! The job ended up being much more in depth than I expected, but I got it done.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/tank.jpg)](/media/images/blog/tank.jpg)
_Tanks for the fun, Waiouru._

Before I even started this job, I had another assigned to me: Dannevirke. Unfortunately, before I even could start driving to this job, another job with a higher priority came into my queue: Masterton.

That's a hell of a drive! But the idea of seeing the giant gumboot gave me the boost I needed.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/booty.jpg)](/media/images/blog/booty.jpg)
_I'm a big fan of a big booty._

Waiouru to Masterton is almost the longest drive I have for work. Before, when I was driving my old personal car, it was exhausting to go on such long voyages. But now I have this new machine with the power and features, it's so much more enjoyable.

Oh, in terms of time? I started work at my desk this morning at 8am, and now it's 6pm and I've still got two urgent jobs to finish.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/plane.jpg)](/media/images/blog/plane.jpg)
_I found this yellow aeroplane on my way to Masterton._

Masterton is a nice town! I've been here a lot lately, for both business and pleasure. The one thing I've learned is that everything shuts early, and it becomes a ghost town. To prove this point I took a selfie in the middle of the main street. I could have pitched a tent there.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/masterton.jpg)](/media/images/blog/masterton.jpg)
_No nightlife, not even early evening... life._

I often have delays in getting access to the machines I need to work on, and at Masterton I arrived 30 minutes before I could get access. I spent that time writing the majority of this blog post, and going for a brisk walk around downtown. It was extremely cold.

I was able to resolve the job at Masterton, but due to an ongoing issue with it I’ll be back - either tomorrow or the next day. And it’ll be a very complicated and long task.

I departed for Dannevirke, and by this point it was dark outside. Doing these long days is so much easier in the summer!

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/dannevirke.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dannevirke.jpg)
_Thor says hi._

The Dannevirke job was easy, just a matter of reseating a cable. After doing that it was getting close to 9pm, and I was hoping no new jobs came in - I wanted to go home!

I was tempted to get some unhealthy takeaways now, as I hadn’t eaten much all day. But no! I got home soon after 10pm and had Weet-Bix with some peanut butter for my dinner.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/dinner.jpg)](/media/images/blog/dinner.jpg)
_Meal of Champions._

I’m tired now. I’d better shower and get some sleep before I do it all over again tomorrow. Goodnight, kids!


]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dulling the sensors with shots and socks]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/18/dulling-the-sensors-with-shots-and-socks/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/18/dulling-the-sensors-with-shots-and-socks/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
What a fun time! Regular viewers will know that I had a mid-winter Christmas at my good friend Mark’s place last weekend. It was so fun! I opted to do something very unusual for me and partake of the alcoholic beverages. I stopped off at the booze shop on my way over, and ended up getting this.

[![shots.](/media/images/blog/shots.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shots.jpg)
_A bucket of shots._

As you already know, the most high class and professional drinks all come in buckets. Turns out they weren’t horribly offensive, and they all went! I had… some.

And it actually went down okay! Being a little bit tipsy is better when you’re not feeling down and mopey. I did frustrate everyone around me by always redirecting conversation to two topics: my personal life, and how big the present I bought for the dice roll gift-giving game is.

Sorry to everyone that put up with that! I’ll leave that rambling here, where reading is optional. In social situations I need to shut up more.

And now the big exciting reveal of what the giant present was.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W13T6MjhXo8`

A Bear in a Chair! I haggled the chair on Facebook marketplace from $25 to $10, and got the giant teddy bear for $4 at a local op shop. I’m sure the handsome man that ended up with this awesome gift is currently enjoying it. As for me? I got the most awesome thing I could imagine.

[![socks.](/media/images/blog/socks.jpg)](/media/images/blog/socks.jpg)
_Pokemon socks! Not pictured: Batman socks._

Even if I did rave on, the beautiful people around me were very kind and generous with listening. A few takeaways:

* I should shut up and move on.
* Most people have gone through what I’m going through, this isn’t special.
* Get out there and meet people.

Whomever is… lucky enough to be in a relationship, or even just be friends, with me in the future? I don't want to frustrate them with how incredibly dense and stupid I am. I'll beg them to yell at me and hammer how they're feeling into my stupid wee head.

(Metaphorically. I actually have a big head.)

And I'll listen! I will shut up and listen, and also not bounce between extremes. Everyone gets pissed off with me, difficult times will come! But I need to have the… mental discipline to not start feeling hated because a partner or even a friend expresses how upset they are. I won't jump to the conclusion that they hate me - it'll be a grey area, not hot or cold! Tepid, lukewarm. In other words, nice! And also sustainable.

I really like doing things for people.

I help and do everything I can to make people happy and, as you'd imagine, that is amplified a hundred times over when I have a committed partner. And now I know that, even with all the affection, flowers and effort I put in, I just missed the obvious stuff I should be doing as a partner. The “are you happy?” and “what can I do to support you?” stuff. 

With everything going on, I lost track of how the other half was coping with stress and life. 

With hindsight? It didn’t even cross my mind as something I should be aware of. Despite the effort and time I was putting into the relationship, my constant worrying and my behaviour made the stresses worse. I was extremely selfish and now I’m embarrassed about how bad of a boyfriend I was, even though I would have done anything to make her happy and to make us work.

It sucks that I couldn't be what I so desperately wanted to be.

Live and learn. Due to a number of factors, that old relationship was probably doomed before it began, and now I know that I’m in a much better place to make whatever comes next for me succeed. I’m still full of problems, but hopefully now that I’m more aware of what they are I’m better equipped to mitigate them.

One last thing: I’m really wanting to help friends and family more. If you’re reading this? You count as friends! Is there anything I can write here that you’d like? Not about me - doing that only helps one person. Do you want a guide on how to do something tech related? More baking ideas? Reviews of movies, shows, food or wigs?

I’m here and, like Frasier Crane, I’m listening. If anyone just wants someone to talk to about anything at all, please reach out.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is me learning]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/16/this-is-me-learning/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/16/this-is-me-learning/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
I know most people see this on Facebook and what not, but I like putting it here. It's more organized!

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5inAzzvq9tA`]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Check your emails]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/14/check-your-emails/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/14/check-your-emails/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Well, that was fun. I got up bright and early for a job in sunny (cold) Otaki. I was sitting in the car for 20 minutes, waiting for my security escort to show up before I went to my phone to figure out why it was so late.

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/otaki.jpg)](/media/images/blog/otaki.jpg)
_Not pictured: The cold and the wind._

The job had been delayed from 9am till midday. My work phone is appalling with notifications, and I didn't get the email that morning telling me about the delay.

Oh well, live and learn.

It's very cold. When I've been matching on Tinder somehow I always end up bringing up the weather. Yep, impressing girls with my slick and sexy weather banter! It's just… the weather is something I know we have in common. No one likes the cold! Well, maybe crazy ice queens. Do I want to date a crazy ice queen?!

Sure!

If anyone has advice on that whole conversation front, bring it! I’d be open to anything. Sometimes the conversation is just the best! It’s fun and it flows like butter on a hot grill. I don’t know, maybe when it’s difficult to get things rolling it’s a clear and present sign that stuff just won’t go anywhere.

I went back home to catch up on what I will call office work. Office work for me involves being frustrated with the worst part of my job - logistics. Getting parts, job details and stock status is a never ending fight. Sometimes I think this company is held together with string and staples given how some of this behind the scenes stuff is. 

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/officework.jpg)](/media/images/blog/officework.jpg)
_Home office._

I hate it when work is slow. I like working hard! The satisfaction of doing a good job is something I’m riding high on these days. Yep! Diving headfirst into work. First it was to distract from soul crushing regret and heartbreak, now it’s just… to distract from nothing? Hey! Focusing on nothing isn’t very fun.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logistics]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/13/logistics/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/13/logistics/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Today was Tuesday. I'm striving to just write about my days more often here, at least when work allows me to. I really don't think anyone will be that interested in it! It's more of a journal - but putting it out here for the world to see is a good way to keep me accountable.

I had a few minutes free today, waiting at home for a part to be delivered for work. Rather than sitting about, I organized my work bag. It's embarrassing to open up my bag in front of a customer when it's so cluttered! They gave me a car to look more professional, so having a toolbag that is orderly probably helps with that too.

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/shoe.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shoe.jpg)
_Hey! I've been busy._

This thing is falling to bits. I've had it for just over a year, and she's had a hard life.

Oh, I also magnetized my screwdrivers. 

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/gif.gif)](/media/images/blog/gif.gif)
_She asked me if I'd like to magnetize._

My head is very much not screwed on properly. Remember all those years ago when I wrote about how **[Dating is hard and I am very awkward?](https://aarond.me/blog/2017/04/11/dating-is-hard-and-i-am-very-awkward/)** Well, that hasn't changed.

I'm far more confident now. Wait, that might be wrong. I am far less nervous now? Yeah, more accurate. I'm  confident about who I am, but I'm not at all confident that a girl brave enough to get a drink with me will enjoy my company. I don't get anxious, I'm very blasé about it.

I do have anxiety attacks, but they're generally about work being overwhelming. For the longest time I was often crippled with anxiety about the failure of my relationship. I was still deeply in love, even when she pushed me away, and I really thought I'd ruined the only good thing that would ever happen to me. I was lucky to get such an amazing woman, and I royally screwed up.

But hey! I'm older and wiser now. It's not too bad, it's now just enough to make me take my job and my… life more seriously. 
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When I get that feeling]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/12/when-i-get-that-feeling/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/12/when-i-get-that-feeling/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It's been a little slow at work these past few weeks. I've had a few early starts, but other than that I've generally been home by about 7pm. It's unsettling! When work gets intense I can be out until close to midnight, but when there are no urgent calls coming in I just sit around at home… waiting. 

I find it difficult to do stuff when I'm on call like this. Can I bake? Watch a movie? Learn a new dance? Not really, if a priority one call comes in I've normally got to be out the door in 10 minutes just to meet resolution targets.

I dance far worse than I sing, so it's a very scary thought.

To be honest? While I'm single and alone I'd rather be working long hours than just loafing about at home. I just feel way less productive and accomplished when I'm sitting around home "relaxing" when I could be out there earning cash and fixing stuff!

And I love complaining about how much I work. I inherited my love of complaining from my Dad, so at this point it's a tradition.

My Instagram is still banned. I got suspended as someone reported me as an imposter. I think they were just jealous of my… wild and exciting life? Nope, maybe not that. It sucks, I liked posting my bad singing and torturing all the people following me! I've done the appeal process to try and get it back, but given how these companies work I'm not holding out hope.

But hey, to make up for it I put this on my dating profile.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkabUfWmzWk`

How the hell am I still single?!

It kind of worked? Some match with me and ask "What's up with that video?!" Others find it funny. Either way? It's something unique!

Right! Out the door at 6am tomorrow. I have to get to site for a scheduled job, but want to participate in the weekly meeting for work. Only way to make it fit is to leave very early, then sit in the car tuning into the exciting meeting from my phone.

Shit it's going to be cold!]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turns out? I'm not an asshole]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/11/turns-out-i-m-not-an-asshole/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/11/turns-out-i-m-not-an-asshole/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
Shit I’m old. I turned a grand age of 34 on Monday. But let’s not panic, I’m not frail and fatigued yet!

I was resigned just to have a night in, but I got invited out. A girl I dated many moons ago took me out to a really nice local place with her partner. It was an awesome night: Pizza, Beer and Banter. Turns out just hanging out with cool people is a fun thing to do!

[![drinks.](/media/images/blog/drinks.jpg)](/media/images/blog/drinks.jpg)
_And I didn't used to like beer! Times they are changing._

And after that? I’m slowly realising I might not be the biggest asshole in the world. 

My ex thinks I wronged her in so many ways and never wants to have anything to do with me again. That got to me! I don’t like people hating me, it’s unsettling. With hindsight, it was one of the reasons I was finding it tough to get up and move on. If something is broken, I fix it! I don’t leave it shattered in a million pieces.

But knowing that the only other person I’ve dated seems to think I’m actually not the biggest asshole in the world has given me a boost. I mean, that relationship didn’t last very long, and was a long time ago. But still. 

I know with my ex I made some bad decisions, but honestly? Not that bad. I made amends for my mistakes as best as I could, and tried to be understanding. If that relationship was going to be successful in the long term these problems would have been things we would have worked through together.

Another thing I learned that night was that this cool couple were maybe looking to get… A Playstation. No! Cool people don’t do that! How can I sleep at night if I let such a stylish, outgoing and handsome household end up with a damn Sony Playstation. I mean, I want friends! But even I have my limits.

So I got them an Xbox. **[Series S!](https://www.xbox.com/en-NZ/consoles/xbox-series-s)**

[![handwriting.](/media/images/blog/xboxnote.jpg)](/media/images/blog/xboxnote.jpg)
_Don't diss my handwriting._

A bit of a nerdy tangent, but the Series S is an amazing console. It’s such a capable and sleek powerhouse. Last time I went up to Auckland for training I took mine with me in my suitcase - it’s small enough to fit in next to my undies. And this little black and white box doesn’t miss a beat! I’m playing through Jedi: Fallen Order, and with the next gen update it runs super smooth and looks amazing. Right now they’re $549 here in New Zealand - a little steep, but they’re still hard to find on shelves. When the demand eases up and this global semiconductor shortage is over there’ll likely be a price drop - and at $400 they'd be a must have.

[![Gin.](/media/images/blog/sonicscale.jpg)](/media/images/blog/sonicscale.jpg)
_Xbox Series S. Sonic the Hedgehog provided for scale._

I gifted the Xbox plus six months of Game Pass, and they’re set. I didn’t have to sweat bullets about what games to give them - they’ve got a huge library to choose from! They’re a very stylish couple, and that sleek little white console will look amazing on their mantle.

Yes, I’m a mega nerd. That’s my good deed for the week. I’ve improved their lives! I prevented them from making a bad decision that would have led them down a horrific path of sadness and despair.

Oh, she also took my phone and went on a particular dating app on my behalf. No, I’m not sharing details of how that went here. You’ll just have to guess.
git p]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lament]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/03/lament/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/07/03/lament/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Breaking news
A 2011 Mazda Demio is for sale. 

It's green! Yes, the original grasshopper is on the market. She served me well! I spent today removing all of my stuff, vacuuming it all out, reinstalling the back seats and giving it a wash. She’s done 150,000 kilometers, but has been serviced regularly. And after driving my White Tiger for a few weeks I realise how extremely fuel efficient the old grasshopper is.

[![Grass.](/media/images/blog/grass.jpg)](/media/images/blog/grass.jpg)
_This could be yours! All offers considered._

It’s been a solid week. There’s a huge amount of scheduled work going on, so juggling that alongside my usual day to day stuff is a challenge. I have to be in Ohakune at 8am next week, so I’m pushing my boss to let me stay over the night before. Driving those icy roads at the coldest part of the night doesn’t seem wise, even in my All-Wheel Drive machine.

Yikes, it's cold in the morning. Having my car tell me what the outside temperature isn’t very comforting. I burn money all night long keeping the heating on, and I think it’s the absolute best investment ever. Rolling out of bed would require more willpower than I currently have if my house was an ice wonderland. The cold always bothered me.

[![Cold.](/media/images/blog/cold.jpg)](/media/images/blog/cold.jpg)
_This counts as very cold._

Oh, my Instagram account got suspended! The reason? I was accused of being an imposter, pretending to be someone I’m not. Someone reported me for that! Have you seen what I post on Instagram? I mean, I do pretend to be a lively and fun person, but that’s hardly identity fraud. Maybe someone was just sharply jealous of the slice I reviewed.


[![Cold.](/media/images/blog/ban.jpg)](/media/images/blog/ban.jpg)
_And I'm not even a goot actor._

Oh, and of the lament I broadcast about my ex.

Yes, I know what you’ll say. Get over it! Or, as one friend put it, “Y u miss that skank anyway”. I’ll get there! However I’m not going to sit around and lie to myself. Hey, I’m an emotionally attached person! Moving on from the love of my life isn’t something to be rushed. You can’t hurry love, and you also can’t hurry falling out of love. But then again, my ex once did catch me Googling “Can you fall in love with someone in a week”. 

I have boatloads of regrets, but even if I had a time machine I wouldn’t be confident I could make better choices for it to work.

**[But I’d die to find out.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQt6jIKNwgU)**

We might be ultimately incompatible, but for some strange reason that doesn’t make moving on easier for me. 

Do I still have feelings for her, after all of this? That’s classified.

But hey, I am feeling way more confident these days. I’m happy with how stuff is going, really. Nothing special, but I’m not some sad heartbroken shrew anymore. I’m a confident, successful, smiling, hard working and… heartbroken badger! Yes, some things haven't changed. Badgers are better than shrews.

In the months since the messy breakup I have gotten out there on that dating scene a bit, but with no luck. Every date I’ve ever been on was through online dating, specifically Tinder. I’m very much wanting to try out the more old fashioned approach, but I wouldn’t know how to go about that. Party in the club? I’m taking applications for a wingman! Or wingwoman. The hourly rate is good, plus all drinks are provided.

But, like I wrote last week, not having a partner right now is ok with me. My boss must love it, because it’s letting me dive head first into work! After this is pushed live I’ll be finishing off a training guide on a new bit of hardware my company is deploying. Doing it isn’t part of my job, but oddly? I enjoy it.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's a game of give and take]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/26/it-s-a-game-of-give-and-take/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/26/it-s-a-game-of-give-and-take/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
My first day off in about three weeks? I slept a lot!

My plan was to clean out my old car and put the back seats back in it, but the weather didn’t play ball. Vacuuming in the rain isn’t a smart idea, and my garage is full of… stuff. Work stuff, rubbish stuff and my sister's stuff.

How are you, anyway? What's happening with everyone out there in the world? I've been on a rollercoaster with work, so I want to know what everyone else has been up to lately.

Continuing my journey of being a more secure person, I realize I need to put effort into being more assured and even happy on my own. I am on my own! I work and live by myself, and if I really think about it that's not a bad thing. I have so much agency over everything I do.

It is annoying sometimes, especially figuring out what to eat for dinner. Lately it's been a small bit of meat and a bag of salad, trying to stay away from carbs and high calorie options - I've got to trim down!

Back on topic, I cannot let myself feel empty or lacking because I'm single or not leading a lively social life. Those things can be really comforting and beneficial things, but I'm going to be bad at them if I feel like I have a desperate need for them just to be happy. 

My history proves that. My insecure nature made me demanding and needy, and this frustrated the people I cared about and pushed them away. I remember saying how I felt the stuff I did was unappreciated, but that's… dumb. Don't do nice stuff for cool people to get affection and appreciation, do it because it's a nice thing to do.

Just giving myself permission to be happy and self assured on my own has been a revelation. Since my relationship crashed and burned I was trying to find something to fill that gap in my life. But now? I don't need that. If that stuff comes my way, great! It could be something amazing. It's just not something I need, but I do know if it comes my way I'll be in a better headspace to make it work.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/embed/C9IwBJYTwQ0`

You’re a smart man, Phil Collins. But I have to disagree with you on some points.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Never Know What It's Like]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/24/you-can-never-know-what-it-s-like/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/24/you-can-never-know-what-it-s-like/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
It’s never two years.

I’ve missed it by a few days, but it’s been two years since my Dad died. Even though my life and my lifestyle have changed so much, it still doesn’t feel like two whole years. I'm definitely not the same person I was back then, I've learned and experienced a lot! But still.

[![gus.](/media/images/blog/gus.jpg)](/media/images/blog/gus.jpg)
_These two loved a midday snooze._

I miss Dad. He was just an awesome person, and someone that I'm still very proud of. 

And I know he'd like the company car they gave me. A big white Subaru Outback. It's actually making my days a lot less exhausting. I've got ample space to fit giant parts in so I'm not always juggling stuff around. Plus driving it is a lot less stressful. The fancy adaptive cruise control just means a lot less fidgeting about. If there's a car ahead of you, just lock it in and it'll keep pace with it. It makes my many, many hours of driving each day just seem a little bit less like work.

[![car.](/media/images/blog/car.jpg)](/media/images/blog/car.jpg)
_White Tiger Subaru Power!_

Oh, but I need to be careful. On the way back from Dannevirke earlier in the week I eagerly passed two semi trucks in a short passing lane. The Subaru did it well! I zoomed passed, smooth as butter! But, it's a company car, and if I speed my boss gets a notification. 

It was a bad judgement call on my end. Call it the excitement of a new toy! But now I take a much more relaxed approach to driving. I won't be having that need for speed again.

And, in another revelation, I'm incredibly insecure. Talking with a friend really got me to realize this. Here I am being and working alone, and I'm just not… confident and sure of myself. It's probably why my past (and only) two relationships didn't work out. I just was always demanding so much reassurance and compassion from the other person that it pushed them away. I become possessive and somewhat obsessive, and put so much pressure on the other person. 

I have to learn to be more assured in myself and my life in general. A needy and insecure me cannot be part of a happy and healthy relationship, no matter how cool, funny, smart, caring, good looking and interesting I am. 

I'm all of those things, by the way. Just in case you didn't already notice! 

And, you know what? Stuffs going pretty damn good for me. I've got a job I enjoy, I'm good at and that pays well. Many people live long lives never having that. I also have a house, a company car and extremely cool shoes.

[![car.](/media/images/blog/shoes.jpg)](/media/images/blog/shoes.jpg)
_I got style, I got class._

Work is very fulfilling, being the world's most bestest uncle is the most satisfying thing ever! And I love to be able to do nice things for cool people.

But to succeed? To get what I want? I need to work on finding gratification from within me, rather than external sources. And that actually sounds like something I can do. 
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anxiety]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/08/anxiety/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/06/08/anxiety/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
### Do you get anxious?

I'm realizing that I do, and it's frustrating because I'm not entirely sure why.

Last night and all this morning I found myself bubbling away with anxiety. I was a little bit scared and apprehensive about going to work. It wasn't crippling - I know many people can become completely disabled when overwhelmed with anxiety. This was just a not very nice feeling that I couldn't shake.

Looking back, I have had anxiety issues since I was a teenager. When I was coming to terms with my Asperger's I would get overwhelmed with social anxiety. It reached a point where I had to leave school just because I couldn't cope. For years after that I had to live the life of a hermit, lest I get consumed by fear and dread. I never socialized!

But, I worked through that. I learned, through a huge amount of conscious effort, to cope and even thrive in reasonable social situations. It's still exhausting! I might behave all zany and loud sometimes, but that's not because I'm a wild and free extravert - it's just my way of taking command of a situation. Taming the beast.

On something more recent, I think my anxiety boiling under the surface was a big contributing factor to the downfall of my relationship. We dove into buying a house together, and I just couldn't help but sweat bullets over all the little details. Buying a house and renovating it is stressful anyway, and me being like that made it worse. 

I made some bad decisions, not just bad for the relationship but also bad for me. When my hopes and dreams were starting to fall apart I really struggled. I couldn't sleep well and constantly felt like I was being crushed into little pieces. I still find myself getting consumed by a feeling of dread and fear that, because I failed so badly in that relationship, I can never be successful in any relationship. I miss what I had and stress that I'll never have anything like it again, and it's all my fault. 

And now it's my job. Last night I was just stressing about work. I had a dozen non-urgent tasks to get to, and got anxious trying to figure out what exactly I should do - and the seemingly dire consequences for making the wrong choice. My fear is that I'll dive in deep on a job, be half way through then suddenly get assigned an urgent job that will drag me away . It's silly! I know I have options of what I can do in that situation, but it just makes me dread that I'll make the wrong choice of what to do in the morning.

Going to bed tonight? It's not a problem. An urgent job has come up that I'll need to travel to first thing in the morning. It's such a relief! I'll jump out of bed knowing exactly what I need to do, and as it's a priority one job nothing can stand in my way!

Writing about it here? It makes it all seem so silly. I know I'm not going to get punished for making the wrong choice of what to do in the morning, and my bosses have been clear that I've been doing a good job with the work I do. 

But I think that's often true with anxiety - it's often irrational! I'll be fine, I just need to stay…

Grounded in reality.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Staging]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/25/staging/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/25/staging/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
What a fun start to the week.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/flying.jpg)](/media/images/blog/flying.jpg)
_Soaring, Flying, Breaking Free!_

Right now I'm flying back home after another visit to Auckland for training. I seem to be up here more and more frequently these days! It's really nice. I enjoy heading into the office and being able to see all the awesome people I normally only email or phone.

No drunken shenanigans this time; I didn't get locked out of the hotel room in my undies.

That caramel slice I made? I took it to the office and it all went! I was pleased at how well it survived transport in my carry-on bag. My boss, my boss’s boss, my boss’s boss’s boss and Karl all liked it! The secret is all in the caramel. Maybe my ego is just getting too big, but I'm very proud.

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/slicegone.jpg)](/media/images/blog/slicegone.jpg)
_And those last four pieces were gone before I left._

Speaking of bosses, I realised just how much the management at my work really goes into bat for me. I work hard and scarcely get any feedback, but when I asked about how it was looking for me to get a full time salaried job, he showed me a PowerPoint presentation he was going to present to international senior management basically stating how they'd better hire me and a few other contractors before we jump ship!

Someone loves me, even if my ex doesn't.

I also spoke to another boss about my hours - he's asked me to come up with a working roster for after-hours work. He's really given me the freedom to choose what hours I want to do (within reason!). I absolutely want to keep doing the late shift - sometimes when I get home early, I get bored sitting there eagerly waiting for jobs to come in of an evening. I'm just not sure if I want to keep doing five days a week 8 till 11, or if I want to transition to alternating weeks on call. I'll have to think about it.

The CBD area around the office and the hotel I stay at has become so familiar to me. It's entrenched with memories - not of Auckland, but of what has been happening in my life when I've been here. 

[![slicegone.](/media/images/blog/streets.jpeg)](/media/images/blog/streets.jpeg)
_Written on these streets are the stories that I can't explain._

The first time I was up here? I was on top of the world! I felt amazing. I remember places where I bought Christmas presents, and where I was when I was on the phone to a certain someone. I remember feeling guilty that I was away yet having such a good time up here.

The second time I was here I was at an all time low, struggling to recover and having booze for the first time in 10,000 years. Yeah, I’m still embarrassed about what happened, especially when I found out that everyone in the office knows! Does it count as office gossip if everyone already knows what happened?

This time? I'm good. I mean, I'm not great! But I can't complain about how stuff is going right now. I still have a massive empty hole in me, but somehow I seem okay to not be in a rush to fill it. Everyone says it will happen, from my skepical best friend Mark to my kick ass colleague Jazz. Thank you! You empower me heaps.

Being around myself every day, I don't really have a view on how I've progressed, but having these semi-annual trips away acts as a kind of checkpoint. It gives me an opportunity to reflect on who I am, where I've come from and maybe even where I'm going.

I might be moving forward. I might be moving sideways. Heck, I might just be staying in one place dancing really awkwardly! But right now I can absolutely say I'm not moving backwards.

And that's an achievement worth unlocking.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The appalling state of Caramel in this country]]></title>
            <link>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/23/the-appalling-state-of-caramel-in-this-country/</link>
            <guid>https://aarond.me/blog/2021/05/23/the-appalling-state-of-caramel-in-this-country/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
As some of you may already know, I have a vendetta: The quality of caramel slices in this country is appalling.

As a “hobby”, to keep me sane during my long working days (which involve a lot of driving), I've been stopping off at bakeries and cafes around the area and sampling the caramel slice available. I got into caramel slice last year when I curated a range from all over the region to put together gift packages! It was very interesting just to see how diverse the offerings are. 

So far, Dannevirke has won. One bakery there had a gooey, oozy caramel in a crunchy and yum slice. But other places? Horrific. Wanganui, Palmerston North, Hunterville, Foxton, Eketahuna - all terrible, and definitely below par. Sometimes it’s crumbly and old, and at other times it just… tastes like porridge.

No more! It’s very clear that I need to show people how it’s done.

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL108VewJBdOA_OfLkchSuUgJumDqZTGPe" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>

Oh, I’m not an expert - I just like talking big. I’m going to ride that hype train! I’d rather boost myself up and let you, my readers, be disappointed. I will set your hopes way too high. But maybe, this one time, you should trust me.

First, put caster sugar and water into a giant pot. Yes, that’s right: White sugar and water. No butter, no brown sugar. Trust me here.

Let that bubble away on a medium heat for about 10 minutes, stirring all the time. It’ll develop a nice dark brown colour. Be careful: The colour will change very quickly! Pay attention, and don’t let it get away on you.

Now, pour in some cream. Not too much! Be careful, as the sugar solution will bubble up and put on quite a show. Remember to keep stirring. It’ll eventually settle down, and you’ll be left with a very concentrated brown caramel solution.

Next, add a can of condensed milk. Turn the heat down to low, and keep stirring. At this point you’re reducing the moisture and caramelising the sugars from the condensed milk. Here it’s all about the consistency you want - the longer you simmer it for, the thicker and harder the caramel will set. For slices you don’t want it to be very runny, but if you were making this as a sauce you’d simmer it for a shorter time.

[![Caramel.](/media/images/blog/caramel.jpg)](/media/images/blog/caramel.jpg)
_Ooooooooh._

And then it’s done! Wasn’t that easy? It’s a gooey caramel, full of flavour. You’ll love it, I promise.

With this batch, I put together a caramel slice. I sandwiched a thick layer of caramel between two vanilla cookie sheets, and then covered it with a thin layer of a dark chocolate and butter icing.

[![Caramel.](/media/images/blog/slice.jpg)](/media/images/blog/slice.jpg)
_It looks a bit... messy, but this would blow your mind!_

I swear I’m a humble person - sometimes - but this is just an order of magnitude better than most of the caramel based bakery treats I’ve had over the past year. The flavour is just amazing, and it’s got that ultimate smooth, gooey toffee texture. I may be hopeless at so many things, but this time? I’ve won!
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>